<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2020-03-18T21:58:01-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Distributed Web of Care</title><subtitle>DWC </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Oddkins</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/oddkins/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oddkins" /><published>2020-03-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-03-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/oddkins</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/oddkins/">&lt;p&gt;by Taeyoon Choi&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/oddkins.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;an ink drawing with circle, triangles and squares that look like alien entity. some lines are dotted and others are solid. black and white art work by Taeyoon.  &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oddkin&lt;/em&gt; is a word Donna Haraway uses to describe an unlikely collection of intimate people. In ‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q9gis7-Jads&quot;&gt;From Cyborgs to Companion Species&lt;/a&gt;,’ a lecture Haraway delivered on September 13, 2003 at the University of Berkeley, she unpacks the concept through various stories and metaphors. I’m fascinated by the word oddkin. The word captures the expansive and intimate relationships I have in my personal life, at my work in the School for Poetic Computation, and in the Processing community. I’m bilingual, so it’s natural for me to translate a new word into Korean. The word kin is 친척 (親戚 in Chinese), a family member. I couldn’t find the Korean translation of oddkin. I asked my Twitter followers if anyone would help translate it, and media artist Masayuki Akamatsu suggested 기묘한동류(妙な同類 in Japanese). It doesn’t have the earthy, crittery feel of oddkin, but it contains the sense of unlikely intimacy. It’s close enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear oddkins. I’ve been lucky to participate and help the &lt;a href=&quot;https://p5js.org/community/contributors-conference-2015.html&quot;&gt;p5.js contributors conference&lt;/a&gt; at the Frank-Ratchye STUDIO for Creative Inquiry in 2015 and remain a member of the project. &lt;a href=&quot;https://p5js.org/&quot;&gt;p5.js&lt;/a&gt; is a JavaScript library for creative coding, with a focus on making coding accessible and inclusive for artists, designers, educators and beginners. Artist and founder of p5.js, Lauren McCarthy asked me to write a piece for the p5.js zine in early 2020. In this letter, I take an opportunity to think about you, my oddkins in the world of art, technology and education, and share a list of questions for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to challenge the misuse of the word “democracy” in the context of technology. “Democracy” implies distributed power, fair representation, and equity for every citizen in a society. In conferences or demo days, I will often hear someone say that they are trying to ‘democratize’ technology by making tools or resources. For example, “I made this open-source tool. Now everyone can do what I do!” What they are not saying, and the privilege they are ignorant of, is that in order to use the tool you need to be technically fluent, be in an environment where you are accepted as a technical person, and have access to computers and network. In reality, technology, tools and resources alone cannot uphold democracy. Truly democratic societies require ongoing maintenance, stewardship and education. The question of who’s considered a citizen of society remains in every democratic system. Thus, the question of democracy is essentially a question of personhood– who is visible, whose labor is valued and who is heard in space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What the p5.js project does differently, and has from the beginning, is demystify the common narrative of a lone engineer creating a powerful framework and the stereotypes of who’s seen as technical and/or artistic. p5.js is a community where contributions from QTPOC, non-binary, disabled and Deaf, and non-technical individuals  are valued equally. The p5.js community is definitely more woke than most other software communities, but it is also a truer reflection of the reality of software/hardware development. There are almost always non-technical and non-traditional contributors who are integral to the success of any technology. They include but are not limited to writers, educators, testers, designers, Quality Control professionals and service workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The questions of whiteness in the open source field remains unresolved for me. I’ve attended numerous software and hardware conferences over the years. Some were highly exclusive and self-selective, others were open and inviting to newcomers. In the U.S. and Europe, the conference speakers and attendees were dominatingly white males. In Asia, I noticed the conference organizers and attendees trying to replicate white supremacy, tech solutionism, and patriarchy with a bit of nationalism. Codes of Conduct did not exist in major tech spaces until a few years ago. I could write a book about the troubling experiences I have had and witnessed in tech conferences. Older, established, white male engineers and academics making rude comments to female, gender non-conforming, people of color, may need to be divvied up into a few chapters. Young tech dudes promising to solve the world’s greatest challenges with code. Introverts who are actually just snobbish, escaping to their devices to avoid human contact, yet stalking women with overt confidence. The most insidious forms of racism  happen offstage. How a speaker badge isn’t enough for a person of color to enter the speakers’ lounge, how white bartenders treat a black person with offhand racist jokes, how women of color are tokenized for photo opportunities and a shout out on a diversity statement. They can get a chapter of their own in my book about tech conferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To survive in white spaces as a person of color, I learned to adapt to the expectations of others. In other words, I learned to play the white man’s game. Once I felt grounded, I leveraged my place to give voice to the others. Speaking my truth made some people uncomfortable and I lost some opportunities. Speaking up brought me the respect of others, especially those who want to use their power in white spaces to bring changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to speak up to challenge the establishment? I think nuance and candor are essential to start a conversation. No one likes to be criticized, but everyone loves to be understood. When I was learning to code, a friend told me, “Treat your computer like your younger sibling.” During the p5.js Contributors Conference, Jason Alderman, Tega Brain, Luisa Pereira and I created ‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://p5js.org/learn/debugging.html&quot;&gt;Debugging guide for p5.js&lt;/a&gt;.’ This approach of care, patience and play is essential in exploratory and poetic computing. I think a similar approach is necessary to navigate the technology industry and community. When someone makes a mistake, call them out, but don’t cancel them out. Give them a humane error message: &lt;em&gt;Hi there. You’ve done something that made me feel uncomfortable. It doesn’t mean you are a bad person. May I suggest how your behavior can be improved?&lt;/em&gt; Give them a second chance. If they improve, great! If they continue to make the same mistake, move on. That is the labor of care in a technological society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Media and design researcher Shannon Mattern’s essay “&lt;a href=&quot;https://placesjournal.org/article/maintenance-and-care/?cn-reloaded=1&quot;&gt;Maintenance and Care&lt;/a&gt;,” published in Places Journal in November 2018, offers “a working guide to the repair of rust, dust, cracks, and corrupted code in our cities, our homes, and our social relations.” Mattern connects care-work in relation to the practice and concept of maintenance to reveal that “the distinctions between these practices are shaped by race, gender, class, and other political, economic, and cultural forces.” Inspired by her provocation, I want to ask some questions regarding the maintenance of technology and the tech industry. How can we distinguish between humane, unintentional errors within the systems of oppression that make a global impact? How can we scale the practice of care to a global network of solidarity towards social and environmental justice?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should we train machine learning algorithms with a better data set to be less biased? Or should we not train the machines if the algorithms can be appropriated for malicious uses? If current algorithms contain biases of white male engineers, should POC engineers train machine learning algorithms to be more inclusive of their data and perspectives? Unlearning the biases we’ve been taught and undoing wrong are very difficult. Things get complicated, especially regarding restorative justice in the context of a Capitalist society. When we cooperate with those who’ve committed social ill in the past, what is the real cost of their redemption? By greenwashing, diversity-washing and care-washing, are we maintaining a system of injustice? Sure, no money is clean, but we decide how to get it. The conversation about ethical grayscale is highly contextual, but are there some things that are just wrong and should not be tolerated? If the true meaning of care is to take responsibility, are there some things that must be divided through binary determinism? In other words, are there some people or organizations we should not consider working with at all?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m struggling to come to terms with these questions, my oddkins. The distinction between what is ethical and unethical seems blurry, while technology is used to create greater disparities between those who have wealth, power and resources and those who don’t. The reason I’m attracted to the word and idea of oddkin is that it mends contradictions (oddness) with intimacy (kinship). If we consider ourselves, developers, users and educators of p5.js as an example for an alternative technological community, what can we offer to the greater world? Should we maintain a system that’s unfairly designed? Should we start a new system?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kindly ask if we can think about the question of care in relation to independence (autonomy) and interdependence (kinship). I’m interested in hearing from my oddkins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distributed Web of Care is an independent publishing project. Please support us via tax-deductible donation at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://opencollective.com/distributed-web-of-care/&quot;&gt;OpenCollective&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by Taeyoon Choi, February, 2020, Published in March 18, 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Illustration by Taeyoon Choi for &lt;a href=&quot;https://p5js.org/books/&quot;&gt;Getting Started with p5.js&lt;/a&gt; published by O’Reilly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edited by &lt;a href=&quot;http://sheafitz.com/&quot;&gt;Shea Fitzpatrick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://wordsinspace.net/shannon/&quot;&gt;Shannon Mattern&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;lauren-mccarthy.com&quot;&gt;Lauren McCarthy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dorothysantos.com/&quot;&gt;Dorothy Santos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://akamatsu.org/&quot;&gt;Masayuki Akamatsu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mizuki0730&quot;&gt;Mizuki Takeshita&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mill6chat.org/&quot;&gt;Centre for Heritage and Textile&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flong.com/&quot;&gt;Golan Levin&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://studioforcreativeinquiry.org/&quot;&gt;Frank-Ratchye STUDIO for Creative Inquiry&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/saeromsuh/&quot;&gt;Saerom Suh&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/taeyoon.png&quot; alt=&quot;a photograph of Taeyoon, who's in his mid-thirties. He's wearing a silver glass and looks out to the distance. he's wearing a shirt with graphic - care, not control&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://taeyoonchoi.com&quot;&gt;Taeyoon Choi&lt;/a&gt; is an artist, educator, and organizer. He is a cofounder of the School for Poetic Computation, an artist-run institution with the motto of “More Poetry, Less Demo!” Taeyoon seeks a sense of gentleness, intellectual kinship, magnanimity, justice and solidarity in his work and collaboration. He has presented installations, performances and workshops at Eyebeam Art and Technology Center, Los Angeles County Museum of Art, New Museum, M+ Museum, Istanbul Design Biennale, Seoul Mediacity Biennale and Venice Biennale for Architecture. He contributed to alternative education such as the Public School New York, Occupy University and Triple Canopy Publication Intensive. Recently, Taeyoon worked with Mimi Onuoha to start the New York Tech Zine Fair. He collaborated with Nabil Hassein and Sonia Boller to organize the Code Ecologies conference about the environmental impact of technology. As a disability justice organizer, Taeyoon continues to work with the Deaf and Disability community towards accessibility and inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">by Taeyoon Choi</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Merchandise</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/october-merch/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Merchandise" /><published>2019-10-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/october-merch</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/october-merch/">&lt;p&gt;Dropping new merchandise for the Distributed Web of Care.
Shop from &lt;a href=&quot;https://taeyoon-workshop.myshopify.com/&quot;&gt;Taeyoon Workshop online store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/products/neema1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/products/neema3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These long-sleeve shirts are 100% organic cotton and they are super comfortable. They have silk-screened graphics in the front and back. Front image is Care, not Control. Back image is a bibliography from the Distributed Web of Care 2018-2019. The graphics are printed with love by One Custom City in Detroit. The products will ship from Brooklyn, New York.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Model is Neema of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/radicallove&quot;&gt;Radical Love Consciousness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Dropping new merchandise for the Distributed Web of Care. Shop from Taeyoon Workshop online store.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Announcing Decentralized Networks Workshop</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/decentralized-networks/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Announcing Decentralized Networks Workshop" /><published>2019-08-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/decentralized-networks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/decentralized-networks/">&lt;p&gt;Free, public workshop for the WYFY School, in partnership with BUFU. 8.11.2019 6:30 - 8 p.m. at the School for Poetic Computation, NYC. This posting is a work in progress guide for Decentralized Networks Workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://distributedweb.care/static/images/wyfy/dandelions.svg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;centralized-networks&quot;&gt;Centralized Networks&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Social media: Instagram&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cloud computing: Amazon Web Services&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cloud storage: Google Drives&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Postscript on the Societies of Control&lt;/em&gt; by Gilles Delueze&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://poeticcomputation.info/chapters/ch.3/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Control Society&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Taeyoon Choi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Capitalization of attention economy: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/600671/how-to-do-nothing-by-jenny-odell/9781612197494/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to do Nothing: Resisting Attention Economy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Jenny Odell&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Erasure or overexposure of the marginalized communities: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.abc.net.au/news/science/2019-07-13/dark-patterns-online-captcha-accessibility-disability-community/11301054&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The internet thinks you’re a robot, and other ‘dark patterns’ people with disabilities face online&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Ariel Bogle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“If memes reiterate the inequities between black creators and white appropriators, can they also move us into a new collective blackness?” &lt;a href=&quot;https://reallifemag.com/poor-meme-rich-meme/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Poor Meme, Rich Meme&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Aria Dean&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://distributedweb.care/static/images/wyfy/questions.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;decentralized-networks&quot;&gt;Decentralized Networks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-silicon-valley-perspectives&quot;&gt;1. Silicon Valley Perspectives&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;History of Utopias and idealism&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hackers and counterculture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Whole Earth Catalogue&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Information sovereignty&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_wants_to_be_free&quot;&gt;Information wants to be free&lt;/a&gt;”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Suburbanization of the Web: Squarespace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://distributedweb.care/static/images/wyfy/party.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-a-variety-of-decentralizations&quot;&gt;2. A variety of decentralizations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Community networks: &lt;a href=&quot;https://alliedmedia.org/dctp/digitalstewards&quot;&gt;Digital Stewards Training&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.odbproject.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/ODB_DDP_HighRes_Spreads.pdf&quot;&gt;Digital Defense Playbook&lt;/a&gt; by Detroit Community Technology Project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peer to Peer protocols: &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1660460/hong-kong-protesters-use-airdrop-to-breach-chinas-firewall/&quot;&gt;Hong Kong’s protesters put AirDrop to ingenious use to breach China’s Firewall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mesh network: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nycmesh.net/&quot;&gt;NYC Mesh&lt;/a&gt; and DWEB Camp &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dweb-camp-2019/meshnet&quot;&gt;Mesh topology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Offline first: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/El_Paquete_Semanal&quot;&gt;El Paquete Semanal&lt;/a&gt; in Cuba&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solar-powered:&lt;a href=&quot;https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/&quot;&gt;LOW←TECH MAGAZINE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apc.org/en&quot;&gt;Association for Progressive Communications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How is a users’ privacy honored in each cases?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How is a users’ identity defined in each cases?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-an-alternative-to-google-drives&quot;&gt;3. An alternative to Google Drives&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://datproject.org&quot;&gt;Dat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://distributedweb.care/posts/codesocieties/&quot;&gt;How-to&lt;/a&gt; Demonstrations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Art projects: &lt;a href=&quot;https://coolguy.website/projects/dat-zine-library/index.html&quot;&gt;Dat Zine Library&lt;/a&gt; by Zach Manderville, ‘For the Birds’ Podcast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://distributedweb.care/static/images/wyfy/ssb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-an-alternative-to-instagram&quot;&gt;4. An alternative to Instagram&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scuttlebutt.nz/&quot;&gt;Secure Scuttlebutt&lt;/a&gt;(SSB)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Friendly &lt;a href=&quot;https://ssb-landing.netlify.com/&quot;&gt;new site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How-to Demonstrations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scuttlebutt.nz/principles/&quot;&gt;Principles&lt;/a&gt;: “Environment reflecting Technology reflecting Community reflecting Society.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scuttlebutt.nz/concepts/&quot;&gt;Network Topology&lt;/a&gt;: “it maps a the social network on to a computer network that is essentially the same topology! that is, the connections between humans maps approximately to the the connections between computers. if you follow someone, you really actually follow them at the data layer.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SSB concepts and terms&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scuttlebutt.nz/concepts/identity&quot;&gt;Identity&lt;/a&gt;: “The private key is your secret not to be shared with anyone. The public key is used as your identifier.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Local first: “offline first” Peer to Peer protocol&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scuttlebutt.nz/concepts/feed&quot;&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;: “A feed is a signed append-only sequence of messages. Each identity has exactly one feed.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Append-only log: Once you publish, you can’t edit or delete&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Global &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scuttlebutt.nz/concepts/gossip&quot;&gt;Gossip&lt;/a&gt; Network: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gossip_protocol&quot;&gt;Gossip protocol&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/4ec9ab624bc94d3829331cacc850c6d78a4ad6b2/01f43/assets/gossip-graph2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What actually happens?:&lt;a href=&quot;https://ssbc.github.io/scuttlebutt-protocol-guide/&quot;&gt;Protocol guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Client: &lt;a href=&quot;https://ahdinosaur.github.io/patchwork-downloader/&quot;&gt;Patchwork&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ssbc/patchbay&quot;&gt;Patchbay&lt;/a&gt;, what are the differences?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Friend hops: Show hops option in Patchbay&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scuttlebutt.nz/concepts/pub&quot;&gt;Pub&lt;/a&gt;: ‘Always-online friend,’ SSB on a server which you can follow to connect with friends remotely&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SSB Community: &lt;a href=&quot;https://one.camp.scuttlebutt.nz/&quot;&gt;Scuttle Camp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conversations on SSB: A reading group about ‘White fragility,’ discussion about ‘Decolonizing technology,’ a channel about ‘Vegan junkfood’ and etc&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creative projects: Scuttlebooth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://distributedweb.care/static/images/wyfy/ssb.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-qtpoc-perspectives&quot;&gt;5. QTPOC perspectives&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A conversation about conflict of needs: Preservation of privacy and intimacy versus Openness and inclusivity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Abuse, misuse, harassment scenarios: White supremacy, hate speech and toxic masculine behaviors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decolonizing the internet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Honoring the indigeneous and traditional communities, land and the environment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deaf and Disabled rights on the Decentralized web&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-critical-perspectives&quot;&gt;6. Critical perspectives&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Corporate appropriations and re-centralization&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Decentralization is not the goal. Orthogonality of Data, Transport, Identity ‘not used to capture each other, they are 90 degrees from each other’ for Information freedom and user agency. For a sense of self and privacy” - Peter Wang’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=1314&amp;amp;v=-z47R9wN5SQ&quot;&gt;talk&lt;/a&gt; at the DWEB Camp&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Military contracts: Brooklyn Start Up &lt;a href=&quot;https://gotennamesh.com/products/mesh&quot;&gt;GoTenna&lt;/a&gt; lands a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaspending.gov/#/keyword_search/gotenna&quot;&gt;contract&lt;/a&gt; with the Department of Homeland Security, U.S. Customs and Border Protection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;7-group-discussion&quot;&gt;7. Group discussion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;QTPOC safe space on Decentralized Web&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Code of conduct and community stewardship&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Copyright versus ownership of ideas and identity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;8--leaving-with-a-positive-note&quot;&gt;8 . Leaving with a positive note&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.datproject.org/2019/03/22/three-protocols-and-a-future-of-the-decentralized-internet/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Three protocols and a future of the decentralized internet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Darius Kazemi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://runyourown.social/&quot;&gt;Run your own social&lt;/a&gt;:How to run a small social network site for your friends by Darius Kazemi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ournetworks.ca&quot;&gt;Our Networks&lt;/a&gt; in Toronto&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://radicalnetworks.org/&quot;&gt;Radical Networks&lt;/a&gt; in New York&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alliedmedia.org/amc&quot;&gt;Allied Media Conference&lt;/a&gt; in Detroit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dwebcamp.org&quot;&gt;DWEB Camp&lt;/a&gt; in San Francisco&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.archive.org/2019/07/31/remembering-the-first-dweb-camp-july-2019/&quot;&gt;Remembering the First DWeb Camp, July 2019&lt;/a&gt; By Frances Sawyer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://reading.supply/post/432f6903-c7cd-4cb0-a894-c09155a8ca8b&quot;&gt;The Internet’s Old Guard&lt;/a&gt; By Jay Graber&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/decentralized-web/transforming-ourselves-to-transform-our-networks-f4511a3d7483&quot;&gt;Transforming Ourselves to Transform Our Networks&lt;/a&gt; by mai ishikawa sutton&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;9-a-case-for-emergent-networks&quot;&gt;9. A case for emergent networks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“trust the people and they become trustworthy. trust the people and you will become trustworthy.” &lt;a href=&quot;http://adriennemareebrown.net/2019/07/01/trust-the-people-2/&quot;&gt;
trust the people&lt;/a&gt; by adrienne maree brown&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“We are not idealistic. Decentralization is not a solution to the problems of the centralized networks. However, we are not pessimistic. Decentralized networks, when they are designed by the folx traditionally marginalized from the networks, LGBTQPOC, Deaf, Disabled, Indigenous and traditional communities,  can lead to an equitable, distribtued web of care.” by Taeyoon Choi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;10-activity-suggestions&quot;&gt;10. Activity suggestions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create an append-only journal with peers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build your own social network with peers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Role play a situation for community stewardship and protection&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;List your priorities for data privacy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Map your ‘orthogonal’ approach for a better web&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;support&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much love for &lt;a href=&quot;http://bufubyusforus.com/thewyfyschool&quot;&gt;BUFU&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://sfpc.io&quot;&gt;The School for Poetic Computation&lt;/a&gt;, SFPC &lt;a href=&quot;http://sfpc.io/codesocieties-winter-19&quot;&gt;Code Societies&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://melanie-hoff.com&quot;&gt;Melanie Hoff&lt;/a&gt; for supporting the WYFY School, &lt;a href=&quot;http://flawlesshacks.com&quot;&gt;Flawless Hacks&lt;/a&gt; for supporting the ‘work in progress’ zine and the DWEB Camp and the Secure Scuttlebutt community.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Free, public workshop for the WYFY School, in partnership with BUFU. 8.11.2019 6:30 - 8 p.m. at the School for Poetic Computation, NYC. This posting is a work in progress guide for Decentralized Networks Workshop.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On Stewardship</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/on-stewardship/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Stewardship" /><published>2019-05-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-05-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/on-stewardship</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/on-stewardship/">&lt;p&gt;by Jerron Herman&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;338&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/AulQkgzjecU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Attending. Attending. Attending. As you prepare to demonstrate your prowess, attend to the ones here. If ego plays a part, you are doomed. Also, you’ve got something to offer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/jerron/1_Jerron.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image description: Jerron Herman takes the floor to guide participants through movement exercises, exploring the various states a network can be. He stands in all black in the center of the room, with one arm raised and the other cradling his torso. The stewards in DWC shirts sit on the ground around him, in front of the audience seating. He introduces himself as “a disabled dancer with an interest in bridging disparate things together, hence computational theory and dance.” Jerron tells the audience that together we’ll be going through “experiences of taking the networks - centralized, decentralized, and distributed into our bodies.” He states his intent of using the disability experience to deepen our communal understanding of care, offering the idea of “disability genius,” as a singularly distinct output a disabled folk will communicate in a new way of working.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, you have to encourage yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contributing to the Distributed Web of Care event at The Whitney Museum was a real-time activation of collaboration for me, one that still reverberates across my professional career in impressionable ways. In it I learned the compelling truth of humility and the liberation of stewardship. When developing a solo practice, it is very common to take on everything and any delegation is done begrudgingly, when time or energy is scarce. One never seeks help with full capacity. Yet, as I entered the first rehearsal of DWC, I felt the unmistakable dizziness of assistance, of support. In addition to the DWC Stewards, a steering collective of artists and engineers, the space contained a scribe, multiple rooms to play, smart volunteers, and snacks. These are considered luxuries in other contexts whereas here it was commonplace. This context set me up to imbibe on critical thought that was not based on exasperation or exhaustion; this was an easy task, the rigorous part was yet to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still processing the series of events: invitation to interpret distributed networks via movement, good first rehearsal, dismal tech rehearsal, formative discussion, last minute rehearsal, magical activation. Across these events I felt my usual tension to perform melt to the simmering sensation of release, an incomprehensible comfort with unknowing and a growing delight in play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How was I to know Distributed Web of Care was a metaphor?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humility is possibly the last emotion before a breakthrough. With humility, one is absolved of their need to strive, instead becoming present, able to mindfully solve problems without needing perfection. I believed, as a first-time collaborator to the project, that I didn’t know how to interpret this vast ontological concept, this new ideology, that was &lt;em&gt;distributed web of care.&lt;/em&gt; I began to regurgitate Taeyoon and Cori Kresge’s original formula, thinking no one would see me slipping if I just repurposed a found object. Yet, it was evident that in denying the activation of my voice, even the template fell flat for this event. It could not be regurgitated. But I had other rehearsals and jobs where I was responsible for grants and donors, not to mention my own self-care. It could not be regurgitated. Confronted with this truth, I finally asked for clarity, a brainstorm, another way in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was after our tech rehearsal at the Whitney. You know that feeling that something’s not right, but we’re all smiling through? I was so bemused by the DWC collaborators’ generosity and optimism that I didn’t want to seem confused or possibly laborious because I needed some extra help. We’re all doing our part. But I remember approaching Taeyoon, understanding Taeyoon, to reveal that I was lacking some grounded identity. Reassuring, he suggested a phone call the next day wherein we collaborated on the format. Clarity happened with the introduction of myself in the web of care. I thought, what am I curious about? The answer(s) were how this activity would expand relationships and get us moving, period. With a new breath, and my intention on the event restored, I made a movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started with the movement phrase. It was deliciously simple and yet very “of my body” which made me feel more comfortable about facilitation. I tried out the phrase - mostly torso and hands to mitigate any separation for those seated or otherwise less mobile - in the communal holding space at The Whitney in plainview of the stewards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can play the facilitator or actually facilitate. I have internalized this unnecessary pressure as the facilitator to be flawless in the presence of audience or aids, but do not have a critical framework for failure. So, I’m simply nervous to fail and that’s all. In this experiment I spent too much time worrying rather than enjoying. The stewards were never supposed to be my lemmings, but my peers; us working together. I finally saw that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began to facilitate when I simplified what would occur and what would be the parts of entry for the stewards. From another, still complicated but clearer, rehearsal I set a plan and continually asked for agreement from the group. We would explicitly use the three totems of the web of care, “centralized”, “decentralized”, “distributed” and refer to our individual and collective bodies as the metaphor. So people would first feel their own network, then relate to multiple networks through extended tethering activities, like creating smaller circles of networks. The stewards were going to hold the space for others to explore and be centering figures, mediating my instructions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/jerron/2_Jerron.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image description: Jerron guides the audience through the first movement exercise: recognizing and feeling our own individual sense of network before we start to experience others’. Participants and stewards have their arm raised in various directions, instructed by Jerron to “take your right arm and extend it out in a safe position, maybe in front, maybe behind, maybe above you.” He continues to guide, “move it [your arm] around a little bit in a circular motion, but keeping the tension of the arm as straight or as tense as it can be.” After being led through other exercises of feeling our own bodies, Jerron states: “that’s your network. Your own individual network”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was an extraordinary mutual learning moment in the midst of us creating smaller networks where one steward, Lori Hepner, disclosed she felt particularly stressed about the activity involving coordinated movement within the “decentralized” section. In this section, stewards and participants would take my guided choreography into smaller networks to replicate and interpret without my facilitation. In these smaller networks, they would have to know and continue the movement in a more private way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew this moment. Even as a professional dancer I still cannot “pick up” choreography. I need time to orient myself if facings to the front change or I need time to feel it when different parts of the body are being employed. This activity was supposed to be accessible. However, accessible doesn’t just mean easier, it means equitable. How can one enter into a space on their own terms. It’s more about possessing the amount of information that breeds the most autonomy - knowing where the bathroom is located, how many steps to the bar, who surrounds me, and what movement quality are you really looking for - this knowledge combines with a personalized fortitude to make something inviting. As Lori and I talked, I reassured her that her autonomy was intact in the exercise. Still unsure, she would become an asset in another way. She would use her voice to describe and translate my movement during the event for everyone, making the choreography accessible and helping me transform access into an aesthetic. &lt;strong&gt;There’s tension in access because it can shift. When we approach access like art, it retains a form of care.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/jerron/3_Jerron.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image description: Participants take the floor, standing behind Jerron who’s center in front of the audience. Lori Hepner stands to the right of Jerron at the front, holding a microphone to announce the choreography to the room. Jerron’s right arm is extended out towards his right side, bent ever so slightly into a downward facing arc. The crowd follows his movements behind him, with a slew of arms extending outwards in the distance. As Jeron begins to lead the room through movements he announces, “In the centralized place, you don’t have autonomy. So what I’m going to do is take you through a piece of choreography that you’re going to have to take on and then we’ll figure out what happens next.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/jerron/4_Jerron.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With the crowd now dispersed into smaller circles, a DWC steward is captured interpreting Jerron’s choreography as her own now. She reaches her right arm outwards towards her right side, her torso and head follow accordingly. Behind her is a group of participants, each themselves interpreting the choreography without instruction. These are the smaller, decentralized networks, where the task remains to just interpret. Jerron guides them, stating: “when I say ‘go.’ you’re going to take on the same movement you just learned, and your intention is to imagine an invisible string that connects you all, and yet its not there. So from here, recreate the movement and see what happens.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/jerron/5_Jerron.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image description: An older woman with orange tinted glasses, a blue sweater, and white hair stands in front of a group of other participants, holding a pink string with both hands in front of her. The string is part of a larger web, criss-crossing and tangling behind her. Introducing the element of string and the final phase of distribution, Jerron tells the audience, “In this configuration now, you’re going to speak to each other…with the choice of three phrases: ‘May I?’ ‘Can I’ and ‘I will.” In the distributed configuration, the intention is “to remain connected as you complete the choreography…but then also try and create connections that otherwise weren’t there the first time you tried this choreography.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/jerron/6_Jerron.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image description: A diverse group of people look tenderly towards one another entangled in a web pink string. Some arms are raised upwards holding the string, some stay holding it closer to the body. Jerron affirms the group that at this point, “some of the choreography has gone out the window.” He also instructs them participants that “should they want to leave the network, you can.” In the distributed phase, audience members have autonomy over both their movements, and their participation in the choreography itself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exhilarating climax to this experience with the Distributed Web of Care occured when the majority of attendees stood to create the first large circle. In that moment I realized language, intention, inflection, body language, and space had communicated to them permission to be present and experience together. What did we do to get here? From my standpoint the prompts I gave came out of ways I usually felt connected. Simple and deep prompts, like place your head on your neighbor’s shoulder. Still, I was taken aback by their willingness to be vulnerable. In my mind I went back to the rehearsal even a few hours before when the stewards and I didn’t know how the large audience participation would  settle in our bodies. We had gone through “feeling your own network” and had a semblance of what the smaller networks would entail. The larger circle was a great unknown. The scale was different: by rehearsal we had grown familiar with each other to warrant comfort to lean on someone’s shoulder, not so in the activation. I lovingly mentioned this with, “we didn’t have this in rehearsal!” There was a shorter, older woman next to me who delighted in being asked to lean or squeeze or participate. Her reaction was mine. The proceeding elements of play disbursed with glee as stewards wielded string and participants entangled themselves, as people closely observed disabled movement alongside a live audio description, and enjoyed a bespoke accompaniment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/jerron/7_Jerron.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image description: Approximately 25 audience members participate in the scaffolding activity. They stand shoulder to shoulder next to one another, learning collectively towards the right side. Their heads and weight rest on the shoulder of the person to the right of them. Bound tightly together, the tilted configuration retains a steadiness and stability, marked by shared participation, trust, and care.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a group of people forever bound by a night at the Whitney. Within, the presentations and knowledge crept into their bodies, then their bodies creatively expressed minute or massive understanding of the new bits of knowledge, eventually creating an atmosphere that I thought symbolic of the content. Care is an action and we collectively built ourselves up through mutual understanding and joy to act carefully. I know everyone who attended the Distributed Web of Care event carries it with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I entered this activation striving to be worthy of a computational theorist only to realize that as much unlearning needs to occur as learning. I think when stewardship is invoked, an almost archaic word already, bringing notes of feudalism and lords, it calls on you to be similarly valorous. How? By true presence and presence alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/jerron/8_Jerron.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image description: A DWC Steward smiles jubilantly, with her eyes closed and arms raised above her as she holds onto the pink string, entangling behind her into the web of people. The image captures a moment of presence, focus, delight and trust.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-the-author&quot;&gt;About the Author:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/jerron/9_Jerron.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jerronherman.com/&quot;&gt;Jerron Herman&lt;/a&gt; is an interdisciplinary artist who’s been featured with Heidi Latsky Dance at Lincoln Center, ADF, the Whitney Museum, and abroad in Athens. He’s been a principal member of HLD since 2011. Jerron now serves on the Board of Trustees at Dance/USA. Jerron has also shot for Tommy Hilfiger Adaptive, consulted for a Nike-sponsored project, and was profiled in Great Big Story. In 2018 he was a Snug Harbor PASS artist, a finalist for the inaugural Apothetae/Lark Play Development Lab Fellowship and was nominated for a Fellowship in Dance from United States Artists. His latest solos include Phys. Ed. and Relative – a crip dance party. Jerron studied at Tisch School of the Arts and graduated from The King’s College. The New York Times has called him, “…the inexhaustible Mr. Herman.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">by Jerron Herman</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Movement Scores</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/movement-scores/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Movement Scores" /><published>2019-05-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-05-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/movement-scores</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/movement-scores/">&lt;p&gt;by Cori Kresge and Taeyoon Choi&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A set of movement scores for Distributed Web of Care developed by Cori Kresge and Taeyoon Choi between 2018-2019 in collaboration with DWC stewards and students from the School for Poetic Computation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scores in various forms were developed and shared by Cori Kresge for the Uncomputable in 2018, 
Movement, Memory, and the Unconscious Resource and &lt;a href=&quot;https://sfpc.io/classes/movement&quot;&gt;Code Movement&lt;/a&gt; workshop in 2019 at the School for Poetic Computation in New York.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scores were adapated for workshops by Taeyoon Choi for the Decentralized Web Summit in San Francisco, M+ Museum in Hong Kong, Nam June Paik Museum in South Korea, Istanbul Design Biennale and various venues between 2018 and 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This movement score is a documentation of a participatory performance presented by Cori Kresge and Taeyoon Choi for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eyebeam.org/events/refiguring-the-future-conference/&quot;&gt;Refiguring the Futures&lt;/a&gt; conference organized by REFRESH / Eyebeam at the Knockdown Center in New York in February 10, 2019. The performance was accompanied by music and sound by stud1nt and Tiri Karanuruk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/movement/image4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;initiation--lead-by-taeyoon&quot;&gt;Initiation – lead by Taeyoon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Group forms a circle. Everyone stands around the circle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone closes their eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The activity leader instructs the group:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Imagine you are a big animal.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Walk as slowly as you can to the center of the circle.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you feel other’s presence, take a moment to pause.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the group is tightly close to each other in the center, ask them to open eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walk back to make a circle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Repeat a few times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/movement/image1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;walking-together--lead-by-cori&quot;&gt;Walking together – lead by Cori&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone has their shoulders touching, forming a long line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They close their eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They try to walk all together in a group at the same speed. 
They walk across the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try a few times until everyone can walk in a similar speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;interdependence--lead-by-taeyoon&quot;&gt;Interdependence – lead by Taeyoon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone pairs up with someone next to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One person (leader) has their right palm facing down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another person (follower) has their right palm facing up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their palms are touching. They communicate only with their touch, no sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The palm-down leader is guiding the follower around the room. With extreme care to the safety and wellness of the follower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The activity leader instructs the group: at any point during the activity, the follower can turn their palm to face down. Then their roles change. The follower is now the leader and opens their eyes, and the leader is now the follower with their eyes closed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The activity continues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about 10 minutes, the activity leader instructs the group they can exchange their followers using only eye contract to agree upon the exchange, no words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When two leaders have made eye contact and agreed, they gently exchange their partners who still have their eyes closed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about 10 minutes, the activity leader instructs the group they can connect to other pairs, still using no words only eye contact agreement, and make a long line of followers / leaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The leaders are now taking care of two or more followers. Those who are at the end of the line can switch the roles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;string-networks--lead-by-taeyoon-and-cori&quot;&gt;String Networks – lead by Taeyoon and Cori&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Materials: a spool of soft strings or ribbons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concept: Everyone is a node and the strings are the networks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/movement/image3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-centralized-network&quot;&gt;1. Centralized network&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The facilitator asks if someone wants to become a dictator of the network. The dictator can tell everyone what to do, where to connect, and how they connect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dictator can connect the network themselves or ask another node to connect on behalf of their direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/movement/image2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-decentralized-network&quot;&gt;2. Decentralized network&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The facilitator asks the group if there is a ‘Code of Conduct’ that they would like to have for the group.  When everyone in the group agrees on five principles of the network, they self initiate the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/movement/image6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-distributed-network&quot;&gt;3. Distributed network&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The facilitator presents the rule: Everyone can join or leave the network anytime. When they join by touching the strings, they need to close their eyes and constantly be moving in small or large gestures. Whenever they desire, they can leave the network and open their eyes. They can cut the strings and create new network or modify and add new rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/movement/image5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-invisible-network&quot;&gt;4. Invisible network&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now everyone is instructed to reenact the distributed network without the strings but moving their arms and bodies as though they are still holding string. They need to understand every movement they take on in the space will have effects on other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/movement/image7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All photographs by Christine Butler&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SimjRuytXIY&amp;amp;t=0s&amp;amp;list=PLBez-U3NPcCu2THKggOiS4kJWGOsEi0C1&amp;amp;index=14&quot;&gt;Video documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;about-the-author&quot;&gt;About the Author:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/corikresge/&quot;&gt;Cori Kresge&lt;/a&gt; is a NYC based dancer, collaborator, writer, and teacher. Kresge graduated from SUNY Purchase with a BFA in dance and the Dean’s Award. She was a member of the Sri Chinmoy Meditation Center and International Vocal Ensemble. Kresge has been a member of the Merce Cunningham Repertory Understudy Group, functioning as a living archive for Cunningham works from the 60’s, 70’s, and 80’s. In 2016 Kresge staged Cunningham’s Field Dances, an improvisational score, on students of CNDC, Angers, France. She has also been a member of José Navas/Compagnie Flak, and Stephen Petronio Company. Kresge currently collaborates and performs with various artists including Rashaun Mitchell+Silas Riener, Liz Magic Laser, Rebecca Lazier, Xavier Cha, Esmé Boyce, Ellen Cornfield, Sarah Skaggs, Bill Young, Wendy Osserman, Sally Silvers, The School for Poetic Computation, and film makers Alla Kovgan, Zuzka Kurtz, and Charles Atlas. She has taught technique and improvisation at NYU Tisch School of the Arts, Bard College, Dickinson College, Barnard College, Princeton University, the Dalton School, and other institutions. Kresge also teaches the Little Creators preschool program at Church Street School for Music and Art in NYC. She is currently studying Zero Balancing, a therapeutic bodywork.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">by Cori Kresge and Taeyoon Choi</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Who Owns the Stars: The Trouble with Urbit</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/who-owns-the-stars/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Who Owns the Stars: The Trouble with Urbit" /><published>2019-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/who-owns-the-stars</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/who-owns-the-stars/">&lt;p&gt;by Francis Tseng&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application that introduced peer-to-peer (P2P) computing to the mainstream was file sharing, services like Napster, Kazaa, Gnutella, and BitTorrent. For me, these programs were the first time the contradiction of artificial scarcity—the imposed scarcity of infinitely replicable digital information—and the excessive measures that were used to enforce it became startlingly clear. Over time, I encountered the term P2P in other settings and alongside other ideas—democratic governance, communalism, autonomy, cooperatives—and I started to see the purchase this idea had beyond file sharing and networking protocols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://p2pfoundation.net/the-p2p-foundation/about-the-p2p-foundation&quot;&gt;The P2P Foundation’s mission and strategic priorities&lt;/a&gt;, for example, extend the early P2P ideas of open culture and exchange into values of cooperative living and regenerative production. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scuttlebutt.nz/principles/&quot;&gt;Scuttlebutt, a more recent P2P social networking protocol, has its own “principles stack”&lt;/a&gt; that similarly advocates pluralistic exchange and mutual interdependence. It’s beautiful how, at least in the ideal scenario, by using a P2P service we are helping others access it as well. P2P is both an acknowledgment of our shared needs and an example of how cooperation helps us fulfill those needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years, I’ve followed along with P2P projects because of these shared values, and I always find it exciting when new projects emerge. It seems that P2P is experiencing something of a renaissance, likely due to the frenzy around blockchain (which purports to offer something similar to P2P) and the increasing popular anxiety around centralized internet services like Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Urbit, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://urbit.org/&quot;&gt;a personal server built from scratch&lt;/a&gt;,” first came across my radar a couple of years ago. Urbit positions itself as a P2P project, but it stands out in contrast to other P2P projects, mainly because the person behind it, Curtis Yarvin, seems antithetical to what I understand P2P to represent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My central question is this: &lt;em&gt;Is Urbit a project that should be supported?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can further break this down into two parts. First, Urbit’s marketing materials correctly identify that concentrated data aggregation and decision-making power are fundamental issues of the internet-as-we-know-it. Twitter’s persistent neglect of harassment on its platform is one everyday example. It is clear that new protocols and platforms that reduce our dependency on distant power are needed to challenge these issues. What’s less clear, though, is whether or not Urbit actually offers a meaningful alternative. Does Urbit genuinely enable new kinds of relations? Or, does it merely replace the old aristocracy with a new one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second, and more urgent, question is: who and what are we supporting by supporting Urbit? Many people in tech still believe that technology can be divorced from its creators; however, those of us in tech need to recognize that we have a considerable amount of influence over which products enter the mainstream consciousness, which products get created at all, and who receives both financial and social capital (shout out to &lt;a href=&quot;https://techworkerscoalition.org/&quot;&gt;Tech Workers Coalition&lt;/a&gt; et al.). For example, consider Peter Thiel , who co-founded PayPal and was an early investor in Facebook. Early support of PayPal and Facebook contributed to their financial success, which developed Thiel’s influence and made him quite rich. Thiel then turned that money and influence into Palantir Technologies, a software company that &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2017/03/02/palantir-provides-the-engine-for-donald-trumps-deportation-machine/&quot;&gt;develops technologies to help expand surveillance and deportation for the government&lt;/a&gt;. We have to consider what similar groundwork we help to lay by supporting Urbit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;context&quot;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to discuss Urbit’s design, we need to have an understanding of the politics of its creator, Curtis Yarvin. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Curtis_Yarvin&quot;&gt;Curtis Yarvin&lt;/a&gt; is innocuously described on Wikipedia as an “American political theorist and computer scientist,” but to many, he is better known as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2017/02/behind-the-internets-dark-anti-democracy-movement/516243/&quot;&gt;one of the intellectual forebears of the alt-right&lt;/a&gt;. From 2007 to 2014&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, working under the pen name Mencius Moldbug, Yarvin writings, which among other things espoused anti-democratic ideas and scientific racism and helped introduce many of what are now understood as the alt-right’s foundational ideologies to a wider public. The term “red pill,” which describes the process of reactionary radicalization and the community around it, was first used in this way by Yarvin.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Defenders of Urbit are quick to dismiss any inclusion of Yarvin’s politics in discussions about Urbit as unfair or irrelevant, and might point out that Yarvin left the project in January of this year.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; However, given that Yarvin basically laid out the general design for Urbit independently, as he worked on it alone for 11 years&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and in parallel with his political writings&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and that Urbit, as a P2P project, is a fundamentally social and thus incorporates ideas about how people should be organized, Yarvin’s politics should be considered as something that influences his design decisions and his long-term vision for the project. &lt;a href=&quot;https://lobste.rs/s/z5j1hq/urbit_2017#c_4z4gik&quot;&gt;Dog-whistles&lt;/a&gt; have been identified in some of his writing about Urbit and its design, including his &lt;a href=&quot;https://urbit.org/posts/essays/the-dao-as-a-lesson-in-decentralized-governance/&quot;&gt;leaning on Nazi philosopher Carl Schmitt&lt;/a&gt; for questions around Urbit’s governance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To save space I’ll provide only a very brief overview of Yarvin’s political philosophy—if you like, you can read more about it &lt;a href=&quot;https://thebaffler.com/latest/mouthbreathing-machiavellis&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.viewpointmag.com/2017/03/28/the-darkness-at-the-end-of-the-tunnel-artificial-intelligence-and-neoreaction/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://thebaffler.com/latest/the-moldbug-variations-pein&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/2013/10/20/the-anti-reactionary-faq/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yavin refers to his brand of political philosophy as “neocameralism.” Neocameralism, as described in his essay “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unqualified-reservations.org/2007/08/against-political-freedom/&quot;&gt;Against Political Freedom&lt;/a&gt;,” is a political philosophy arguing that state should be run like a business, (i.e., with a CEO at its head and no democratic mechanisms). His ideas are credited as being foundational to the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2013/11/22/geeks-for-monarchy/&quot;&gt;neoreactionary” movement&lt;/a&gt;, which could be described as a neo-monarchist movement (though Yarvin himself doesn’t identify as a “monarchist” because of its association with a constitutional monarchy and not absolute monarchy). In the neoreactionary movement, “divine right” is supplanted with “genetic right” based on scientific racism reframed as “human biodiversity.” Yarvin’s writings are also popular within the right-libertarian sects of Silicon Valley, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://thebaffler.com/latest/the-moldbug-variations-pein&quot;&gt;with Peter Thiel&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/2/21/14671978/alt-right-mencius-moldbug-urbit-curtis-yarvin-tlon&quot;&gt;Peter Thiel also has a stake in Tlön&lt;/a&gt;, Yarvin’s company which develops Urbit, via Thiel’s VC firm, Founders Fund). The point here is that Yarvin is not a fringe philosopher. His writings have influence over people with considerable power and contributes to the intellectual miasma that emboldens and normalizes anti-democratic, anti-immigrant, misogynistic, and racist policies and attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;urbit&quot;&gt;Urbit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-self-sovereign-internet&quot;&gt;A self-sovereign internet&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Urbit positions itself as infrastructure for self-sovereignty in the digital age, liberating people from ceding control of their data to corporations.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:5&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The core idea is that Urbit helps you run a personal server that acts as an intermediary between you and other services, including existing services like Facebook (yes, there is a lot more to Urbit—such as its reinvention of parts of the lower-level computational stack—but its P2P layer is what’s of interest here).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self-sovereignty is an important principle, and I wager that many who regularly use the internet would agree that more of it is valuable for a healthy internet: for being able to control who can access your data, who can and cannot contact you, and so on. &lt;em&gt;But&lt;/em&gt;, self-sovereignty is far too vague of a concept on its own. Left- and right-libertarianism both start with self-sovereignty as a core value, but they end up with vastly different conceptions of what meaningful self-sovereignty looks like and how it can be achieved. Left-libertarianism finds that self-sovereignty arises from social organizing, care, and democratic governance, which build towards positive freedoms (freedom to learn, to flourish, and so on); whereas, right-libertarianism believes it comes from the market and that negative freedoms (freedom from restrictions and regulation) are the goal. Though Yarvin does not identify as a libertarian (he is, in his own words, sympathetic to it), his neocameralism is right-libertarianism taken to its logical conclusion&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:6&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:6&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; of corporate tyranny and serfdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To draw an example that you might be familiar with, consider the Twitter-alternative, Gab, which markets itself as a bastion for free speech. Gab, in practice, operates as a niche platform for members of the far-right who have been banned from Twitter: “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/28/us/gab-robert-bowers-pittsburgh-synagogue-shootings.html&quot;&gt;a haven for white nationalists, neo-Nazis and other extremists&lt;/a&gt;”. We might ask then, is Gab a platform for free speech, or is it a platform for hate speech? Who’s speech does Gab prioritize? It quickly becomes clear that the concept of “free speech” that Gab deploys is not quite the same as what others see it to mean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a similar way, this slipperiness of self-sovereignty as a concept, especially in light of Yarvin’s political writings, makes me suspicious of what it really means in the context of Urbit. Is Urbit actually designed to give users more autonomy and control? Does it restore any power to internet users?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One central design feature of Urbit is its network hierarchy. As a participant in Urbit, you may be a galaxy (the top of the hierarchy), a star (which fall under galaxies), or a planet (which fall under stars). The description of this hierarchy &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cgyarvin/urbit/blob/6ac688960687aa9c89d4da6fff49a3125c10aca1/Spec/urbit/3-intro.txt&quot;&gt;used to use explicitly feudal metaphors&lt;/a&gt; as part of what Yarvin called “digital feudalism,” with himself as the “prince,” and further contributes to my suspicion of Yarvin’s conception of self-sovereignty actually entails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In trying to backpedal on these naming conventions, Yarvin claims that his ideas about governance are flipped for the internet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If the real world today is governed as an insanely dysfunctional republic, and the Internet today is governed as a cluster of insanely despotic corporate monarchies, it doesn’t strike me as at all inconsistent with historical thought to treat the former case of misgovernment with efficient monarchism, and the latter case with liberating republicanism.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:7&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rationale for why the opposite is the ideal in each case—beyond contrarianism, at least—is unclear. We should dig into how Urbit’s governance is laid out to better understand what’s going on here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Urbit’s primary governance model is a “self-governing digital republic” where &lt;em&gt;“authority is proportional to property.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:8&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:8&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Galaxies, stars, and planets are conceived of as property to be purchased and in limited supply, and one’s power within Urbit is determined by what tier of ownership they occupy and how much they own. The republic is structured as a “&lt;a href=&quot;https://urbit.org/posts/essays/the-urbit-address-space/&quot;&gt;three-chambered legislature balanced against itself&lt;/a&gt;,” where galaxies, stars, and planets constitute the three tiers. There is not much detail on how this government would operate, other than an &lt;a href=&quot;https://urbit.org/posts/essays/interim-constitution/&quot;&gt;interim constitution&lt;/a&gt;, which doesn’t describe how these tiers actually balance each other. For instance, the “planetary assembly”, which manages technical governance, doesn’t have any oversight of the “stellar congress”, which manages internal governance, or the “galactic senate”, which selects consuls, who hold “full authority” in this interim.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:9&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:9&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; When it comes to the stars and galaxies, &lt;a href=&quot;https://urbit.org/posts/essays/why-urbit-probably-does-not-need-a-blockchain/&quot;&gt;the extent of your political agency as a planet is exit&lt;/a&gt;—that is, the only meaningful action you can take is to move to a different host star.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:10&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:10&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This notion of “exit,” which is popular among Silicon Valley libertarians like Peter Thiel&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:11&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:11&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, is a key part of Yarvin’s political philosophy. It is summarized as, in Yarvin’s own words as: “If residents don’t like their government, they can and should move.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:12&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:12&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Of course, this formulation of mobility as the ultimate form of political action neglects all the actual complications of uprooting yourself (leaving behind friends, family, and history), the question of whether or not any other place will accept you (e.g., in the case of borders or discrimination), and reduces your political expression to a single vote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, exit in a digital context is logistically simpler than in a physical one, but it is still not easy. People critical of Twitter’s policies still use Twitter, not because they are hypocritical but because it’s a lot of effort to migrate to a new platform and re-establish connections from the former. People critical of Facebook may remain because it’s the only connection they have to some friends and family members. In both of these cases, having some mechanisms for democratic oversight would be more effective than showing people the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are still further issues with exiting. For example, I may be unable to exit if, perhaps for discriminatory reasons, I cannot find a star that is willing to host me. Or, I may be unable to establish my own star if no one is willing to sell to me for similar reasons. Additionally, we are forced to ask, How bad do things have to get before I decide to exit? Do I just have to endure everything below that threshold? The point of other (democratic) forms of political voice and agency are that they allow us to have a nuanced process of change, one that allows for fundamental shifts as well as the fine-tuning that is inevitably necessary. Limiting one’s political agency to exit, dismisses any potential for incremental change or open discussion—basically, if you don’t like the way things are, you can go. Otherwise, shut up and take it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;property-ownership-and-power&quot;&gt;Property, ownership, and power&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because &lt;em&gt;“authority is proportional to property”&lt;/em&gt; in Urbit, we should look more closely at how ownership is understood and operates in its design.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:8:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:8&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; In &lt;a href=&quot;https://urbit.org/posts/essays/a-founders-farewell/&quot;&gt;his farewell&lt;/a&gt;, Yarvin, out of ignorance or for rhetorical purposes, does not seem to recognize how ownership is a power relation. This is especially baffling because, as just quoted, in Urbit power and ownership are explicitly linked. Somehow in Yarvin’s broader understanding of things, property ownership is “random” and this means we should just let it be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When you live in Manhattan, you simply don’t worry about who owns it or why; and nor does it matter. Are they Jews? Muslims? Christians? Communists? Italians? You don’t care and you don’t have to. You know it’s basically random and probably unfair. Randomness, even blatant unfairness, creates a kind of neutral, peaceful, even promising urban anonymity.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, contrary to Yarvin’s claims, who owns what in Manhattan matters to a great many people. With &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/07/21/upshot/when-the-empty-apartment-next-door-is-owned-by-an-oligarch.html&quot;&gt;apartments left vacant&lt;/a&gt; to be used as investment vehicles, or else in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brickunderground.com/rent/pied-a-terre-airbnb-affordable-housing-crisis-nyc&quot;&gt;low-use&lt;/a&gt; because it’s more profitable to rent them out as Airbnbs, many people are rightfully critical of who owns (and profits) from these properties—properties that could, among other things, serve to house some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bowery.org/homelessness/&quot;&gt;New York’s homeless population&lt;/a&gt;. Likewise, people are critical of how the developers who own large portions of the city &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/developers-of-manhattan-luxury-towers-give-millions-to-upstate-candidates&quot;&gt;use their positions to lobby state government&lt;/a&gt; to compound and expand their influence. Whether or not the current allocation of Manhattan’s space is random (how developers lobby local government is a clear example that it’s not) or unfair does not mean we should throw up our hands and let it be. This line of argumentation is a red herring to deter questioning the property-power dynamics that undergird Urbit’s design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If power in Urbit is predicated on ownership, then it’s worth asking who owns what. The distribution of galaxies (&lt;a href=&quot;https://urbit.org/posts/essays/the-urbit-address-space/&quot;&gt;as of 2016 at least&lt;/a&gt;) puts 185 of the 256 in the hands of Tlön, Tlön’s employees, and urbit.org (which is &lt;a href=&quot;https://urbit.org/posts/essays/interim-constitution/&quot;&gt;currently under management and ownership of Tlön&lt;/a&gt;). The story for stars is not much different: 57.62% of stars (almost 38,000 of the 65,500 stars) are also owned by Tlön, its employees, and urbit.org. Even with Urbit’s tiered hierarchical structure, which ostensibly decentralizes power, we can see that power is quite concentrated (which they acknowledge).&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:9:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:9&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This comparison to Manhattan calls back to Urbit developers’ comparison of their system to land.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:8:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:8&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Urbit’s design creates a class of digital landlords who are the primary political authorities. There are obviously significant differences between physical land and digital space, but it strikes me as a regression to reproduce land scarcity (and rent-seeking structures) in cyberspace. For Urbit’s digital land, scarcity has to be manufactured, and manufactured digital scarcity seems antithetical to P2P values—where the easy replicability of data represents new opportunities and alternatives to the crude economies we’ve stumbled through in the physical world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How then does Urbit justify this manufactured scarcity? The primary reason is as a defense against Sybil attacks—a class of attacks endemic to pretty much any digital networking system where adversaries can generate identities in bulk to attack the system (e.g., DDoS attacks or spam).&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:13&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:13&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:8:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:8&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:5&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Spam is something like a Sybil attack—it’s easy to make tons of email addresses and use them to bombard people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paper that introduced Sybil attacks proved that there is no way to altogether prevent such attacks without introducing a centralized identity-verification authority.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:14&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:14&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; In the case of spam this would be like one organization that manages a global registry of non-spam emails. There are, however, ways to make Sybil attacks more expensive and thus less feasible to execute. In the case of Urbit, the scarcity is meant to compel prices for stars and planets such that they are too expensive for an attacker to purchase in bulk.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:8:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:8&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are other decentralized Sybil-defense schemes proposed for P2P networking. Some introduce cryptographic puzzles, similar to Bitcoin’s proof-of-work.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:15&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:15&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:16&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:16&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;16&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:17&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:17&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;17&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Others are based on explicit trust in social networks.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:18&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:18&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;18&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:19&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:19&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; These approaches aren’t without their flaws—Sybil attacks can’t be completely prevented, after all—but, crucially, these schemes don’t introduce points of centralization that require concentrated trust or introduce authorities that can exclude non-adversarial actors from the network. Because Urbit’s supply is explicitly controlled by owners of galaxies and stars, they can deny people access for any arbitrary reason. This is especially concerning because of the aforementioned concentration of Urbit property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet even though Urbit’s design grants political power proportionally to ownership, “[f]or the interim, full authority is held by the (Roman style) consulate.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:9:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:9&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Urbit is functionally an authoritarian regime for now. It is designed to &lt;a href=&quot;https://urbit.org/posts/essays/common-objections-to-urbit/&quot;&gt;decentralize eventually&lt;/a&gt;—Urbit documentation acknowledges a need to spread out ownership of its assets.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:8:5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:8&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; But, given the initial distribution of galaxies—95 galaxies to the Tlön Corporation; 50 to urbit.org (the future community foundation); 40 to Tlön employees and their family members (24 to Yarvin, who started in 2002, and 16 to everyone else who started in 2014); 34 to outside investors in Tlön; and 37 galaxies to 33 other individuals, who donated to the project, contributed code or services, won a contest, or were just in the right place at the right time—it isn’t clear what kind of further distribution of ownership they have in mind, or even whether it will be meaningful. More troubling still is that in their own words, Urbit describes this distribution as being spread “across a diverse set of entities,”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:8:6&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:8&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; when it seems to only encompass people in their immediate networks. This arrangement is reminiscent of Manhattan real estate: the earlier you got in, the more ownership, and thus power, you accrued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, “decentralization” when used to describe governance is notoriously slippery, especially in blockchain and blockchain-adjacent contexts such as P2P. What does it mean for a government to be meaningfully decentralized? If galaxies and stars become prohibitively expensive to the point where only the wealthy can purchase them, does that lead to a decentralized government? Decentralization also says nothing about representative ratios. In the US, we have 535 members of Congress representing 320 million Americans; if Urbit achieves full adoption, there’ would be 256 galactic senate members representing 4.3 billion planets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s nothing to suggest that Urbit even cares about how representative its governance structures are. The word “democratic” is scarce across descriptions of Urbit’s governance. “Democracy” only appears once throughout all of urbit.org, and it is &lt;a href=&quot;https://urbit.org/posts/essays/the-dao-as-a-lesson-in-decentralized-governance/&quot;&gt;in a sarcastic quote&lt;/a&gt;. The term also appears in an older document, and its use is telling: “Urbit will never be a democracy, but it should always remain a republic.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:21&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:21&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;21&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; In that same document, Yarvin does mention that the dukes (now “galaxies” in the new terminology) will be organized democratically, but this is consistent with the republic formulation.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:21:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:21&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;21&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, combined with Yarvin’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unqualified-reservations.org/2007/04/formalist-manifesto-originally-posted/&quot;&gt;admiration of the Roman Principate&lt;/a&gt; as an example of a government that “retain[s] the symbolic structures of democracy”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:6:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:6&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; while being autocratic in practice (the Roman Principate was ruled by an emperor but maintained a superficial senate for the appearance of a continuing republic), gives me reason to doubt the intentions around governance here. A new internet under this regime could easily turn out to be just as bad as or worse than it is now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;who-urbit-supports&quot;&gt;Who Urbit Supports&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Yarvin is officially removed from the further design and development of Urbit, he still maintains a minority share in Tlön and a few thousand stars (he is “&lt;a href=&quot;https://urbit.org/posts/essays/a-founders-farewell/&quot;&gt;probably the only individual with a fair amount of Urbit address space&lt;/a&gt;”). His departure at this point is not enough to counteract his heavy, and at times exclusive, involvement in Urbit’s foundational design and development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, there is an issue that goes beyond Urbit’s design and future ambitions. It comes down to the fact that if I were to support Urbit, I would also be supporting Yarvin—he still has a substantial stake in its success and, like any network-based platform, the value of Urbit increases the more people use it. At least &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/4bxf6f/im_curtis_yarvin_developer_of_urbit_ama/&quot;&gt;some people do support Urbit because they support Yarvin’s politics&lt;/a&gt;. Yarvin’s years writing as Mencius Moldbug were possible &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.2blowhards.com/archives/2007/04/_trial_version.html&quot;&gt;because of money made during the dot-com boom&lt;/a&gt;. After announcing his departure, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/slatestarcodex/comments/ag2s4f/curtis_yarvin_quit_tlon_the_startup_making_urbit/&quot;&gt;people have expressed excitement around his return to writing&lt;/a&gt;, so we may see further works of political philosophy from him. Even if Yarvin were to never write again, the success of Urbit is likely to draw attention to its creator—and introduce more people to his past writings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond introducing Yarvin’s writings to new audiences, we should also consider how supporting Urbit supports Yarvin more directly. We can get a rough sense of Yarvin’s financial stake in Urbit, leaving aside speculation about his financial stake in Tlön itself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 256 galaxies and 65,536 stars across all of Urbit.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:8:7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:8&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; There are roughly 4.3 billion planets that were initially evenly distributed across stars, so each star started with 65,000 planets.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:22&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:22&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;22&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; In the long-run Urbit developers believe $10 to be a fair price for a planet.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:23&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:23&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;23&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Assuming that the price eventually converges to $10 per planet and Urbit achieves widespread adoption, then each star is worth $650k in planet real estate alone. Planets are also expected to pay a monthly fee to their stars for routing services (which is the bare minimum service; the star may choose to offer services as well).&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:24&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:24&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;24&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; This fee is estimated to be anywhere from $10–$100 per month.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:22:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:22&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;22&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s assume the lower end, that $10/month is required for the routing services. If a star sells all of its planets and they remain under that star, that’s potentially another $650k in revenue per month. When we consider that Yarvin owns “a few percent of all stars” (which is thousands of stars)&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, if Urbit does achieve widespread adoption, then that is a staggering amount of wealth. Yarvin’s nominal departure from Urbit does not change the fact that he stands to gain tremendously from its success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does an internet in which Urbit achieves widespread adoption look like? I’m not sure it would look much different. You would have a personal server, sure; but then there would then be a new infrastructural layer between you and your ISP (who you’ll still have to pay) owned by &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; class of rentiers who you’ll also pay. One of the great appeals of P2P is that routing occurs almost as a side-effect of everyone using the internet, so by being online, you help others be online at essentially no additional cost. Urbit abandons this P2P property of mutual aid such that the property and power relations of the internet are mostly kept intact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, it’s not certain—or even likely—that Urbit will ever achieve this level of adoption and value. What is clear, however, is that if I were to support Urbit, then I would, even in a small way, be making its spread and adoption all the more likely. We already spend so much of our time and money supporting regimes of violence, oppression, and inequality by merely existing in a capitalist society. These relationships are hard to break because they are so deeply established and entrenched within culture and the market. Urbit is not yet entrenched in the same way, and I do not want to help it get there. I want to have no part in supporting Yarvin or any other project or creator whose underlying ideology is hateful, reactionary, or anti-democratic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;closing-words&quot;&gt;Closing Words&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Urbit is still in such a nascent state with much left ambiguous. Its value (or your expectations of its value) largely depends on how much you trust the people behind it. It’s hard for me to trust people who have no problem working for someone like Yarvin who has actively contributed to the re-emergence of white supremacy and anti-democratic ideas, or who would go so far to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/2/21/14671978/alt-right-mencius-moldbug-urbit-curtis-yarvin-tlon&quot;&gt;dismiss Yarvin’s Nazi apologia (“What’s so bad about Nazis?”) as “trolling.&lt;/a&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;http://art.yale.edu/file_columns/0000/0066/borges.pdf&quot;&gt;Tlön, Uqbar, Orbis Tertius&lt;/a&gt;,” the Borges story where Yarvin’s company gets its name, describes a secret society, &lt;em&gt;Orbis Tertius&lt;/em&gt;, that architects an entirely new world, &lt;em&gt;Tlön&lt;/em&gt;, by publishing an encyclopedia describing it. Over time, bits of this fictional world begin to emerge in the real world, consuming it, such that “[t]he world will be Tlön.” What ideas are Yarvin’s Tlön trying to manifest in our world? What world would Yarvin seek to manifest with his new wealth?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In asking these questions, we should consider them not only as tools for evaluating similar projects but also as criteria with we might develop new projects. What ideas do we want to manifest in our world? I absolutely agree that what Urbit positions itself against—an internet dominated by concentrated corporate interests and surveillance infrastructure—is something that internet technologists need to build alternatives to. But we shouldn’t replace it with another system of undemocratic control or one that supports far-right intellectuals. I hope to see more P2P projects that commit to most promising values of P2P systems—plurality, democracy, mutual interdependence, sharing, and cooperation—as they take on the difficult but necessary task of creating egalitarian platforms and infrastructure, rather than rehashing the old hierarchies. P2P computing is still a burgeoning technology, and while there are projects like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scuttlebutt.nz/&quot;&gt;Scuttlebutt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://beakerbrowser.com/&quot;&gt;Beaker Browser&lt;/a&gt;, and the various &lt;a href=&quot;https://fediverse.party/&quot;&gt;Fediverse projects&lt;/a&gt;, which all reflect its potential, there is plenty of room for more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Additional acknowledgements: thanks to Dan Taeyoung and Matt Goerzen for their comments and insights.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-the-author&quot;&gt;About the Author:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/francis/francis.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://frnsys.com&quot;&gt;Francis Tseng&lt;/a&gt; in an engineer working primarily with simulation and machine learning. His research interests include climate change, tech autonomy, and traps. He is currently a fellow at the Jain Family Institute. Formerly, he taught at the New School and co-published The New Inquiry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“UR.” Unqualified Reservations by Mencius Moldbug. Accessed May 02, 2019. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unqualified-reservations.org/#archive&quot;&gt;https://www.unqualified-reservations.org/#archive&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Moldburg, Mencius. “Gentle Introduction to Unqualified Reservations Chapter 1: The Red Pill.” January 8, 2009. Accessed May 02, 2019. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unqualified-reservations.org/2009/01/gentle-introduction-to-unqualified/&quot;&gt;https://www.unqualified-reservations.org/2009/01/gentle-introduction-to-unqualified/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Yarvin, Curtius. “A Founder’s Farewell.” Urbit /Posts. January 19, 2019. Accessed May 02, 2019. &lt;a href=&quot;https://urbit.org/posts/essays/a-founders-farewell/&quot;&gt;https://urbit.org/posts/essays/a-founders-farewell/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Yarvin, C. Guy. “Urbit: Functional Programming from Scratch.” Moron Lab. January 13, 2010. Accessed May 02, 2019. &lt;a href=&quot;http://moronlab.blogspot.com/2010/01/urbit-functional-programming-from.html&quot;&gt;http://moronlab.blogspot.com/2010/01/urbit-functional-programming-from.html&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:5&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“Primer.” Urbit. Accessed May 02, 2019. &lt;a href=&quot;https://urbit.org/primer&quot;&gt;https://urbit.org/primer&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:5&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:5:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:6&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Moldburg, Mencius. “A Formalist Manifesto.” Unqualified Reservations by Mencius Moldbug. April 23, 2007. Accessed May 02, 2019. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unqualified-reservations.org/2007/04/formalist-manifesto-originally-posted/&quot;&gt;https://www.unqualified-reservations.org/2007/04/formalist-manifesto-originally-posted/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:6&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:6:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:7&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Lecher, Colin. “Alt-right Darling Mencius Moldbug Wanted to Destroy Democracy. Now He Wants to Sell You Web Services.” The Verge. February 21, 2017. Accessed May 02, 2019. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/2/21/14671978/alt-right-mencius-moldbug-urbit-curtis-yarvin-tlon&quot;&gt;https://www.theverge.com/2017/2/21/14671978/alt-right-mencius-moldbug-urbit-curtis-yarvin-tlon&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:7&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:8&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“Common Objections to Urbit.” Urbit. June 28, 2016. Accessed May 02, 2019 &lt;a href=&quot;https://urbit.org/posts/essays/common-objections-to-urbit/&quot;&gt;https://urbit.org/posts/essays/common-objections-to-urbit/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:8&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:8:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:8:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:8:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:8:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:8:5&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:8:6&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:8:7&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:9&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“The Urbit Address Space.” Urbit. May 16, 2016. Accessed May 02, 2019 &lt;a href=&quot;https://urbit.org/posts/essays/the-urbit-address-space/&quot;&gt;https://urbit.org/posts/essays/the-urbit-address-space/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:9&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:9:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:9:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:10&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“Why Urbit Probably Doesn’t Need a Blockchain.” Urbit / Posts. July 14, 2017. Accessed May 02, 2019. &lt;a href=&quot;https://urbit.org/posts/essays/why-urbit-probably-does-not-need-a-blockchain/&quot;&gt;https://urbit.org/posts/essays/why-urbit-probably-does-not-need-a-blockchain/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:10&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:11&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Tiku, Nitasha. “Silicon Valley’s Ultimate Exit Is a Fantasy of Seceding from the U.S.” Gawker. October 21, 2013. Accessed May 02, 2019. &lt;a href=&quot;http://valleywag.gawker.com/silicon-valleys-ultimate-exit-is-a-fantasy-of-seceding-1449199349&quot;&gt;http://valleywag.gawker.com/silicon-valleys-ultimate-exit-is-a-fantasy-of-seceding-1449199349&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:11&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:12&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Moldbug, Mencius. “Patchwork: A Political System for the 21st Century Chapter 1: A Positive Vision” Unqualified Reservations by Mencius Moldbug. November 13, 2008. Accessed May 02, 2019. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unqualified-reservations.org/2008/11/patchwork-positive-vision-part-1/&quot;&gt;https://www.unqualified-reservations.org/2008/11/patchwork-positive-vision-part-1/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:12&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:13&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“Interim Constitution.” Urbit / Posts. May 16, 2016. Accessed May 02, 2019. &lt;a href=&quot;https://urbit.org/posts/essays/interim-constitution/&quot;&gt;https://urbit.org/posts/essays/interim-constitution/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:13&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:14&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Douceur, John R. “The Sybil Attack.” International workshop on peer-to-peer systems. Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg, 2002. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:14&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:15&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Li, Frank, et al. “SybilControl: Practical Sybil defense with computational puzzles.” Proceedings of the seventh ACM workshop on Scalable trusted computing. ACM, 2012. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:15&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:16&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Sohl, Eli. “Resisting Sybil Attacks in Distributed Hash Tables.” Sohliloquies. February 25, 2017. Accessed May 02, 2019. &lt;a href=&quot;http://sohliloquies.blogspot.com/2017/02/resisting-sybil-attacks-in-distributed_25.html&quot;&gt;http://sohliloquies.blogspot.com/2017/02/resisting-sybil-attacks-in-distributed_25.html&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:16&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:17&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Baumgart, Ingmar, and Sebastian Mies. “S/Kademlia: A practicable approach towards secure key-based routing.” 2007 International Conference on Parallel and Distributed Systems. IEEE, 2007. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:17&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:18&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Lesniewski-Laas, Christopher and M. Frans Kaashoek. “Whānau: A Sybil-proof Distributed Hash Table.” 7th USENIX Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation, NSDI 2010, April 28-30, 2010, San Jose, Calif. Version: Author’s final manuscript &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:18&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:19&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“Tonika.” Tonika - P2P Foundation. Accessed May 02, 2019. &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.p2pfoundation.net/Tonika&quot;&gt;https://wiki.p2pfoundation.net/Tonika&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:19&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Viswanath, Bimal, et al. “An analysis of social network-based sybil defenses.” ACM SIGCOMM Computer Communication Review 41.4 (2011): 363-374. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:21&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Cgyarvin. “Cgyarvin/urbit.” GitHub. Accessed May 02, 2019.&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cgyarvin/urbit/blob/6ac688960687aa9c89d4da6fff49a3125c10aca1/Spec/urbit/3-intro.txt&quot;&gt;https://github.com/cgyarvin/urbit/blob/6ac688960687aa9c89d4da6fff49a3125c10aca1/Spec/urbit/3-intro.txt&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:21&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:21:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:22&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“R/urbit - What Will a Star Owner Do?” Reddit. Accessed May 02, 2019.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/urbit/comments/78wean/what_will_a_star_owner_do/&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/urbit/comments/78wean/what_will_a_star_owner_do/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:22&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:22:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:23&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“Primer.” Urbit / Docs. Accessed May 02, 2019.&lt;a href=&quot;https://urbit.org/docs/learn/azimuth/&quot;&gt;https://urbit.org/docs/learn/azimuth/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:23&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:24&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Murphy, Justin. “On Urbit and Exit (featuring Urbit Engineer Ted Blackman).” YouTube. November 24, 2018. Accessed May 02, 2019.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=07LE6SAhUdo&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=07LE6SAhUdo&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:24&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">by Francis Tseng</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Announcing WYFY School with BUFU</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/wyfy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Announcing WYFY School with BUFU" /><published>2019-05-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-05-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/wyfy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/wyfy/">&lt;p&gt;by Taeyoon Choi&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are excited to collaborate with BUFU (By Us For Us). The WYFY (With You For You) School Board of the Wise is a free, online and IRL school for a distributed learning community. We hope to explore new models for collective learning for code, code of ethics and code of conduct, please follow the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bufubyusforus.com/thewyfyschool&quot;&gt;BUFU’s site&lt;/a&gt; for the updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/wyfy/wyfyposter1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/wyfy/wyfyposter2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BUFU is a unique collective of artists, designers, storytellers and organizers. I first learned about BUFU around 2016 and I’ve been following their work closely. BUFU is building cultural solidarity among QTPOC and the wider public, combining art, fashion and music, and recently through technology. BUFU’s events feel different from any other arts and technology events. There’s an electric sense of excitement and radical inclusivity. BUFU’s conceptual approach is fearless and provocative. They explore the intersections of ideas and identifications with grace. Their aesthetic practice is rich and enticing, often combining graphic elements with photo, video and online storytelling. I’m thrilled to collaborate with them and their large community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/wyfy/bufu-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/wyfy/bufu-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/wyfy/bufu-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/wyfy/bufu-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/wyfy/bufu-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photos by Taeyoon Choi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hosted the inaugural “Orientation &amp;amp; Co-creation” at the Data and Society Research Institute (D&amp;amp;S) on May 1, 2019.The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h3azPormLc0&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; is available but forgive us about the poor sound quality. The event was a culmination of long term collaboration with the D&amp;amp;S team. I intended to invite BUFU community to the D&amp;amp;S’s space and encourage them to learn about the D&amp;amp;S’s research on topics such as algorithmic accountability and AI, privacy and security, truth in the age of misinformation. I also wanted my friends at the D&amp;amp;S to experience BUFU’s organizing style and meet their community. The Distributed Web of Care project grew out of my fellowship at the D&amp;amp;S between 2017 - 2018 and it has been an intellectual home for me. The researchers and fellows at the D&amp;amp;S are creating powerful conceptual tools to gain critical perspectives about technology. I hope artists, organizers and creative individuals can utilize &lt;a href=&quot;https://datasociety.net/output/&quot;&gt;their research&lt;/a&gt;, activate it in their practice and to empower their community. A number of D&amp;amp;S researchers and staff participated in the orientation event and contributed to imagining ‘dream schools’. Thanks to Rigo, Audrey, Janet, Sam, Madeline, Erica, Natalie, Eli, Shadi, Sareeta and the Data and Society family.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">by Taeyoon Choi</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Announcing Lecture Performance at the Whitney Museum</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/whitney/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Announcing Lecture Performance at the Whitney Museum" /><published>2019-03-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/whitney</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/whitney/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;by Taeyoon Choi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m excited to present the Distributed Web of Care project with my collaborators and stewards this month in New York City. Hope to meet you there!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://distributedweb.care/static/images/og.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distributed Web of Care at the Whitney Museum of American Art&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WED, Mar 27, 2019
7 pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://whitney.org/events/distributed-web-of-care&quot;&gt;Ticket&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Susan and John Hess Family Gallery and Theater&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lecture-performance by Taeyoon Choi imagines a more equitable, caring Internet and asks: what kind of network do we want for the future? Choi engages in a conversation with Chancey Fleet, Jonathan Dahan, and stewards and students from the School for Poetic Computation to explore the poetics and politics of computation, the relationship between Internet privacy and collective agency, and alternative methods of communicating via peer-to-peer protocols. The discussion considers the Internet’s underlying structure and how bodily experiences of the Internet differ for disability communities and other marginalized groups. The conversation is followed by an interactive performance choreographed by Choi and Jerron Herman, accompanied by live audio from Tiri Kananuruk and stud1nt. The movements explore how it feels to be a node programmed in centralized, decentralized, and distributed networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ASL interpretation and audio description are available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&quot;http://heidilatskydance.org/current-company/g5n1f8y4lv3y48p7afxncbgmwlqbdx&quot;&gt;Jerron Harman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://stud1nt.nyc/&quot;&gt;stud1nt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://xxx.tiri.xxx/&quot;&gt;Tiriree Kananuruk&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://jedahan.com/&quot;&gt;Jonathan Dahan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/ChanceyFleet&quot;&gt;Chancey Fleet&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://sfpc.io&quot;&gt;School for Poetic Computation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bibliography and inspiration: &lt;a href=&quot;http://cultureandcommunication.org/galloway/&quot;&gt;Alexander R. Galloway&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ariciano.com/&quot;&gt;Ari Malenciano&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://callil.com/&quot;&gt;Callil Capuozzo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://christinesunkim.com/&quot;&gt;Christine Sun Kim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://noranahidkhan.com&quot;&gt;Nora Khan&lt;/a&gt;, Cori Kresge, &lt;a href=&quot;http://cleomiao.info/&quot;&gt;Cleo Miao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifewinning.com/&quot;&gt;Ingrid Burrington&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jessicalynne.co/&quot;&gt;Jessica Lynne&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mindyseu.com/&quot;&gt;Mindy Seu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://shannonfinnegan.com/&quot;&gt;Shannon Finnegan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://wordsinspace.net/shannon/&quot;&gt;Shannon Mattern&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.poetryfoundation.org/poets/stephanie-gray&quot;&gt;Stephanie Gray&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%C3%89douard_Glissant&quot;&gt;Édouard Glissant&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stewards: &lt;a href=&quot;http://saltzshaker.github.io&quot;&gt;Emily Saltz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;www.marcusbrittainfleming.com&quot;&gt;Marcus Fleming&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jayspaper.com/&quot;&gt;Suphitcha “Jan” Donsrichan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;carlos-sanchez.info&quot;&gt;Carlos Sanchez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lorihepner.com&quot;&gt;Lori Hepner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://nahee.website/&quot;&gt;Nahee Kim&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;mayaontheinter.net&quot;&gt;Maya Man&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://nataliafloreszalles.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;Natalia Flores Zalles&lt;/a&gt;, Sarah McCaffery, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/chicanocyborg&quot;&gt;Rigoberto Lara&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ashleyjanelewis.com/&quot;&gt;Ashley Jane Lewis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://nitchafa.me/&quot;&gt;Nitcha Fame Tothong&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Production: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.netabomani.com/&quot;&gt;Neta Bomani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.emilymariemiller.com/&quot;&gt;Emily Miller&lt;/a&gt;, Livia Huang, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shira-feldman.net/&quot;&gt;Shira Feldman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://yhsong.com/&quot;&gt;Yen Song&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://cezar.io/&quot;&gt;Cezar Mocan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Whitney Museum of American Art Staff: Andrew Hawkes, Isabelle Dow, Justin Allen, Madison Zalopany, Max Chester, Megan Heuer, Sasha Wortzel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Poster: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/markallenartjams/&quot;&gt;Mark Allen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://taeyoon-workshop.myshopify.com/products/dwc-poster&quot;&gt;Posters&lt;/a&gt; are on sale until April 14, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Postcard: &lt;a href=&quot;http://coraliegourguechon.fr&quot;&gt;Coralie Gourguechon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Support: The Whitney Museum of American Art, &lt;a href=&quot;http://codeforscience.org/&quot;&gt;Code for Science and Society&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://pioneerworks.org&quot;&gt;Pioneer Works&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">by Taeyoon Choi</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Announcing Call for Deaf or Disabled Stewards</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/stewards/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Announcing Call for Deaf or Disabled Stewards" /><published>2019-02-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/stewards</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/stewards/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update May 2019: Applications for this particular call are no longer open, however if you are interested in collaborating with the project please reach out.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distributed Web of Care (DWC) is a collaboration between artists, writers and engineers to imagine a more equitable, caring internet for the future. The project is initiated by Taeyoon Choi, who has been working with disability community and artists to criticially challenge the notions of accessibility and inclusion. Read his article &lt;a href=&quot;https://thenewinquiry.com/artificial-advancements/&quot;&gt;Artificial Advancement&lt;/a&gt; and Shannon Finnegan’s article &lt;a href=&quot;http://distributedweb.care/posts/accessibility-dreams/&quot;&gt;Accessibility Dreams&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/party/decentralizedwebsummitmedia-20180801-session1-1_0085.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In February - March 2019, we are looking for stewards who identify as a Deaf or disabled person. We are planning a large scale participatory performance art in the end of March. The event will have ASL interpretation and audio description. We would like to work with stewards who identify as a Deaf or Disabled person to create an inclusive and welcoming experience for the disability community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/party/decentralizedwebsummitmedia-20180801-session1-1_0085.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A large group of people holding strings&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://decentralizedweb.net/distributed-web-of-care/&quot;&gt;Decentralized Web Summit&lt;/a&gt;, The Internet Archive/San Fransisco Mint, 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/party/mplus.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Group of people holding strings in a theater&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.westkowloon.hk/en/mplus/m-programmes/m-matters-art-and-design-in-the-digital-realm&quot;&gt;M+ Matters&lt;/a&gt;: Art and Design in the Digital Realm, M+/Tai Kwun, Hong Kong, 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/party/CButler-330.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eyebeam.org/events/refiguring-the-future-conference/&quot;&gt;Refiguring the Future&lt;/a&gt;, Eyebeam/REFRESH, Knockdown Center, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From February to March 2019, we are planning a large scale participatory performance art in the end of March. The event will be wheelchair accessible, and will have ASL interpretation and audio description. We would like to work with stewards who identify as a Deaf or disabled person to create an inclusive and welcoming experience for the disability community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stewards are guest collaborators who contribute to DWC initiatives with their domain expertise. Stewards are invited to rehearsals for DWC events and contribute to building the piece as well as code of conduct. In this volunteer role, stewards will collaborate with fellow artists, engineers, organizers, staff and with Taeyoon Choi directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DWC is a movement activity which involves strings and other props, sound and visuals, which requires assistance of stewards to help other participants in the movement activity stay safe. We are asking for stewards to join a rehearsal and the final performance to help the choreographer and other stewards make space for people who identify as disabled to feel welcome, secure and comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our efforts to imagine the future of the internet, we hope to create an inclusive and equitable experience for everyone, however, we understand the impossibility of this as there may be conflict of access needs. In order to be prepared for all contingencies, we are inviting the disability community to be a part of planning and execution of the project. We also hope to avoid creating an unintentionally exclusive experience, therefore stewards mentorship and guidance will help us create a better experience for everyone attending the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rehearsal dates are March 3, 2-5 PM and March 25, 2-5 PM, 2019 in wheelchair accesible locations in Manhattan, NYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://airtable.com/shrJKwgf305PUDKjm&quot;&gt;Apply&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; or email studio@taeyoonchoi.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Equal opportunity:
Distributed Web of Care is committed to providing an environment that is free from discrimination and harassment based on race, age, creed, color, religion, national origin or ancestry, sex, gender, disability, veteran status, genetic information, sexual orientation, gender identity or expression, or pregnancy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Update May 2019: Applications for this particular call are no longer open, however if you are interested in collaborating with the project please reach out.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Making Space in Online Archives</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/online-achives/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Making Space in Online Archives" /><published>2019-02-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/online-achives</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/online-achives/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;by Mindy Seu, DWC Artist in Residence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following is a condensed transcription of a conversational talk given by the author for the Distributed Web of Care workshop series.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My studio experience as a designer focused on interactive installations. While user experience usually connotes people’s movements through an online interface, the phrase could also apply to engagement with physical installations. There are cues that help people navigate a physical environment with a digital layer. This weaving in and out of physical and digital space — which  all could be considered an interface — is a space that should motivate discursion rather than display.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sense of navigation informs how I construct online archives, which I consider a type of activation of a physical site and collection of objects. I would call myself an archival enthusiast, but I’m not a trained archivist, and I would never use the term because it disregards the years of required training. When I first moved to San Francisco, as in all new cities, I sought out used bookstores. Then I fell into a rich library/archival community. While indexes, taxonomy, and categorization have always fascinated me, I was dissatisfied with the use of pre-existing platforms and their navigational structures. Digitized books, regardless of their form or content, were seemingly dumped into templates that used skeuomorphic design (like page turns) and poor UX (like clicking through hundreds of pages).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/mindy/01_mindy.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Image description: L: Jedi Archives, Star Wars: Episode 2, Attack of the Clones // R: Trinity College Library, Dublin”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the Jedi archives from &lt;em&gt;Star Wars: Episode 2, Attack of the Clones.&lt;/em&gt; It looks like a real library, except these book spines have transmissive light. I see this as a metaphor for how people think about digital or online libraries, transplanting shelves onto the screen with a search field, and not necessarily considering how digital space is different. The original library is based off Trinity College Library in Dublin. Physical libraries have a constraint of nesting books next to each other on shelves. And despite this, libraries have an embedded serendipitous discovery. It’s really easy to get lost in a library. There’s nooks, aisles, hidden corners, shelves nested on top of each other. And that depth, even if it’s linear online, is gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Prelinger Library and Archives in San Francisco offers a fascinating example of a physical space that creates its own unique taxonomy as a reflection of their collected objects. Founded by Megan and Rick Prelinger, the library includes obscure printed ephemera for which Megan created a novel indexing system based on geospatial location. At the front of the aisles you have all the books related to San Francisco, based on theme. The further back you move into the library, you travel through different regions and finally land in outer space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the archive exists in physical space, Rick Prelinger offers encouraging insight the digitization of collections. In his &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1JDDanuvz1fJXxhHzD64ymQQ20eMsOWHj/view&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Appropriation Manifesto&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; he writes, “If cultural permaculture is our goal, we might think of finding thoughtful ways to represent and re-contextualize old works. So how can we think of alternative methods for digitizing analog materials into a digital interface or a digital screen.” I embraced this as a move away from templatization online and towards the creation of bespoke interfaces that allow for specific viewing conditions for different types of content, much like the geospatial index adopted in his own collection. Rick also states that “mortar is just as historical as bricks, but we only ever talk about the bricks.” Mortar to bricks. We, lay people, can break these histories apart, add or note what is missing, and then rearrange or reform these bricks for our current climate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/mindy/02_mindy.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Image description: Close-Up: 110 West 40th Street as a domain to note the studio of Herb Lubalin and Ralph Ginzburg in New York ; &lt;a href=&quot;http://avantgarde.110west40th.com&quot;&gt;http://avantgarde.110west40th.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/mindy/03_mindy.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Image description: 110 West 40th Street, New York, present day&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created the &lt;em&gt;Avant Garde&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Fact&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Eros&lt;/em&gt; archival microsites with Jon Gacnik, co-founder of Folder Studio, and Alexander Tochilovsky, curator of the Herb Lubalin Study Center at the Cooper Union. (Note: in the original talk, I explained our decisions for the site interface, redacted here). These publications, created by Ralph Ginzburg and Herb Lubalin in the 1960s-70s, were considered controversial at the time, and led to prison time over a battle with the US Government over obscenity charges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we first launched these sites, I was happy that Laurel [Schwulst] noted the domain name 110west40th.com. Sasha [Alexander Tochilovsky] and I had carefully considered other domain names. It didn’t seem right to name it after one of the co-creators. They have a larger body of work, first of all, and these publications are the result of a collaboration in a physical space. We decided to embed this in the naming structure to ground the online sites in the physical site, their studio in Manhattan on 110 West 40th. When Laurel mentioned it, she included a screenshot of Google Maps of the location which has become a shop called Crisp. The domain was able to narrate a bit of the story about where these three iconic publications were born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/mindy/04_mindy.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Image description: “Mosaic of Subcultures,” image excerpt from A Pattern Language&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chapter “A Mosaic of Subcultures” in &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1vDHRtYnKYzchQtMTZOPQfXOQrepc8LB_/view&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Pattern Language&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, notes the importance of subcultures, which I find helpful to revisit when designing bespoke interfaces and considering online communities. Instead of homogenizing, or templatizing, visible differences in different communities should be embraced. Moving from one space to another should feel unique, representative of the various cultures, people, identities included. These spaces, however, should be small and nested closely together so you can naturally stumble out of one and into another. You can feel aesthetic or tonal shifts; they are not walled gardens. They are open for others who may not be part of the subculture to visit, embracing inclusivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/mindy/05_mindy.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Image description: ASCII Town, A-B-Z-TXT 2017, &lt;a href=&quot;http://ascii.designforthe.net&quot;&gt;http://ascii.designforthe.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This chapter motivated a workshop that I created for &lt;a href=&quot;https://a-b-z.co/&quot;&gt;A-B-Z-TXT&lt;/a&gt; 2017. This computational typography summer school is based in Toronto, created by Michèle Champagne, Garry Ing, and Greg Smith. We named it ASCII Town, or A-B-Z-TWN. After a brief introduction to ASCII art, typewriter art, and concrete poetry, the two hour drawing exercise asked how we might still draw with these gridded, constrained systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/mindy/06_mindy.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Image description: ASCII Town text file, example by Owen Dodd, 2017&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using a humble text editor, participants drew the exterior of their ‘home’ and a room that others could visit after clicking through. Jon [Gacnik] created a script that would aggregate the exteriors on a group landing page and create detail pages of the interiors using simple labels, ‘Outside:’ and ‘Inside:’ in the text file. The only constraint were these labels and the inclusion of their name somewhere on the exterior. Participants could publish by dragging the file into a communal FTP. ASCII Town asks the user to consider alternative interfaces for online communities, and how this change in interaction might affect how we choose to engage with others in digital spaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/mindy/07_mindy.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Image description: Kameelah Rasheed, “On Refusal,” 2016&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an interview on &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thecreativeindependent.com/people/kameelah-janan-rasheed-on-research-and-archiving/&quot;&gt;The Creative Independent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, Kameelah Rasheed states that archiving our histories is a way to actively engage with the way we move through the world. This recenters us, so we think of ourselves as constructed subjects that come from a long lineage of histories that we can reflect back into our personal archives. I think this idea is crucial, particularly when we consider archiving digital space, and the histories of our own constructions online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently a summer fellow at the Internet Archive, co-organizing the Arts Track of the Decentralized Web Summit with Sam Hart. The goal of the Summit at large is to bring together technologists, humanitarians, policy-makers, designers, and artists to discuss the constraints and affordances of various forms of decentralization. For example, with the Dat protocol and Beaker browser, it’s really easy to create and clone a static site or dataset. This feature suggests an invitation to archiving the web, which is noticeably different from ‘scraping’ a site, which is possible but traditionally unauthorized. The Dat and Beaker browser foregrounds cloning and archiving as an essential feature of a decentralized network. Your peers can seed and help host the site. Paul Frazee, a co-founder of Beaker, aptly stated, “Your friends are your data center.” We decide what is valuable, what we want to support, and question what we should read or publish online. While I’m excited about the possibilities, I’m cautious about a technocratic misconception that implementing a decentralized technical or architectural infrastructure will lead to ethical governance or the thoughtful development of culture. How can we reshape online culture as a whole? It’s not like creating a decentralized Facebook will actually make us more connected, even if we do have ownership of our data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Arts Track has a conversation series, installations, workshops, and performances that will try to create accessible points of entry, historicize the movement, and consider novel uses of the decentralized web. It’s nice to see some of those people here too. Laurel Schwulst is co-leading a workshop called p2p2p2p. Melanie Hoff, Callil Capuozzo, and a larger team are creating an interactive installation called Distributed Gardens. Yeli Omayeli Arenyeka is co-leading a workshop that prototypes the DWeb with browser extensions. And Taeyoon Choi, with help from Lai Yi Ohlsen, will kick-off the Summit with a large-scale string network performance of Distributed Web of Care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;qa-audio-transcript-shortened-for-coherence&quot;&gt;Q&amp;amp;A, Audio transcript shortened for coherence.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q: Do you experience tension with making something with a single version or duplication that is reproducible endlessly?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A [Mindy]: Attribution immediately comes to mind. I think it’s fine to duplicate something endlessly if the source material is noted. In some ways, this is what’s great about an open source model. The problem is the difficulty of a precedent that does not include this. I believe it is very important to include this, a clear source or an initial link that is archived to prevent link rot. p2p protocols like dat or platforms like Github allows for this, because you’re cloning something that already exists and a is trail built. Duplication is also important for preservation purposes also. Even at the Internet Archive, where I’m currently a fellow, they have crawlers that click every link and archive every page. They are able to archive the internet once every four months, roughly. It’s only through screenshots, so dynamic content is really hard to capture. But while they have a copy of everything on their servers in the Bay, they have a duplicate in Alexandria and another in an undisclosed location, understandably. The fire at the Library of Alexandria destroyed all of the content it held, and the founder of Internet Archive, Brewster Kahle, will state that this was a key reference for their priority to duplicate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q: When you were talking about your Avant Garde work, you mentioned that you wished the rest of the internet could be more like this. Were you trying to emphasis on idiosyncratic archives?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A [Mindy]: By that statement, I meant I would like things to be comprehensive. When people go to an article, do they actually read the whole text? The way it’s laid out now, in these long scrolls with embedded links, with link rot, most don’t read the entirety. In the essay “How We Read: Close, Hyper, Machine,” N. Katherine Hayles writes about how we scan the first few sentences and then your eyes go down. It could be attributed to short term attention span, but I think we can give people more credit than that. It’s built into the reading structure. So by comprehensive, I meant, yes, make the information more robust, but also, what are ways we can explore different ways that encourage comprehension on the screen. I don’t know if Avant Garde is the best way to do that. But I felt that for this publication, we were trying to be very thoughtful about the interface, so people can keep digging. I’d hope that we can be more thoughtful about digestion and comprehension, instead of speed, whatever form that takes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q: Could talk about the difference between the library and the archive?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A [Mindy]: Can I throw that to you, Zach [Zach Coble, head of the Digital Scholarship Services at the NYU Libraries]?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A [Zach]: I’m a librarian, and I see libraries as being primarily driven by access. If you want a book or an article or a piece of data, libraries will help you get access to them. Whereas archives are driven by preservation. For that book in the archive that you want to read, every time it’s pulled that off the shelf, the archivist is thinking if there’s some damage that’s happened to the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A [Mindy]: I was going to say something similar. I was thinking about inclusivity versus exclusivity. Public libraries are amazing because they’re becoming these new cultural centers, as well as continuing to be a silent space. It is about access. It’s easier to enter a public library rather than an archive — no appointments or white gloves. I feel like there’s a tension between who an archive is for and who created it. It claims to be for community memory, but if it’s inaccessible, it becomes an ethical question about whose memory we are preserving, what we consider valuable, who has the credentials to access it, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A [Taeyoon]: One thing about libraries and archives and their distinction: archives tend to centralize knowledge and power to the institution. Libraries tend to open up and distribute that knowledge and power. While libraries have selection policies, archives tend to be have even more narrow and strict policies about what comes in to the archive. The power of collection leads to preservation, and prioritizing of certain information to last a long time. Take for example, in Los Angeles, The Getty Archive is a very powerful collection of articles and cultural items. It’s a vast resource but it’s not accessible. You need to be a scholar or an authorized person to access the archive. On the other side of town, there’s also a group called Los Angeles Contemporary Archive (&lt;a href=&quot;http://lacarchive.com/&quot;&gt;LACA&lt;/a&gt;), which is an artist-run non-profit organization. LACA takes on a more subversive and grassroots approach to the archive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A [Mindy]: When I mentioned Irit Rogoff and inherited knowledge, that’s exactly what I meant, The same stories are being told over and over, so certain narratives develop cultural capital. That affects what is preserved and what is fixed in history books. Her “response to conditions,” then, is trying to push against these taught histories and how these smaller histories can be told. A strategy for that is, like Taeyoon mentioned, citizen archives and grassroots spaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q: Earlier, you were talking about the difference between digital and physical archives and getting lost in physical spaces. In your work, have you thought about how developers and designers can help users have a serendipitous experience like that online?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A [Mindy]: If you can make your own website, even if it’s ugly and messy, maybe we can reframe it as ugly beautiful. It does give you a lot of power when you see something that you’ve made living in the world. It doesn’t have to be perfect. Does it really matter if something is responsive or snapped to a grid? Maybe that works well for some things but not necessarily for personal voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;readings-for-the-skillshare&quot;&gt;Readings for the skillshare&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1vDHRtYnKYzchQtMTZOPQfXOQrepc8LB_/view&quot;&gt;A Pattern Language, “A Mosaic of Subcultures”&lt;/a&gt; by Christopher Alexander, Sara Ishikawa, and Murray Silverstein&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.e-flux.com/journal/00/68470/turning/&quot;&gt;Turning, “Education”&lt;/a&gt; by Irit Rogoff&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thecreativeindependent.com/people/kameelah-janan-rasheed-on-research-and-archiving/&quot;&gt;Kameelah Rasheed on research and archiving&lt;/a&gt; by Kameelah Rasheed and Brandon Stosuy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://denten.plaintext.in/think.stack/archives&quot;&gt;Archives&lt;/a&gt; excerpt by Dennis Yi Tenen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1JDDanuvz1fJXxhHzD64ymQQ20eMsOWHj/view&quot;&gt;Appropriation: is it finished? A Manifesto&lt;/a&gt; by Rick Prelinger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This essay is based on a skillshare by Mindy Seu on July 8.2018 at the Ace Hotel New York. It’s been edited by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shira-feldman.net/&quot;&gt;Shira Feldman&lt;/a&gt; and published on February 8, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;mindy-seu&quot;&gt;Mindy Seu&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/mindy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mindyseu.com/&quot;&gt;Mindy Seu&lt;/a&gt; is a designer and educator. She is currently a student in Harvard’s Graduate School of Design, where her research focuses on digital archives UI and methods of digitization. Formerly, she was a designer at 2x4 and instructor for Interactive 2 at California College of the Arts.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">by Mindy Seu, DWC Artist in Residence</summary></entry></feed>