<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2019-01-11T13:34:20-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Distributed Web of Care</title><subtitle>DWC </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Residency at LACA</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/laca/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Residency at LACA" /><published>2018-12-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-12-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/laca</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/laca/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Taeyoon Choi will hold a residency at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://lacarchive.com/taeyoon-choi-residency&quot;&gt;Los Angeles Contemporary Archive&lt;/a&gt; located at 709 N Hill Street, Suite 104-8 (upstairs), Los Angeles, CA 90012 between January 12 and 18, 2019.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can we code to care and code carefully? The Distributed Web of Care (DWC) is a research initiative on communication infrastructure, exploring the Distributed Web as a peer-to-peer, alternative web which prioritizes personhood, collective agency and individual ownership of data and code. Initiated by Taeyoon Choi, artist and cofounder of the School for Poetic Computation in NYC,  in collaboration with various artists, writers, technologists and community organizers, DWC imagines distributed networks as a form of interdependence and stewardship, in critical opposition to the network platforms and infrastructures that dominate the world today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At LACA, Taeyoon Choi will focus on archiving the DWC skillshares, performances and parties, and hold a few informal gatherings of LA based practitioners over home cooked meals. Follow their process on the project website and LACA’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/lacarchive/?hl=en&quot;&gt;social media&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;previous-event-at-laca&quot;&gt;Previous event at LACA&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://taeyoonchoi.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/sign-0640-768x512.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://taeyoonchoi.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/sign-0631-768x512.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://taeyoonchoi.com/2017/02/sign-making-workshop-la/&quot;&gt;Sign Making Workshop&lt;/a&gt; in 2017&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Taeyoon Choi will hold a residency at the Los Angeles Contemporary Archive located at 709 N Hill Street, Suite 104-8 (upstairs), Los Angeles, CA 90012 between January 12 and 18, 2019.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Class for Code Societies at SFPC</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/codesocieties/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Class for Code Societies at SFPC" /><published>2018-12-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-12-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/codesocieties</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/codesocieties/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;by Taeyoon Choi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A class at Code Societies Winter 2019 at the School for Poetic Computation in New York City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distributed Web of Care is an initiative to code to care and code carefully. In this class there will engage in three different activities. First, we will investigate centralized, decentralized, distributed and peer to peer networks. We will analyze the popular technology platforms, focusing on its network infrastructure and terms of services. We will compare them with decentralized alternatives such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://datproject.org&quot;&gt;Dat&lt;/a&gt; Peer to Peer Protocol and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scuttlebutt.nz&quot;&gt;Scuttlebutt&lt;/a&gt;. Second, we will take on performative exercises to explore the feeling of being in a network. We will learn to move around in physical space with strings in order to care, not control, each other. Lastly, we will imagine the kinds of network we want for the future and we will discuss how we can build it with code and code of conduct. We will distribute our code and code of conduct as zines in physical print and data, published with Dat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suggested readings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://newrepublic.com/article/133889/reboot-world&quot;&gt;Reboot World&lt;/a&gt; by Paul Ford&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vanityfair.com/culture/2015/01/ray-johnson-art-pranks&quot;&gt;Meet Ray Johnson, the Greatest Artist You’ve Never Heard Of&lt;/a&gt; by Rachel Tashjian&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thecreativeindependent.com/people/laurel-schwulst-my-website-is-a-shifting-house-next-to-a-river-of-knowledge-what-could-yours-be/&quot;&gt;My website is a shifting house next to a river of knowledge. What could yours be?&lt;/a&gt; by Laurel Schwulst&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/zachmandeville/dat-zine-library&quot;&gt;Dat Zine Library&lt;/a&gt; by Zach Mandeville&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://decentralizedweb.net/distributed-web-of-care/&quot;&gt;Distributed Web of Care&lt;/a&gt; by Taeyoon Choi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://distributedweb.care/posts/eaw/&quot;&gt;Ethics and Archiving the Web&lt;/a&gt; by Distributed Web of Care&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hyperallergic.com/474137/at-the-new-york-tech-zine-fair-the-digital-and-the-tactile-converge/&quot;&gt;At the New York Tech Zine Fair, the Digital and the Tactile Converge&lt;/a&gt; by Megan N. Liberty&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/about.html&quot;&gt;Low-tech Magazine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In class, we will use terminal, git and Dat. Please familiarize yourself with using the terminal. The class is based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tchoi8/distributedwebofcare/tree/codesocieties&quot;&gt;a  class&lt;/a&gt; from Summer 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;concepts&quot;&gt;Concepts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intersections of Race – Gender – Environment – Disability justice&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SFPC/codeecologies/tree/master/notes&quot;&gt;Code Ecologies&lt;/a&gt; notes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thenewinquiry.com/artificial-advancements/&quot;&gt;Artificial Advancements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sfpc.io/classes/computingandstories/&quot;&gt;Computing and Stories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@tchoi8/diversity-at-sfpc-d494d7390375&quot;&gt;Diversity at SFPC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Code of Conduct from &lt;a href=&quot;http://etextilespringbreak.org/&quot;&gt;eTextile Spring break&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;keywords&quot;&gt;Keywords&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dat create : You are creating your digital archive.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dat keys: In case you forget your key, you can get it again.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dat share: You will start to seed your archive.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dat sync: You can connect to a remote dat, and live sync to it’s changes. This also results in you sharing the archive even when the original archive is not available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;step-by-step&quot;&gt;Step by step&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Getting set up
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;open up terminal, go to your project directory&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;mkdir datzines&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;cd datzines&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;install &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/get-npm&quot;&gt;npm and node&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;npm install -g dat&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cloning an archive
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;dat clone (Taeyoon’s archive unique hash – revealed in class)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;cd (into the cloned folder)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;ls (show files)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;dat sync&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Taeyoon will update the original archive. Students will see their files synchronizing.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Making your own archive
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;cd ..&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;mrkir yourname_zine&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;cd yourname_zine&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;create zine.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;touch yourname.txt&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;nano yourname.txt&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;dat-zines&quot;&gt;Dat Zines&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guidelines for the zines, appropriated from &lt;a href=&quot;http://designforthe.net/workshops/ascii/index.html&quot;&gt;ASCII Town Workshop&lt;/a&gt; by Mindy Seu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;File must be titled yourfirstnamelastname.txt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;no spaces, all lowercase&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;File must include&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside: 
(for cover of your zine)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside: 
(content of your zine)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;for-outside&quot;&gt;For Outside:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Width: minimum 20 characters, maximum 50 characters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Height: minimum 10 lines, maximum 20 lines&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Include a zine cover with your name so your friends know which zine belongs to you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In your text file, write “Outside:” (make sure you include the colon) above the house you drew, followed by a hard line break.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;for-inside&quot;&gt;For Inside:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below your cover, write “Inside:” followed by a hard line break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Monospaced font&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One size (16 pt)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One weight (no bold, italicized, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One color (black)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No links&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No mark-up&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No motion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is no width or height restriction for the inside of your zine. Use the negative space creatively. Consider creating movement through scale, placement, and scrolling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;publishing&quot;&gt;Publishing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dat share, start publishing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;write your unique key&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Give the key, written on a piece of paper to a TA or Taeyoon, who will clone it into the main archive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;View dat zines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://sfpc.io/static/img/codesocieties/banner.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;code-societies&quot;&gt;Code Societies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SFPC’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://sfpc.io/codesocieties-winter-19/&quot;&gt;Code Societies&lt;/a&gt;, is a winter intensive session organized by Melanie Hoff. Code Societies will examine the ideological and corporeal attributes of computation; concentrating on the poetics and politics of culturally embedded software. How do different platforms and processes — including algorithms, data collection, social media, infrastructure, and interface — yield distinct modes of seeing, thinking, feeling, and reinforce existing systems of power? Through a balanced study of critical theory discussion and hands-on coding workshops, students will create small projects that explore and question these ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SFPC/codesocieties-winter-19&quot;&gt;Code Soceties complete syllabus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">by Taeyoon Choi</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Building a Museum 353 Years in the Future</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/ari/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building a Museum 353 Years in the Future" /><published>2018-12-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-12-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/ari</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/ari/">&lt;p&gt;by Ari Melenciano, DWC Artist in Residence&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally posted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@AriMelenciano_88366/el-museu-de-afrotopolis-building-a-museum-353-years-in-the-future-1cb9d9f668b8&quot;&gt;Ari’s blog&lt;/a&gt; on July 2, 2018, reposted on December 26, 2018 with permission.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An exploration on the eradication of racial oppression in future times, through speculative design and futuristic ideating of a utopian city and society called, Afrotopolis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re fighting for a better future. But what does that future actually look like? What will it feel like when Black Americans are no longer living in intensely toxic situations that have been carefully designed for White American gain? What type of art would Black artists be able to make when we no longer have to simultaneously fulfill our artistic needs while also fighting to push our culture forward? What will happen when automation entirely wipes out the proletariat and a war on current societal standards have erupted? This is a speculative exploration on the future through a Blackness lens on the psycho-geography of afro-futurism and societal design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;part-1&quot;&gt;Part 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As one of the Ace Hotel in New York City &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.acehotel.com/newyork/events-and-spaces/calendar/detail/ace-air-taeyoon-ari-menlenciano/&quot;&gt;Artist-In-Residence&lt;/a&gt; (curated by &lt;a href=&quot;http://taeyoonchoi.com/&quot;&gt;Taeyoon Choi&lt;/a&gt;), I began my 24 hour residency by presenting a &lt;a href=&quot;https://distributedweb.care/posts/skillshares/&quot;&gt;skillshare&lt;/a&gt;, where there were about 15 participants, a mix of artists, designers, activists and engineers, who signed up to participate. The presentation started with a survey of my past works from building cameras, to creating a new media arts, culture and technology festival called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afrotectopia.com/&quot;&gt;Afrotectopia&lt;/a&gt;, to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/aricianoo/status/1002268551582048257&quot;&gt;data visualizations&lt;/a&gt; I’ve built that analyze the relationships between music video cinematography with the rhetoric and sentiments within lyrics. After the survey of past works, I dived into more recent thoughts on the structure of America and the ways these structures have been identified and highlighted within different pieces of art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/01_Ari.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;lets-talk-about-race-oprah-magazine--photographer-chris-buck&quot;&gt;“Let’s Talk About Race” Oprah Magazine | Photographer: Chris Buck&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This survey included monumental work photographed by Chris Buck for the Oprah Magazine (May 2017) that highlights stereotypes and offers an opportunity to reimagine, by reversing them — as well as the hyper-surveillance of Black communities by police, that Jay Z communicates in his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i5fxxMRzi1Q&quot;&gt;Marcy Me&lt;/a&gt; music video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/02_Ari.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;marcy-mejay-z-music-video-screenshots&quot;&gt;Marcy Me — Jay Z (music video screenshots)&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My presentation then shifted to the job of activists and the feelings of being “jaded”. Which, inevitably becomes a sort of Activism Exhaust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/03_Ari.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Activism Exhaust&lt;/em&gt; is the feeling of being “low on fuel” after having exercised various forms of activism for extensive periods of time. It is a frustration that occurs when success and progress within the fights for civil human rights is difficult to identify through standard success metrics. Thankfully, through several conversations with friends and colleagues— I was able to experience necessary paradigm shifts to reinvigorate my sense of possibilities within my own activism work. One included a conversation with Rashida Richardson, a lawyer that spoke on the &lt;em&gt;Black Resistance White Algorithms&lt;/em&gt; panel at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afrotectopia.com/&quot;&gt;Afrotectopia&lt;/a&gt;. In brainstorming possible solutions for the advancement of Black society, she noted how our fight as activists was missing a key element: a constructive and well-researched idea of the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/04_Ari.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;illustration-by-ari-melenciano&quot;&gt;Illustration by Ari Melenciano&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving that conversation inspired me to begin my future activist work by defining an ideal place in time of racial equity and then move backward, creating a series of steps on how to get to this utopia. My thinking shifted from “how do we create a &lt;strong&gt;more&lt;/strong&gt; equitable future for the Black society?” to, “what does an ideal society for Black people &lt;strong&gt;look&lt;/strong&gt; like, and what steps would need to be taken to get there?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this new paradigm, I also spent more time researching digital carceral infrastructure (Jackie Wang’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/carceral-capitalism&quot;&gt;Carceral Capitalism&lt;/a&gt; has become a new favorite), technological automation’s effect on the proletariat, geo-political activism, and different forms of speculative design. Through this lens, I embarked on a more intense analysis of current societal structures, beginning with capitalism and decentralized vs. centralized forms of access — to eventually building my own society and vision for the future, called Afrotopolis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/05_Ari.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/06_Ari.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new paradigm allowed me to dive deeper into an older idea of mine titled, The Afronet — which would serve as a key component in the development of Afrotopolis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Black culture is Black society’s most lucrative export. It is also currently the world’s most profitable culture. Yet, the Black producers of this culture are barely receiving any of the monetary gains, while those that do have the capital to invest in the exploitation of Black culture for capital gain, which are predominately White men, are the only ones truly able to profit off of the culture. It is a cycle of cultural exploitation through racial expropriation via culture vultures funded by venture capitalists who’s ability to exist is off of the backs of poor, Black citizens. So, what sort of tool could be developed to no longer give access to Black culture to the people that do not quintessentially understand it or its history? What sort of system could be developed so that Black culture producers are the only ones profiting off of their creations (or at least profiting the most)? How would America have been able to operate differently if the ability to access a youtube video of Jay Z first required the ability to pass a series of tests analyzing one’s comprehension of Blackness and racial politics? Ideally, the development of The Afronet, would inspire new forms of radical digital activism for other cultures — similar to how the construction and practices of the Black Panther Party inspired the Chicano Brown Berets and Puerto Rican Young Lords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this exploration and development of Afrotopolis, I established a series of common values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/07_Ari.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;values-of-afrotopolis-illustration-by-ari-melenciano&quot;&gt;Values of Afrotopolis, Illustration by Ari Melenciano&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My study progressed to focus on what has currently and previously occurred in various societies around the world — that I feel should be dismantled for the sake of mankind. I began exploring how social media introduces and exercises a form of social capital, and how social media has introduced hyper levels of individualism that may be doing more harm than good. As opposed to collective contribution to a communal society, we are finding odd situations occur — like non-profits of similar objectives competing for the same pool of money (maybe one entity feels that they are more equipped to handle the job than the other — which is understandable, but maybe one group aims for a larger amount of power — which requires a sort of hypocritical oppression of the other) or bureaucracy getting in the way of societal advancement that would better the lives of millions. This ties to a sort of greed (which I believe is current society’s greatest flaw) that is produced by capitalism. Social media has bred a new form of individualism that makes faces and identity a form of currency. It is a type of individualism that is intensely competitive and one that establishes new forms of digital oppression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/08_Ari.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This form of individualism’s most common objective is fame. Fame, i’ve found, is strongly tied to capitalism. What if, in this new society of Afrotopolis, individualism was dismantled and replaced with communal strategy for holistic cultural advancement of all? Would that require the elimination of capitalism? I’m currently not finding a way that fame (in it’s current framework) could succeed without capitalism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These ideas were presented in the skillshare part of the Distributed Web of Care residency. They were followed by an open discussion on afrofuturism, socialism, Blackness, hegemony, decentralized web structures and more — held both inside the Ace Hotel’s Boardroom and in Madison Square Park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/09_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;participants-of-dwc-skillshare-1-photo-by-ari-melenciano&quot;&gt;Participants of DWC Skillshare #1 Photo by Ari Melenciano&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Following photos taken by Taeyoon Choi, and DWC Fellows Cleo Miao and Callil Capuozzo)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/10_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/11_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/12_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/13_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/14_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/15_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/16_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;part-ii&quot;&gt;Part II&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second part of the Distributed Web of Care residency, was a speculative design practice and social experiment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In returning to this idea of &lt;em&gt;Activism Exhaust&lt;/em&gt;, I wanted to give a few of my friends and I a chance to explore a future where we no longer have to be activists of racial oppresion. This exploration tied back to my questions at the beginning of this essay:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What will it feel like when Black Americans are no longer living in intensely toxic situations that have been carefully designed for White American gain? What type of art would Black artists be able to make when we no longer have to simultaneously fulfill our artistic needs while also fighting to push our culture forward? What will happen when automation entirely wipes out the proletariat and a war on current societal standards have erupted?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To speculatively answer these questions, I designed a space for my friends and I to enter and explore with deep imagination, for the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/17_Ari.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;participants-of-el-museo-de-afrotopolis&quot;&gt;Participants of El Museo de Afrotopolis&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/18_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;instant-photos-of-the-artists-of-afrotopolis-2371&quot;&gt;Instant Photos of the Artists of Afrotopolis, 2371&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/19_Ari.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;illustration-by-ari-melenciano-1&quot;&gt;Illustration by Ari Melenciano&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entered into the year, 2371.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the timeline of events:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/20_Ari.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 2100, the massive amounts of investments and research that were being poured into the advancements of technological automation (machine learning and artificial intelligence) had completely wiped out the proletariat — producing an extreme level of poverty, exponentially greater than ever experienced before. As introduced by Walter Mosley in his short read, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.orbooks.com/catalog/folding-red-black-walter-mosley/&quot;&gt;Folding the Read into the Black&lt;/a&gt;, I began to further explore the possibility of AI technology developers being taxed for their productions by metrics of the human labor it has eradicated. By 2150, this taxation on AI would be heavily enforced in attempt to supplement the displacement of the previously existing working class. By 2150, there is a war on capitalism and a true Power to the People Revolution, where the oppressed people of the entire world would unify in the redistribution of access to sustainable living. This would also be the era when the Afronet has fully infiltrated the centralized web network — creating immense amounts of capital for the Black society, right before capitalism is completely destroyed. By 2250, capitalism no longer exists, the tax on automation has eliminated classism by providing all with a bountiful amount of resources to sustain a desired life. Afrotopolis is considered a true Republic of The People, and has completely redefined societal standards — reflecting the Afrotopolis values aforementioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this speculative design experience, the idea was that we had traveled to the year 2371, which was generations further into the future from the war on capitalism and the true Power to the People revolution — leaving the current society in opportunity to relish in this new world of equality in regards to civil rights, distribution of power, and access. Humans alive in the year of 2371 were 353 years removed from the tribulations of today, and deeply immersed in a world that no longer required them to be activists of racial advancement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this context, each participant of the night was then given an entirely new identity and told that they have been invited by the archivists of El Museo de Afrotopolis, to contribute their art into this museum. These moments throughout the experience were possibly the most disorienting as each person in the room currently (today in 2018) creates art that somehow stems from their racial identity, and ways that it oppresses their agency. How would it feel to no longer have that responsibility, but to instead be able to create purely for art’s sake? Would the art we create be purely for art’s sake or would we have other subjects to focus on? We started off with a 45 minute long conversation exploring the possibilities of our new realities, over a group dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/21_Ari.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/22_Ari.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/23.1_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/23_Ari.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then spent the next 30 minutes creating art as we further imagined where we’d artistically communicate from, with this new reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/24_Ari.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;tsige-zen-capturing-for-her-film&quot;&gt;Tsige (Zen) capturing for her film&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/25_Ari.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;artists-at-work&quot;&gt;Artists at work&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/26_Ari.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;artists-at-work-1&quot;&gt;Artists at work&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/27_Ari.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;roxana-migo-at-work&quot;&gt;Roxana (Migo) at work&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/28_Ari.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;tsige-zen-at-work&quot;&gt;Tsige (Zen) at work&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then spent the next 30 minutes sharing our work with one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/29_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;el-museo-de-afrotopolis-archive&quot;&gt;El Museo de Afrotopolis Archive&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/30_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;tao-leigh-goffe&quot;&gt;Tao Leigh Goffe&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/31_Ari.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tao, re-identified as Pumoash, was a dancer, dance coach and urban designer who also enjoyed traveling, going to broadways and baking sweets. Pumoash studied historical games, including Dance Dance Revolution to create, “Dance Dance Revolution Architecture as dancing 2150 Power to the People Revolution as dance dance as revolution urban design + dance.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/32_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;terrell&quot;&gt;Terrell&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/33_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Terrell, re-identified as Yayot, was a digital media artist and painter who professionally practiced computer science and bartending and also enjoyed meditating, drawing and problem solving, in their free time. Yayot created “an interactive tool to compile stories of local customers to capture the stories behind bar visits. Customers tell, bar captures, the tech appropriates data into viable info for population.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/34_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;tsige&quot;&gt;Tsige&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/35_Ari.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
Tsige, re-identified as Zen, was a writer, photographer, and film director who enjoyed gardening, stargazing and debating on politics. Zen made a “meditation with intimacy/love by lil B.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/36_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;roxana-santana&quot;&gt;Roxana Santana&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/37_Ari.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roxana, re-identified as Migo, was a video artist, podcaster, and florist who also enjoyed poetry, drawing flowers, and reading about astronomy. Migo explored botanism and how the creation of a “traditional flower … transitions into freedom of growth.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/38_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/39_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;finding-home-an-immersive-re-discovery-of-identity-through-flavor&quot;&gt;Finding Home: An Immersive re-discovery of Identity Through Flavor&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/40_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;cover-of-recipe-book&quot;&gt;Cover of recipe book&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/41_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;contents-of-recipe-book&quot;&gt;Contents of recipe book&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sandra, re-identified as Oeii, was a writer and journalist for the Afrotropolis Times who was also passionate about the bioengineering of fruits and international recipes. In describing her work, she said, “Art is a written connection of questions and quotes around identity, memory, ancestry, and food. Also, recipes.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/42_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;romil&quot;&gt;Romil&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/43_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Romil, re-identified as Nellano, was a street artist, public sculpture artist and carpenter who enjoyed sculpting with soap bars and watching indie films. For his piece, “Population Projection”, Nellano created an “LED wall with wooden dials. Dials change societal variables to project impacts on population. LED wall also shows historical population changes over time.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/44_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;c-lee&quot;&gt;C. Lee&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/45_Ari.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;twiobi-creator-of-time-travel-robe-exhibits-operation-as-migo-wears-the-robe&quot;&gt;Twiobi, creator of time travel robe, exhibits operation as Migo wears the robe.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Christopher, re-identified as Twiobi, was a seamstress and fashion model who enjoyed collecting stamps and other historical artifacts, hiking and mixing music. Twiobi created a “Metallic time-travel robe with audio clips over the 350 year period when wearer puts on the robe.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/46_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;ari&quot;&gt;Ari&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/47_Ari.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;illustrated-cake-before&quot;&gt;Illustrated Cake (before)&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/48_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;illustrated-cake-after&quot;&gt;Illustrated Cake (after)&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/49_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;woman-001&quot;&gt;Woman 001&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/50_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;woman-002&quot;&gt;Woman 002&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ari (me), re-identified as Mirable, was a cake designer, physicist and molecular scientist who enjoyed cycling, reading vintage sci-fi novels and painting portraits of animals. Through a “series of image manipulations”, Mirable used “part one [to create] illustrations of cakes .. morphed into other objects of abstract form” and “part two [consisted of] photos of Black women of the 21st century … gone through a series of digital distortions — changing their hair and appearance as they attempted to fit into White notions of beauty.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The night brought incredible insight and new alterations to current paradigms of thought. We meditated heavily on thoughts of what the necessary levels of maturity might be needed to experience a night like this (Terrell), how our place in the world changes when we thinking of future societies being descendants of our actions of today (Tsige), what freedom actually means, and what Blackness means absent of oppression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of the audio from the night was recorded, to create a genuine sense of liberty and freedom within our creativity, as well as security and safety within our expression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following morning was spent documenting the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/51_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;ari-me-in-front-of-the-hotel-mirror&quot;&gt;Ari (me) in front of the hotel mirror&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/52_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;entry-in-ace-air-sign-book&quot;&gt;Entry in Ace AIR sign book&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/53_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;photos-from-afrotopolis&quot;&gt;Photos from Afrotopolis&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/54_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;contribution-to-the-ace-air-archive&quot;&gt;Contribution to the Ace AIR archive&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari/55_Ari.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;thank-you-ace-hotel-for-featuring-my-work-on-your-tvs&quot;&gt;Thank you, Ace Hotel, for featuring my work on your TVS.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left the hotel inspired to continue developing and growing the idea of Afrotopolis, with more minds to collaborate with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you Taeyoon Choi, for the opportunity to explore art and technology in my first artist residency. Thank you, Ace Hotel New York City, for the great hospitality. And thank you Christopher, Terrell, Sandra, Tsige, Tao, Romil, and Roxana for joining me in a night of futuristic and experimental thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be more &lt;a href=&quot;https://distributedweb.care/posts/skillshares/&quot;&gt;skillshares&lt;/a&gt; with other Artists in Residence in July and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://distributedweb.care/posts/party/&quot;&gt;The Distributed Web of Care Party&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; will be held at the Liberty Hall at the Ace Hotel New York on July 29th from 3–7pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ari Melenciano is a Brooklyn-based interdisciplinary artist, designer, creative technologist and activist. She recently graduated from NYU’s Interactive Telecommunications Graduate Program (ITP) and will be returning to NYU ITP to be a researcher — focusing on imaginative uses of technology, digital carceral infrastructure, archiving Blackness in new media, and digital activism efforts. Learn more about her work at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ariciano.com/&quot;&gt;www.ariciano.com.&lt;/a&gt; She can also be found on twitter (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/aricianoo&quot;&gt;@ aricianoo&lt;/a&gt;) and instagram (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/ariciano/&quot;&gt;@ ariciano&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">by Ari Melenciano, DWC Artist in Residence</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Finding Intimacy within Black Feminist Criticism</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/findingintimacy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Finding Intimacy within Black Feminist Criticism " /><published>2018-09-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/findingintimacy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/findingintimacy/">&lt;p&gt;by Jessica Lynne, DWC Arist In Residence&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(an evolving statement first commissioned by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.artsinmilwaukee.org/&quot;&gt;Milwaukee Artist Resource Network&lt;/a&gt; in 2017)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://distributedweb.care/static/images/air/jesslynne.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jessica Lynne, on the left with &lt;a href=&quot;http://arts.black/&quot;&gt;ARTS.BLACK&lt;/a&gt; partner, Taylor Aldridge. Photo: Ash Arder.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been spending time with Barbara Smith’s essay, “&lt;a href=&quot;http://webs.wofford.edu/hitchmoughsa/Toward.html&quot;&gt;Towards a Black Feminist Criticism&lt;/a&gt;.” A lot of time, actually. It has become a central point of reference for me recently as I’ve worked to get to the root of my impulses as an art critic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Long before I tried to write this I felt I was attempting to do something unprecedented, something dangerous…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1978, Smith is working towards an impossibility, as she describes, that aims to render visible, through criticism, the literature of Black women writers, especially Black lesbian writers. How does one move against silence(s)? How has the literature of Black women not been served by the larger apparatus of literary criticism (For Smith: white male critics, Black male critics, white woman critics who think of themselves as feminists)? For her part then, Smith puts forth a methodology—the how— that takes seriously the entanglement of race, class, and the politics of sex in any effort to understand the subtleties of Black women’s writing. I like to imagine the following question as subtext: through what lens do you attend to the work of Black women?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1978, I also imagine Smith arguing that even before we get to the how, we must first acknowledge another inquiry: do you attend to the work of Black women? Here I am, almost 40 years after the publishing of this essay feeling like I gotta carry Smith with me at all times as I set priorities for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am often asked: who are you writing for? This question is typically followed by: why do you write? To employ a praxis of Black feminist criticism means that I write to place care around the practices of Black women artists. Their work. Their archives. Their fullness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Criticism, then, is a way of showing up. It is a way of placing intellectual frameworks around the gestures and processes of artists. It is a way of preventing gaps and exclusions. What is most urgent for me now is engaging in a critical practice that moves against silences and undertakes assessments of visual, performance, and literary culture in a manner that centers and prioritizes the complexities of black womanhood(s).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Black feminist criticism would by definition be highly innovative, embodying the daring spirit of the works themselves.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I was in a room full of Black women artists, friends of mine, discussing our big dreams and expressing our big frustrations. “Who is going to do the real thinking about us,” one friend began, “most of this writing is fluff shit.” I nodded my head in agreement. That she made a distinction between the real and the fluff didn’t surprise me. The fluff: surface level analysis, press release regurgitation. The real: deep level, nuanced meditations. “I’m not sure the market is interested in that type of art criticism,” I say. “We’re all writing the same things about the same artist because it’s profitable. It’s a numbers game.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We need a new criticism then,” this friend says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She’s right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, it is true that the job of the critic is to respond in real time. That if an exhibition or gallery show is on view for, let’s say, four months, a strong and early review can be leveraged by an artist for future opportunities. This is especially true for emerging artists (a precarious term but one I will use for the sake of this essay). I will contend here that a strong piece of criticism is not merely one that lauds an artist. It is also a text that contextualizes, proposes new questions, and insightfully articulates what is working and what is not working. On the other hand, as newspapers and magazines shutter their arts coverage and more and more of us cobble together livelihoods from freelance writing or write in addition to full-time jobs ( I am one of these people), it is also true that what is lacking is both time and presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That when my friend calls for a “new criticism” she is calling for a new way by which critics form a relationship to her work. This is to say that, perhaps, a Black Feminist criticism offers a space for this new relationship, one that dares me to slow down and make space for intimacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I only hope that this essay is one way of breaking our silence and our isolation, of helping us to know each other.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a Black woman critic maturing alongside Black women artists. I conduct studio visits with them. I go to their openings and talks and panels. We have our group chats and email threads. They are my peers and colleagues and sounding boards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our exchanges, formal and informal, constitute a necessary, generative meeting point in which we might challenge, provoke, and support one another. I’m not entirely convinced my eye is compromised because of this proximity though such is the argument with which I wrestle. We are women coming from the peripheries and we are seeing one another and we are holding on to one another and we are holding one another accountable. I guess what I’m trying to say is that maybe (art) criticism should also make space for the rigor that can arise when we orient ourselves horizontally. What does criticism look like when we reject the myth that it can only manifest itself in one way? I want to propose that intimacy in criticism serves both a political and aesthetic purpose as it moves us closer to planes of formal experimentation (as in, how does your criticism show up on the page) while allowing for a sustained close reading of a body of work as it unfolds over time in other words, an investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Just as I did not know where to start, I am not sure how to end. I feel that I have tried to say too much and at the same time have left too much unsaid.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll probably return to Smith a few more times before the year ends. Criticism is not static. There is much left to learn. And so, this feels less like an ending and more a righteous beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About the Author:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://distributedweb.care/static/images/air/jess.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://jessicalynne.co&quot;&gt;Jessica Lynne&lt;/a&gt; is a Brooklyn-based writer and art critic. She is co-founder and editor of ARTS.BLACK, a journal of art criticism from Black perspectives. Find her online at @lynne_bias.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">by Jessica Lynne, DWC Arist In Residence</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">still stuck with words</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/stillstuckwithwords/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="still stuck with words" /><published>2018-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/stillstuckwithwords</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/stillstuckwithwords/">&lt;p&gt;by Stephanie Gray, DWC Arist In Residence&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What does it mean to be “stuck with words” or “reading between the lines” or “not reading into anything” as a hearing impaired person? Read on for a poetic exploration…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(from: &lt;em&gt;“&lt;strong&gt;still stuck with language&lt;/strong&gt;, still stuck with words, still stuck with what you know…” (poet Jack Spicer, from one of his lectures)&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;On those words, I’m going to start with a poem:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-with&quot;&gt;WHAT WITH,&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;is how it’s said, how it’s meant, how it’s told, how it’s sent, what with all the what you meant with what got you last time with all the clutter in the air, what with all the things we said we’d never become, we’d never do, we’d never shame, we’d never be game for, what with all those years you said you’d never skip, you’d never cross off with x’s, the what you said you meant with the what with her, and what with him, and what with them, and what with the neighbors upstairs who blast the deep bass boom box til three in the morning, what with your booming dreams that resemble drag car races what does the upstairs boom box matter anyway, what with all the stuff you said what it was that drove home what it was you meant with her, what it was she went without with, you know without with, without with, without with what.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-with-words&quot;&gt;What’s with words?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to be all CliffsNotes-y, but what I’m writing here has to do with language. I know that’s broad. But how I use it (I suppose as a hearing impaired person) for poetry (how I might be suggesting to use it, how I see it used?), its messages between the lines, its repetition, its saying the unsayable; how does it even work with our purposes if we are “still stuck with words”? If they are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;just words&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, then where does the emotion come in? If they are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; words are we always reading in between the lines? &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;That’s a good question…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That phrase (“&lt;em&gt;that’s a good question&lt;/em&gt;”) brings me to: The use of the colloquial as bridging together experimental language and the effect that has on our reading it… What does that mean? This is related to: class. It’s this use of the colloquial that brings me to class, working classness, the speech of that class, that is filtered through my writing…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And on “reading between the lines” and contradictorily, “don’t read into anything” – these colloquialish phrases – which I admit I feel affinity with in this quest to get poetry written:&lt;/strong&gt; If we are to read in between everything we write and say, and also &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; read into anything, are we always sorting through hidden meanings, and if so, what does &lt;strong&gt;that&lt;/strong&gt; mean?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This leads me to think of repetition-&lt;/strong&gt;
Why do it, when outside of the artistic realm, we’ve been told not to, so much of the time (“that’s what you said yesterday” and so forth). Why should artists and poets keep doing it?  This brings up what Gertrude Stein called &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;insistence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Repeating subtle variations to be “heard” about the din of a crowd. Digging thru this insistence through philosophical inflection, and have an epiphany sneak up on you at the end of the poem when you weren’t expecting it. Not that I can perfectly explain how that happens. On being mystified on what mysteries language holds contradictorily in both its &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;breaking apart&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;its words coming together&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.
All of this mixes with what I don’t hear, mishear, and what I want to hear, merging in a full-on experiment. Working with this mix (insistence, repetition, hearing loss…) drives my poetix to getting to the bottom of other concerns of mine in poetry: time-based-ness, nostalgia, dejavu, memory. And with memory(ies), I don’t think we can ever get to the bottom of them. 
All of these investigations lead to a kind of internal rhythm, a kind of music, (but with no sound) in my poetry, a kind of music both figuratively and literally. Perhaps one would expect a person with a hearing loss to not quote so many pop songs, but they’re there, place holders for what couldn’t be said otherwise. So it’s a meta meta &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;what’s been said&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, to say what I wanna say. In this &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;word-music&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; created with the line, the motion of one phrase never really slows, and the prose poem format makes it feel like nothing can afford to stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Then there’s the Schoolhouse Rock effect-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOT THIS BUT THAT&lt;/em&gt; from the song “Conjunction Junction what’s your function” (Schoolhouse Rock was a 70s educational children’s TV show). That phrase and the images of its animated train cars smashing together with the words &lt;em&gt;NotThisButThat&lt;/em&gt; seem to be the CliffsestNotest way I can say what is in my mind when I’m trying to write. How words, ideas, and phrases come together, and my going along or against it. Just like those train cars slamming together.
How to pry open that meaning – when we say “not just this or just that” – what is the space AROUND “just this” or “just that”? It’s a loaded space. Where can you go with it? There’s gazillions of these spaces, this reading between, a space filled with something. Why is this even something to explore, this “space” around the throwaway phrases that only exist with a reading between?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“That’s a good question…”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So is poetry a sophisticated attempt to read between the lines, put it down on paper, so you’re not reading between the lines anymore on one level, but when you start reading between the lines of what is already the poet’s view of reading between the lines, what are we doing then?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A very good question.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The translation that’s involved in reading between the lines, that quiet invisible space.
Now if we were always reading between the lines, which implies finding that hidden truth –  the “real deal” – then – is this what is needed to really “get at”  the heart of something?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A good question.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am going to intercept here with a poem of mine that feels appropriate in this essay’s juncture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This poem is called “I’m telling you don’t forget”:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember who you were&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember what it was&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember what it is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember how it was&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember what it went&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember how it said&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember how it sounded&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember how it went&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember what they did&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember how it goes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember what it meant&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember that’s what she said&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember what it aint&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember who said what&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember what said what&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember who knew who&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember who died then&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember who all knew who&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember what was what&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember who didn’t die&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember who said what they said&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember who didn’t remember you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember who didn’t want to know&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember who tried to change you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember don’t be a cliché here&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember don’t let this poem be 8th grade desperation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember you’re trying to do something with 8th grade desperation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember maybe you can deconstruct 8th grade desperation in a way the language poets would like&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or A Tonalists&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or Quietudes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember, once again, all together now, the more things change the more they stay the same&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember most poets don’t want to hear that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember most news publications have a rule for what not to say&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Including&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more things change the more they stay the same&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember most people will forget you said earlier in this poem it was a sophisticated attempt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To turn around a cliché&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can it be encapsulated in Hey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe, ok?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember maybe these lines need to be more of a mystery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember somebody might be reading between the lines&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember there’s a poem in between the lines&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember in between the lines is where everything happens&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why should I even write&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anything?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An extremely good question.&lt;/strong&gt;   Is it possible to rest our poetics on a question. To think we can. I think we can –let the poetry move long after it has ended. To quote what I just read, “Why should I even write anything.” I just did. So there. Translate as needed. 
It feels like maybe I haven’t really said anything there/here with the some things I said…In these in between the lines, insistences, repetitions…getting at…an &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;un-destination…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; To get at an un-defined space of between the lines. 
Is this &lt;em&gt;reading between&lt;/em&gt; another way to say – that we are trying to use poetry to say the unsayable, to speak the unspeakable, the unexplainable? If that’s what poetry may be …&lt;em&gt;what are we actually saying here?: “Yeah I know it’s unsayable in “regular” language?” So what’s regular?&lt;/em&gt;
Even though I tried to make “reading between the lines” sound all fancy, that is a layperson’s phrase after all which brings me back to filtering class through everything it seems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m curious when it’s said that a poet is “just” playing around with words. Does this mean that wordplay for poets is “just that” there is no deeper relationship to the cumulative effect of the repetition? 
I think I’m surprised by such a question. I think the cumulative effect does do something. That shouting across a loud room to be heard. Or maybe a quiet room with someone who heard you but &lt;em&gt;didn’t hear&lt;/em&gt; you and said HUH? as in &lt;em&gt;WAIT WHAT&lt;/em&gt; are you saying? Then there’s the strait, or bent up reason for repetition for me, of course, my &lt;em&gt;hearing loss.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could be said my poetics practice and filmmaking practice are related. Is there a relationship between the lining up of images together &lt;strong&gt;to&lt;/strong&gt; the lining of sentences or words together (even if are stuck with them?) Probably. And probably because of my hearing loss I “see” images and thoughts moving by like frames, more than I “hear” actual sounds or words. (Well, that is literally; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;internally&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is probably another story.) Yet, I do “hear” gaps and repetition simultaneously when I “see” them. Translating that to my filmmaking practice can mean a similarity when I shoot a recurring image or fade-outs over and over. These film effects could have something in common with how I “&lt;em&gt;hear&lt;/em&gt;” tonal inflection even tho I may not &lt;em&gt;hear&lt;/em&gt; all the words. So if I don’t &lt;em&gt;hear&lt;/em&gt; all the words, in the way that film collects repeated images to be spliced together to make meaning, perhaps the use of repetition invites comparisons to such taping together of film frames (or words/sentences for poetry’s purposes).  Though most of my films actually are “edited in camera”, which means I carefully shoot scene after scene intuitively or like jazz improvisation, and I don’t actually cut the film up afterwards. That could be said is same as what I’m doing in prose poems – with that internal rhythm that’s created – that hopefully should counter prose poem doubters who say the prose poem doesn’t do ENUF with the LINE…The same could be said for edited-in-camera doubters who say those of us who “edit in camera” don’t do ENUF with “editing”. It’s simply a different way of creating  - A WAY OF SEEING, a phrase I’m borrowing from many a poet and filmmaker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I near the end of this essay, what does it truly mean to read between the lines? What exactly is the reading? What exactly are the lines? As a hearing impaired, working class queer, what does it mean for &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt; to “read between the lines” and for others to “read me” between the(se) lines?  To find “the official story”, how far we must “dig” and “re-read” to discover truths – even truths that could be right in our face? Perhaps poetry and film can be ways to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the next time someone tells you to “read between the lines” and to not “read into anything” ask yourself, what does that really mean?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About the Author:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/stephanie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poets/stephanie-gray&quot;&gt;Stephanie Gray&lt;/a&gt; is a poet-filmmaker known for Super 8 films and poetry that explore the experience of urban space, queerness, disability and class. She explores the mysterious ground between pop culture, fact, fiction and desire, while working between nostalgia, place and memory. She is the author of two poetry books, most recently, &lt;em&gt;Shorthand and Electric Language Stars&lt;/em&gt; (Portable Press at Yo-Yo Labs, 2015), and four chapbooks, including &lt;em&gt;Under the Surface&lt;/em&gt; (above/ground press, 2018) and &lt;em&gt;A Country Road Going Back in Your Direction&lt;/em&gt; (Argos Books, 2015). Work also appears in the anthology &lt;em&gt;How Lovely the Ruins&lt;/em&gt; (Spiegel &amp;amp; Grau/Random House, 2017).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">by Stephanie Gray, DWC Arist In Residence</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Distributed Dance Floor</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/distributeddancefloor/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Distributed Dance Floor" /><published>2018-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/distributeddancefloor</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/distributeddancefloor/">&lt;p&gt;by Lai Yi Ohlsen, DWC Steward&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dance floor is a network. Bodies are nodes and the connections between them are edges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; dance floor is distributed. There is no central authority of movement, but we share the principles of the music. Individual bodies contribute to a collective energy and we move to maintain it throughout the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-distributed-dance-floor-has-taught-me-the-following&quot;&gt;The Distributed Dance Floor has taught me the following:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/party/DDFDrawings.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resiliency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peer to peer connections increase the momentum of the network by increasing the number of edges our movement can be shared through. When we dance, we connect and when we connect, we seed. Seeding increases resiliency. The dance floor dies when nodes feel disconnected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authentication&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we dance, we use eye contact to check and verify the authenticity of our peers. While mostly fleeting, it is a way of sharing support and signing our connection into the network. For that moment, nodes become edges and a trust algorithm is performed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Swarming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dance floor is continuously collecting resources in an effort to redistribute them. The distributed web doesn’t centralize around any one dancer for more than a moment; the attention is shared. After we connect around a node, the swarm rejoins the network with connections stronger than before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I see it, there is one fundamental challenge: the dance floor is ephemeral. It is not built to scale. What we grow tonight will not be here tomorrow. And I have wondered - is the same true for a distributed network? Is there a limit to how much we can prioritize care over control?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even if the individual dance floor doesn’t last, the nodes and edges that maintain them do. The distributed web is survived by its dancers. The dance floor is as sustainable as the peer to peer connections it supports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-else-can-we-learn-from-the-distributed-dance-floor&quot;&gt;What else can we learn from the Distributed Dance Floor?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About the Author:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://laiyiohlsen.com&quot;&gt;Lai Yi Ohlsen&lt;/a&gt; is an artist and project manager with a background in movement and computer science.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">by Lai Yi Ohlsen, DWC Steward</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Skillshares: Peers in Practice</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/skillshares/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Skillshares: Peers in Practice" /><published>2018-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/skillshares</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/skillshares/">&lt;p&gt;The Distributed Web of Care presents a skillshare series called &lt;strong&gt;Peers in Practice.&lt;/strong&gt; This series invites the artists in residence at the Ace Hotel to investigate the distribution of power, autonomy and control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through an intimate interactive event, participants and artists will develop a dialog related to their practices by performing acts of collective caring, discussion and documentation.
As a participant in the skillshare, all we require is an open mind and desire to share together. We will be experimenting with different modes of documentation throughout the events. &lt;strong&gt;We will also send out a small set of readings and ask you to generate a few questions based on those readings so we can come together with an informed baseline.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be four skillshares held between July 1st and July 22nd, culminating in a vibrant party in July 29th where the fellows and stewards from the Distributed Web of Care project will present their work on both tools and theory on a web of care, not control. Space is limited for the skillshare event. Please &lt;a href=&quot;https://airtable.com/shrnr16Oq6oalF1S1&quot;&gt;RSVP here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;stephanie-gray-and-eliza-chandler&quot;&gt;Stephanie Gray and Eliza Chandler&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date: 07.22.2018. 1~4pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/skillshare4_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poets/stephanie-gray&quot;&gt;Stephanie Gray&lt;/a&gt; is a poet-filmmaker known for Super 8 films and poetry that explore the experience of urban space, queerness, disability and class. She explores the mysterious ground between pop culture, fact, fiction and desire, while working between nostalgia, place and memory. She is the author of two poetry books, most recently, Shorthand and Electric Language Stars (Portable Press at Yo-Yo Labs, 2015), and four chapbooks, including Under the Surface (above/ground press, 2018) and A Country Road Going Back in Your Direction (Argos Books, 2015). Work also appears in the anthology How Lovely the Ruins (Spiegel &amp;amp; Grau/Random House, 2017).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/skillshare4_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eliza Chandler, an Assistant Professor at the School of Disability Studies at Ryerson University, aims to bring together the arts, disability studies, and justice-based activism. She teaches courses on disability arts and culture, disability rights and justice, and community-based social activism; she is the co-director of the project Bodies in Translation: Activist Art, Technology, and Access to Life, a many-partnered grant supports the development of activist art (including Deaf &amp;amp; disability art, fat art, and Indigenous art) and interrogates its connection to the enactment of social justice. Chandler is a practicing curator, a board member of the Ontario Arts Council, and the co-founder of Creative Users Projects, a community arts/activist initiative that supports crip artists through artistic development and works to create a more accessible arts culture. Prior to these roles, she was the founding artistic director of Tangled Art Gallery, a gallery in Toronto that showcases disability arts and advances accessible curatorial practices. Chandler regularly give lectures, interviews, and consultations related to disability arts, inclusive curatorial practices, and disability politics in Canada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://airtable.com/shrnr16Oq6oalF1S1&quot;&gt;Free, RSVP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All Events - Location: Ace Hotel Boardroom, 20 W 29th St, New York, NY 10001&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The space is accessible via service elevator. Please note your access needs in the RSVP form and ask the front desk for assistance. 7.22 skillshare will have a Communication Access Realtime Translation (CART) service&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;past-events&quot;&gt;Past Events&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;1-ari-melenciano&quot;&gt;#1 Ari Melenciano&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/skillshares1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date: 07.01.2018. 1~4pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ariciano.com/&quot;&gt;Ari Melenciano&lt;/a&gt; is a multidisciplinary artist, designer, creative technologist and DJ. She is a master’s candidate at NYU’s ITP department, practicing at the intersection of experiential design and emerging technologies via creative computation, human-computer interaction, engineering and design. She is the creator and producer of new media arts, culture and technology festival Afrotectopia, as well as the creator of Justice Factory, a data visualization platform that highlights social justice issues and human rights violations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@AriMelenciano_88366/el-museu-de-afrotopolis-building-a-museum-353-years-in-the-future-1cb9d9f668b8&quot;&gt;Building a Museum 353 Years in the Future&lt;/a&gt; by Ari about her residency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;2-mindy-seu&quot;&gt;#2 Mindy Seu&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/skillshares2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date: 07.08.2018. 1~4pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mindyseu.com/&quot;&gt;Mindy Seu&lt;/a&gt; is a designer and educator. She is currently a student in Harvard’s Graduate School of Design, where her research focuses on digital archives UI and methods of digitization. Formerly, she was a designer at 2x4 and instructor for Interactive 2 at California College of the Arts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/workshops.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The skillshare will also include the following short workshops presented by stewards of the DWC project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.laiyiohlsen.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lai Yi Ohlsen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peer to peer protocols require trust and the negotiation of shared resources - so does the dance floor. Webs of moving bodies and sound are an ideal environment to understand how we can, and already do, prioritize care over control within a system. With a good enough groove, peers work together without ever skipping a beat. ‘100 Scores’ by Lai Yi Ohlsen is a repository of improvisational movement scores based upon computer science algorithms. For DWC she will present scores related to the potential of the distributed, peer to peer web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://julianacastro.co/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Juliana Castro&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meme culture and fast-paced social networking have encouraged the use of copyrighted resources without proper attribution. This talk will highlight the benefits of open-access, show a selection of available public domain and Creative Commons archives, and address best practices and fair use uses of institutional repositories and other people’s work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://zachcoble.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zach Coble&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants will engage in a conversation about gathering and using data from the web for social good. The steward will briefly show recent projects and we will use these examples to create a dialog about the legal and ethical issues involved in such projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;3-jessia-lynne-and-shannon-finnegan&quot;&gt;#3 Jessia Lynne and Shannon Finnegan&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date: 07.15.2018. 1~4pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location: Ace Hotel Boardroom, 20 W 29th St, New York, NY 10001&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/skillshare3_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jessicalynne.co/&quot;&gt;Jessica Lynne&lt;/a&gt; is co-founder and editor of ARTS.BLACK, a journal of art criticism from Black perspectives. She received her B.A. in Africana Studies from NYU and has been awarded residencies and fellowships from Art21 and The Cue Foundation, Callaloo, and The Center for Book Arts. Her writing has appeared in publications such as Aperture, Art in America, The Brooklyn Rail, and Kinfolk. She was a Winter 2018 Columnist-in-Residence at &lt;a href=&quot;https://openspace.sfmoma.org/&quot;&gt;Open Space&lt;/a&gt;, SFMoMA’s interdisciplinary publishing platform, and is co-editor, alongside Sharon Louden, of the forthcoming book, The Innovators: Defining Change in the Art World, that will be published by Intellect Ltd. and The University of Chicago Press.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She is a board member of Black Art Futures Fund and The Organization of Women Writers of Africa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/skillshare3_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://shannonfinnegan.com/&quot;&gt;Shannon Finnegan&lt;/a&gt; is an artist whose practice involves a mix of drawing, design and writing. Her current motto is “Reinventing my strangeness as an art form that only I am the perfect practitioner of.” She’s created Anti-Stairs Club Lounge, Disability History PSA, and other projects about disability culture and access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://airtable.com/shrnr16Oq6oalF1S1&quot;&gt;Free, RSVP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are planning to offer skillshares and party in July in partnership with the Ace Hotel New York. We will announce details about workshops and events via Taeyoon Choi’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinyletter.com/tchoi8&quot;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt;. Please join us for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dwc-tchoi8.hashbase.io/posts/party/&quot;&gt;Distributed Web of Care Party&lt;/a&gt; on July 29th.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Distributed Web of Care presents a skillshare series called Peers in Practice. This series invites the artists in residence at the Ace Hotel to investigate the distribution of power, autonomy and control.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Distributed Web of Care Party</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/party/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Distributed Web of Care Party " /><published>2018-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/party</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/party/">&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IDbdPNCSx34?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/party/party.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;July 29th, 5-9pm, 2018&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Liberty Hall at Ace Hotel New York, 20 W 29th St, New York, NY 10001&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Free with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/distributed-web-of-care-party-tickets-47220143721&quot;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The party space is wheelchair accessible via service elevator. Please inquire about access needs. taeyoonstudio@gmail.com&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cash bar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Distributed Web of Care Party will be held at the Liberty Hall at Ace Hotel New York on July 29th from 5-9pm. The party will be a collection of talks, presentations, interactions and music to illustrate the collective power of caring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team of Fellows, Stewards and Artists in residence will all contribute toward sharing their knowledge and expertise in a series of talks concerning the distributed web. These talks will be both technical and abstract, but grounded in the project’s mission:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Care, in contrast to cure, is a form of stewardship between people who support each other in communication, action, and social engagement. It is actualized by extending one’s mindfulness of another person’s dignity and feelings, while respecting their independence.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the talks, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laiyiohlsen.com/&quot;&gt;Lai Yi Ohlsen&lt;/a&gt; will lead a distributed dance. &lt;a href=&quot;http://laurelschwulst.com/&quot;&gt;Laurel Schwulst&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdxs.ist/&quot;&gt;Becca Abbe&lt;/a&gt; will be doing live drawing with code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event will progress into dancing and socializing with music curated by the multi-instrumental artist and DJ &lt;a href=&quot;http://stud1nt.nyc/&quot;&gt;stud1nt&lt;/a&gt; of Discwoman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/party/unnamed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;stud1nt is a multi-disciplinary sound artist from Queens. Their work sits at the intersection of improvisation and meticulous approaches to composition. A member of the collectives #KUNQ and Discwoman, their work is especially attentive to queerness, the body, sound, and space. stud1nt has given workshops on creative production at Vassar College, the New School, Recess Art, Pioneer Works, Moogfest, and Ableton Loop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The timing of the event is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5:00-6:30pm
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Talks and Discussion about care, distribution and publishing in the context of the distributed web by Taeyoon, Callil and Cleo&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6:30-7:00pm
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Collective Poetry and Distribution with &lt;a href=&quot;http://distributedweb.care/posts/skillshares/&quot;&gt;Distributed Web of Care Team&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7:00-7:30pm
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Movement as Peers with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laiyiohlsen.com/&quot;&gt;Lai Yi Ohlsen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Music with &lt;a href=&quot;http://stud1nt.nyc/&quot;&gt;Stud1nt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7:30-8:00pm
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Live Code Cameras with &lt;a href=&quot;http://laurelschwulst.com/&quot;&gt;Laurel Schwulst&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdxs.ist/&quot;&gt;Becca Abbe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Music with &lt;a href=&quot;http://stud1nt.nyc/&quot;&gt;Stud1nt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8:00-9:00pm
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Hang out!&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Music with &lt;a href=&quot;http://stud1nt.nyc/&quot;&gt;Stud1nt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party will be governed by the DWC &lt;a href=&quot;https://dwc-tchoi8.hashbase.io/posts/coc/&quot;&gt;code of conduct&lt;/a&gt;. It is open to the public and free with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/distributed-web-of-care-party-tickets-47220143721&quot;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Communities and new infrastructures</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/cleo/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Communities and new infrastructures" /><published>2018-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/cleo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/cleo/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/fellows/cleoimg.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;by Cleo, DWC fellow&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some things I am thinking about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the role and importance of communities in the access of information&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;communications through communities vs. information curated by platforms and medias&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;offline communities vs. online communities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;locality of the net&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;integration of the offline and the online&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ownership of information and related power structures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google exited China when I was just about to enter middle school in a small city somewhat close to Shanghai. That was around the time when I really started using the Internet. I was made aware of the importance of the freedom to access information in the digital age and started to see technology as an alternative possibility for that freedom. When censorship is done in the analog world (an example would be books banned from circulation in any market or library), the information being controlled is very hard to access. However, in the case of digital censorship, the counteraction can be easier and safer. Tools such as VPNs provide easy access to locally censored information while offering anonymity to users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, these technologies can be alienating and exclusive. For most of the general public with an Internet connection, the loss of Google did not have a substantial effect. But because of the government’s central control over digital information and the public’s need for open knowledge and discourse, the Internet in China grew into a very different thing then in most of the western countries. Even though there is a bootleg version of Facebook that was popular very briefly, it was forgotten quickly. There seem to be somewhat less of an interest in creating a version of real identities and connections virtually, and more of one in creating and discovering new communities through channels of online communication. Forums and chat groups became an important part of online activities for a lot of people. These forums and private chat groups are still monitored and censored by the government. After sensitive topics and keywords come up in a group chat, the chat group would usually get deleted. Even then, people were able to come up with alternative terms that address the same subjects without hitting the keyword detections. These forums therefore are becoming important channels for knowledge and discourse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I moved to the states for college. I went to a computer engineering program that was very competitive. Having gone into the program because of a fascination towards the poetics of computing, I soon became very disillusioned. My peers were the people who wanted to build digital infrastructures, but many of them fail to think about the communities being affected by the infrastructures outside of being either users or a part of the datasets. Everyone was concerned with efficiency and marketing, but few thought about the ethics of coding and algorithmic bias. During my first months in the program, I was told by almost every professor for the engineering classes I took that the program would be hard, but the financial payout was promising. I became skeptical of the approach taken by core engineering programs and the disconnect between the general social science classes and the technical classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was introduced to experimental music and performance art and started going to shows in living rooms, basements, and alternative venues. Around the same time I moved to Boston and transferred into a studio art program. I started booking and running shows as well as performing in them. I was excited by the ecology of these subculture communities and the focus on ideals and inclusivity. This extends to the larger creative community, but is unique in its dependency on a gift economy. A small group of people actively participate through creative endeavors, contribute through small donations, and usually both. This community thrives on the idea of supporting and caring for each other. However, communication is largely based on proprietary platforms that can limit the freedom of such communication while contradicting (or at least poorly reflecting) the idea of caring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/fellows/cleoprj.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jennifer Vanilla performing at Becoming Posthuman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Becoming Posthuman was an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/events/174088576497818/&quot;&gt;event&lt;/a&gt; I co-curated last year. I was trying to use the model of DIY underground shows on a new media art show. My own &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cleomiao.info/archive/&quot;&gt;art practice&lt;/a&gt; involves playful investigation of technology both critically and romantically. Recently I have been &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1OQQ7lqCsw5mOKZOpSKZjapr4D6AtghZNhZgfCs_jTYc/edit&quot;&gt;thinking&lt;/a&gt; a lot about how art like mine can exist within the larger art world. Is it necessary to adapt to the old institution and create tangible artifacts that a gallery can sell, or is it more important to establish new institutions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditional functions of art spaces see art as merchandise, and unavoidably have to consider the function of art for its patronage. Most of the art being made will not enter art museums. The end result of most art should not be as decoration in a private home or in an inconsequential semi-public space (such as hotels and offices).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The first thing that has to be conserved or even created is a situation where art can be seen and accessed. Why is this so? Because art is not art if it cannot be seen.- Hito Steyerl.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new structure for creative communities and the art world at large should consider a redistribution of power that is conscious of the post-internet context and what that means for the process of learning, creating, and dispersion. The distinction between the artists and the curator becomes vague. Traditionally, the curator represents the institutions. As art and curation integrate with each other, maybe it is time to think about a collective approach / strategy as a more sustainable model for creative communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was introduced to the idea of distributed systems by a friend who was looking into creating a mesh network in areas in Boston. Mesh networks immediately became interesting to me. It creates an ecosystem that promotes communities that are both offline and online. It allows for offline local communities to expand to a local “online” and vice versa. This is interesting in that it strengthens and broadens offline communities by creating another channel for communication, while adding an element of caring to digital connections. A similar case can be made for a distributed internet. Besides the expansion of communities, it also gives each member more access and control over information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One important question that was brought up during a conversation about potential mesh networks in Boston is how to make people want to use it. How do we make a tool accessible to anyone, and not just the technologists?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something that has to be considered. These distributed systems are exciting new infrastructures that can subvert power structures and give the power of data and information back to the people. In developing these new infrastructures, we need to build with care and consideration of communities.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Gardens</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/callil/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Gardens" /><published>2018-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/callil</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/callil/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/fellows/callil1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;by Callil, DWC fellow&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was young I lived next to a Biodynamic farm and intentional living community in upstate NY. I was able to freely roam through orchards, cropped fields and small gardens. As I spent time in these environments, unbeknownst to me I was brushing up against embedded knowledge by proxy. In the biodynamic context, the soil, plants and animals are seen as interrelated and dynamic. A farmer or gardener becomes steward of plants with the goal of creating a healthy and holistic system. Biodynamic stewardship comes through not only in caring for the plants,but also in the social structures that makes this approach possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that the Biodynamic framework was never explicitly taught, only implicitly discovered by participating in the farming. These abstract teachings were discovered mostly by stumbling on to the day of harvest. Now, years later this implicit knowledge, and the methods used to disseminate this knowledge is re-emerging for me in the context of my practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/fellows/callil2.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;My garden this morning&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I have been working on my garden here in Brooklyn. In many ways, I still carry with me a lot of the knowledge from the biodynamic context. One method I’ve been experimenting with is called the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wintergreenstudios.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/09/Three-Sisters-Garden.pdf&quot;&gt;Three Sisters&lt;/a&gt;, a technique I was exposed to by hearing this story…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;2&quot;&gt;2.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Corn, the oldest sister, was said to grow strong and proud. Squash, the youngest sister, crouched at the feet of the other two, keeping them protected from predators. Beans, the middle sister leaned on her older sister for support and twined the three together.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.essentialseeds.us/pdfs/the_three_sisters_growing_guide_1.1.pdf&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The act of seeding the Three Sisters is an act of stewardship &amp;amp; guidance that plays with the inherent strengths of each plant and the ecosystem it is part of. Recognizing these symbiotic structures is something that is important in the context of both farming and organizing social structures - so too is the practice of care and maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately I find myself in our current digital context seeking the spaces and communities where new narratives can be written that feel more like biodynamic farming or methods passed down through oral traditions. Maybe together we can make spaces where implicit knowledge is conveyed through the cultivated expression of a holistic point of view. One concrete example of a space where there is potential to create these new narratives is within the distributed web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though the usefulness of extending the metaphor of gardening to the distributed web can only take us so far, here are a few elements of the holistic practice of gardening that we might learn from to stretch the boundaries of the normative patterns in our digital spaces today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The notion of time and seasons as a forcing function for growth, death, rest and rebirth. Maybe as a rejection of the vectorized ideal of technology (uni-directional and totalizing)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slowness and patience in waiting for the development of one’s self and people around you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Seeding and cultivation as an intentional act with a clear understanding of the substrate in which it happens.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sanctuary and reflection related to spaces of calm, quiet and safety.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sustenance related to the growth of communities and knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The relationship between social structures and knowledge, especially knowledge that is embedded in practice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;3&quot;&gt;3.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeking out these patterns within a tech centered practice is one way of putting into practice some of the ideas above. This might take the form of using &lt;a href=&quot;https://hardlyeverything.com/&quot;&gt;tools&lt;/a&gt; that ask different things from you or designing &lt;a href=&quot;https://thecreativeindependent.com/notes/arena-tci-how-do-you-use-the-internet-mindfully/&quot;&gt;systems for your self&lt;/a&gt;. It might also look like organizing events and communities where ideas for a different kind of web can be experimented with and embodied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/fellows/callil3.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/fellows/callil4.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I helped organize an event called &lt;a href=&quot;https://peer-to-peer-web.com/nyc&quot;&gt;Peer-to-Peer Web NYC&lt;/a&gt; at SFPC - for the event my friend &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phil-cao.com/&quot;&gt;Phil Cao&lt;/a&gt; created this poster that uses plants, and flowers in bloom to represent our point of view of what the distributed web might be. During the event, we invited a wide range of local participants to share their projects and practices to illustrate how concepts of seeding, leeching, pollination texture and more can become profound ways of looking at what it means for diverse expressions of the web to form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also been participating in and organizing for groups like &lt;a href=&quot;https://nycmesh.net/&quot;&gt;NYCMesh&lt;/a&gt;. These groups serve as a fertile place to think about new approaches to technology; imagine if the distribution of knowledge was more like a folk tale rather than a singular post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;4&quot;&gt;4.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only recently have I been able to begin asking myself questions like: What are the materials we have to explore and what does it mean to view our digital spaces holistically? What are other disciplines beyond the digital sphere we might look towards?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When considering the concept of the distributed web, we might look towards both the metaphor and practice of gardening and farming. I hope that we can show how building for digital spaces requires respect, patience, and a real awareness of the environment around you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe we can write some new folk tales together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I was walking through a new garden. As I passed each plant they turned to me and smiled - the corn, being tall, had to bend down and said to me: “Come sit and while. I’ll tell you the story of how far my pollen has traveled, the bees that visit me and the minerals that help me grow. They are all connected and we can be too.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/fellows/callil5.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A seeder set up by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/louiscenter&quot;&gt;Louis Center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tchoi8&quot;&gt;Taeyoon Choi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tinanguyen_&quot;&gt;Tina Nguyen&lt;/a&gt;, Livia Huang and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/automaticyes&quot;&gt;Alexander Singh&lt;/a&gt; for their fantastic feedback and edits.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;References:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cultureandcommunication.org/galloway/anti-computer&quot;&gt;http://cultureandcommunication.org/galloway/anti-computer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://digital.library.upenn.edu/women/buffalo/garden/garden.html&quot;&gt;http://digital.library.upenn.edu/women/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://newcomputers.group/ready2use.html&quot;&gt;https://newcomputers.group/ready2use.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>