<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2018-07-26T17:13:03-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Distributed Web of Care</title><subtitle>DWC </subtitle><entry><title type="html">still stuck with words</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/stillstuckwithwords/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="still stuck with words" /><published>2018-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/stillstuckwithwords</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/stillstuckwithwords/">&lt;p&gt;by Stephanie Gray, DWC Arist In Residence&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What does it mean to be “stuck with words” or “reading between the lines” or “not reading into anything” as a hearing impaired person? Read on for a poetic exploration…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;still-stuck-with-words&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;still stuck with words&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(from: &lt;em&gt;“&lt;strong&gt;still stuck with language&lt;/strong&gt;, still stuck with words, still stuck with what you know…” (poet Jack Spicer, from one of his lectures)&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;On those words, I’m going to start with a poem:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-with&quot;&gt;WHAT WITH,&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;is how it’s said, how it’s meant, how it’s told, how it’s sent, what with all the what you meant with what got you last time with all the clutter in the air, what with all the things we said we’d never become, we’d never do, we’d never shame, we’d never be game for, what with all those years you said you’d never skip, you’d never cross off with x’s, the what you said you meant with the what with her, and what with him, and what with them, and what with the neighbors upstairs who blast the deep bass boom box til three in the morning, what with your booming dreams that resemble drag car races what does the upstairs boom box matter anyway, what with all the stuff you said what it was that drove home what it was you meant with her, what it was she went without with, you know without with, without with, without with what.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-with-words&quot;&gt;What’s with words?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to be all CliffsNotes-y, but what I’m writing here has to do with language. I know that’s broad. But how I use it (I suppose as a hearing impaired person) for poetry (how I might be suggesting to use it, how I see it used?), its messages between the lines, its repetition, its saying the unsayable; how does it even work with our purposes if we are “still stuck with words”? If they are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;just words&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, then where does the emotion come in? If they are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; words are we always reading in between the lines? &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;That’s a good question…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That phrase (“&lt;em&gt;that’s a good question&lt;/em&gt;”) brings me to: The use of the colloquial as bridging together experimental language and the effect that has on our reading it… What does that mean? This is related to: class. It’s this use of the colloquial that brings me to class, working classness, the speech of that class, that is filtered through my writing…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And on “reading between the lines” and contradictorily, “don’t read into anything” – these colloquialish phrases – which I admit I feel affinity with in this quest to get poetry written:&lt;/strong&gt; If we are to read in between everything we write and say, and also &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; read into anything, are we always sorting through hidden meanings, and if so, what does &lt;strong&gt;that&lt;/strong&gt; mean?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This leads me to think of repetition-&lt;/strong&gt;
Why do it, when outside of the artistic realm, we’ve been told not to, so much of the time (“that’s what you said yesterday” and so forth). Why should artists and poets keep doing it?  This brings up what Gertrude Stein called &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;insistence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Repeating subtle variations to be “heard” about the din of a crowd. Digging thru this insistence through philosophical inflection, and have an epiphany sneak up on you at the end of the poem when you weren’t expecting it. Not that I can perfectly explain how that happens. On being mystified on what mysteries language holds contradictorily in both its &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;breaking apart&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;its words coming together&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.
All of this mixes with what I don’t hear, mishear, and what I want to hear, merging in a full-on experiment. Working with this mix (insistence, repetition, hearing loss…) drives my poetix to getting to the bottom of other concerns of mine in poetry: time-based-ness, nostalgia, dejavu, memory. And with memory(ies), I don’t think we can ever get to the bottom of them. 
All of these investigations lead to a kind of internal rhythm, a kind of music, (but with no sound) in my poetry, a kind of music both figuratively and literally. Perhaps one would expect a person with a hearing loss to not quote so many pop songs, but they’re there, place holders for what couldn’t be said otherwise. So it’s a meta meta &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;what’s been said&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, to say what I wanna say. In this &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;word-music&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; created with the line, the motion of one phrase never really slows, and the prose poem format makes it feel like nothing can afford to stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Then there’s the Schoolhouse Rock effect-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOT THIS BUT THAT&lt;/em&gt; from the song “Conjunction Junction what’s your function” (Schoolhouse Rock was a 70s educational children’s TV show). That phrase and the images of its animated train cars smashing together with the words &lt;em&gt;NotThisButThat&lt;/em&gt; seem to be the CliffsestNotest way I can say what is in my mind when I’m trying to write. How words, ideas, and phrases come together, and my going along or against it. Just like those train cars slamming together.
How to pry open that meaning – when we say “not just this or just that” – what is the space AROUND “just this” or “just that”? It’s a loaded space. Where can you go with it? There’s gazillions of these spaces, this reading between, a space filled with something. Why is this even something to explore, this “space” around the throwaway phrases that only exist with a reading between?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“That’s a good question…”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So is poetry a sophisticated attempt to read between the lines, put it down on paper, so you’re not reading between the lines anymore on one level, but when you start reading between the lines of what is already the poet’s view of reading between the lines, what are we doing then?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A very good question.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The translation that’s involved in reading between the lines, that quiet invisible space.
Now if we were always reading between the lines, which implies finding that hidden truth –  the “real deal” – then – is this what is needed to really “get at”  the heart of something?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A good question.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am going to intercept here with a poem of mine that feels appropriate in this essay’s juncture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This poem is called “I’m telling you don’t forget”:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember who you were&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember what it was&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember what it is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember how it was&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember what it went&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember how it said&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember how it sounded&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember how it went&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember what they did&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember how it goes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember what it meant&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember that’s what she said&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember what it aint&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember who said what&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember what said what&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember who knew who&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember who died then&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember who all knew who&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember what was what&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember who didn’t die&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember who said what they said&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember who didn’t remember you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember who didn’t want to know&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember who tried to change you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember don’t be a cliché here&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember don’t let this poem be 8th grade desperation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember you’re trying to do something with 8th grade desperation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember maybe you can deconstruct 8th grade desperation in a way the language poets would like&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or A Tonalists&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or Quietudes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember, once again, all together now, the more things change the more they stay the same&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember most poets don’t want to hear that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember most news publications have a rule for what not to say&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Including&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more things change the more they stay the same&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember most people will forget you said earlier in this poem it was a sophisticated attempt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To turn around a cliché&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can it be encapsulated in Hey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe, ok?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember maybe these lines need to be more of a mystery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember somebody might be reading between the lines&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember there’s a poem in between the lines&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remember in between the lines is where everything happens&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why should I even write&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;       Anything?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An extremely good question.&lt;/strong&gt;   Is it possible to rest our poetics on a question. To think we can. I think we can –let the poetry move long after it has ended. To quote what I just read, “Why should I even write anything.” I just did. So there. Translate as needed. 
It feels like maybe I haven’t really said anything there/here with the some things I said…In these in between the lines, insistences, repetitions…getting at…an &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;un-destination…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; To get at an un-defined space of between the lines. 
Is this &lt;em&gt;reading between&lt;/em&gt; another way to say – that we are trying to use poetry to say the unsayable, to speak the unspeakable, the unexplainable? If that’s what poetry may be …&lt;em&gt;what are we actually saying here?: “Yeah I know it’s unsayable in “regular” language?” So what’s regular?&lt;/em&gt;
Even though I tried to make “reading between the lines” sound all fancy, that is a layperson’s phrase after all which brings me back to filtering class through everything it seems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m curious when it’s said that a poet is “just” playing around with words. Does this mean that wordplay for poets is “just that” there is no deeper relationship to the cumulative effect of the repetition? 
I think I’m surprised by such a question. I think the cumulative effect does do something. That shouting across a loud room to be heard. Or maybe a quiet room with someone who heard you but &lt;em&gt;didn’t hear&lt;/em&gt; you and said HUH? as in &lt;em&gt;WAIT WHAT&lt;/em&gt; are you saying? Then there’s the strait, or bent up reason for repetition for me, of course, my &lt;em&gt;hearing loss.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could be said my poetics practice and filmmaking practice are related. Is there a relationship between the lining up of images together &lt;strong&gt;to&lt;/strong&gt; the lining of sentences or words together (even if are stuck with them?) Probably. And probably because of my hearing loss I “see” images and thoughts moving by like frames, more than I “hear” actual sounds or words. (Well, that is literally; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;internally&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is probably another story.) Yet, I do “hear” gaps and repetition simultaneously when I “see” them. Translating that to my filmmaking practice can mean a similarity when I shoot a recurring image or fade-outs over and over. These film effects could have something in common with how I “&lt;em&gt;hear&lt;/em&gt;” tonal inflection even tho I may not &lt;em&gt;hear&lt;/em&gt; all the words. So if I don’t &lt;em&gt;hear&lt;/em&gt; all the words, in the way that film collects repeated images to be spliced together to make meaning, perhaps the use of repetition invites comparisons to such taping together of film frames (or words/sentences for poetry’s purposes).  Though most of my films actually are “edited in camera”, which means I carefully shoot scene after scene intuitively or like jazz improvisation, and I don’t actually cut the film up afterwards. That could be said is same as what I’m doing in prose poems – with that internal rhythm that’s created – that hopefully should counter prose poem doubters who say the prose poem doesn’t do ENUF with the LINE…The same could be said for edited-in-camera doubters who say those of us who “edit in camera” don’t do ENUF with “editing”. It’s simply a different way of creating  - A WAY OF SEEING, a phrase I’m borrowing from many a poet and filmmaker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I near the end of this essay, what does it truly mean to read between the lines? What exactly is the reading? What exactly are the lines? As a hearing impaired, working class queer, what does it mean for &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt; to “read between the lines” and for others to “read me” between the(se) lines?  To find “the official story”, how far we must “dig” and “re-read” to discover truths – even truths that could be right in our face? Perhaps poetry and film can be ways to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the next time someone tells you to “read between the lines” and to not “read into anything” ask yourself, what does that really mean?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About the Author:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/stephanie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poets/stephanie-gray&quot;&gt;Stephanie Gray&lt;/a&gt; is a poet-filmmaker known for Super 8 films and poetry that explore the experience of urban space, queerness, disability and class. She explores the mysterious ground between pop culture, fact, fiction and desire, while working between nostalgia, place and memory. She is the author of two poetry books, most recently, &lt;em&gt;Shorthand and Electric Language Stars&lt;/em&gt; (Portable Press at Yo-Yo Labs, 2015), and four chapbooks, including &lt;em&gt;Under the Surface&lt;/em&gt; (above/ground press, 2018) and &lt;em&gt;A Country Road Going Back in Your Direction&lt;/em&gt; (Argos Books, 2015). Work also appears in the anthology &lt;em&gt;How Lovely the Ruins&lt;/em&gt; (Spiegel &amp;amp; Grau/Random House, 2017).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">by Stephanie Gray, DWC Arist In Residence</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Distributed Dance Floor</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/distributeddancefloor/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Distributed Dance Floor" /><published>2018-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/distributeddancefloor</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/distributeddancefloor/">&lt;p&gt;by Lai Yi Ohlsen, DWC Steward&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dance floor is a network. Bodies are nodes and the connections between them are edges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; dance floor is distributed. There is no central authority of movement, but we share the principles of the music. Individual bodies contribute to a collective energy and we move to maintain it throughout the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-distributed-dance-floor-has-taught-me-the-following&quot;&gt;The Distributed Dance Floor has taught me the following:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/party/DDFDrawings.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resiliency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peer to peer connections increase the momentum of the network by increasing the number of edges our movement can be shared through. When we dance, we connect and when we connect, we seed. Seeding increases resiliency. The dance floor dies when nodes feel disconnected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authentication&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we dance, we use eye contact to check and verify the authenticity of our peers. While mostly fleeting, it is a way of sharing support and signing our connection into the network. For that moment, nodes become edges and a trust algorithm is performed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Swarming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dance floor is continuously collecting resources in an effort to redistribute them. The distributed web doesn’t centralize around any one dancer for more than a moment; the attention is shared. After we connect around a node, the swarm rejoins the network with connections stronger than before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I see it, there is one fundamental challenge: the dance floor is ephemeral. It is not built to scale. What we grow tonight will not be here tomorrow. And I have wondered - is the same true for a distributed network? Is there a limit to how much we can prioritize care over control?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even if the individual dance floor doesn’t last, the nodes and edges that maintain them do. The distributed web is survived by its dancers. The dance floor is as sustainable as the peer to peer connections it supports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-else-can-we-learn-from-the-distributed-dance-floor&quot;&gt;What else can we learn from the Distributed Dance Floor?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About the Author:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://laiyiohlsen.com&quot;&gt;Lai Yi Ohlsen&lt;/a&gt; is an artist and project manager with a background in movement and computer science.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">by Lai Yi Ohlsen, DWC Steward</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Skillshares: Peers in Practice</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/Cabal/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Skillshares: Peers in Practice" /><published>2018-07-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/Cabal</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/Cabal/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;cabal&quot;&gt;Cabal&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;joining-a-distributed-private-chat-room&quot;&gt;Joining a distributed (private) chat room!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/dat/cabal.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Callil, DWC fellow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start with a catch phrase, such as : “Have you ever felt like you need a more private chat room? Have you ever felt like the internet is listening to your conversation, and suggesting product adverstiements? We may have an alternative, private chat room. It requires a bit of set up, but it’s worth explorting!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the options available is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cabal-club/cabal&quot;&gt;Cabal&lt;/a&gt;, which is a messaging client for the terminal that is like a lightweight, DIY, Punk slack! To get started chatting on the distributed web, you’ll need to use Dat. We are going to walk through setting up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But first, what is Dat? And how does this work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://datproject.org/&quot;&gt;Dat&lt;/a&gt; is a peer to peer data sharing protocol that allows people to collectively distribute and access data. Cabal is an example of a open source, distributed app with no central servers and distributed model of ownership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Cabal, a simple database file is initially created and shared to store chat messages. When a new user joins a cabal, they make a copy of this database file on their machine and become peers of this data through the Dat network. When a new message is shared to the network (the swarm) all the peers that are online will make a copy of that record in the database on their local machine. Each person in the Cabal helps keep the data online and shares the responsibility for hosting the chat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is in stark contrast to many messaging services which require advertisements or paid plans to maintain the database of message and persistant availability. Recently, Slack’s AWS instances went down cutting off thousands of teams from access to their main communication tool. Slack’s free option also limits teams to 10,000 messages - this puts messaging data behind paywall. A peer to peer chat app like Cabal alleviates both of these pain points by eliminating a single point of failure (as long as one peer is online, the chat is up) and puts the ownership &amp;amp; responsibility of hosting in the hands of every participant in the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In principle this would mean that the users are free from the burden of finding central hosting and retain ownership over their community’s data. It’s important to point out that there are a lot of complexities around privacy and owndership which Cabal doesn’t yet fully address. For instance, the current database model allows anyone to modify the chat history, and there is no way to kick or ban misbehaving users. For an extremely large chat, although unlikley right now, the data might grow very large over time taking up space on your machine or take some time to sync from the peer network. There are other valid concerns about the security risks of using distributed systems. For now, let’s consider the possibilities and risks objectively, and explore what’s possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If each person owns the network, what changes about the financial model needed to maintain a network? For instance, do we really want advertisement driven social networks? What dynamics would change when the users own the data? Also how does a community enforce code of conducts and best behaviors without central control? Maybe we can think about how we might solve some of the social and intentity issues present in these spaces through building examples of healthy and creative distributed communities together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s get started…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[insert image of a computer person asking a question]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Already have npm installed? Type this in your terminal to join our chatroom.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;npm install -g npx &amp;amp;&amp;amp; npx cabal --key dat://e0413ba557a81fa2d07f2969eb8e0e689ebf670a2c73d59637f9e192f1ae3704&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;install-node-version-manager-by-pasting-this-code-into-your-terminal&quot;&gt;Install node version manager by pasting this code into your terminal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you use macosx, you can open terminal from the finder, click the magnifying glass, and type finder. 
A small box will pop open. This is your door to the inner workings of the computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And copy and paste this code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;curl -o- https://raw.githubusercontent.com/creationix/nvm/v0.33.11/install.sh | bash&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/dat/cabal.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will install node version manager on your machine, we have found that this is important to ensure that npm works with the least amount of problems on your machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow the instructions when the script completes and restart your terminal session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;install-node-on-your-machine&quot;&gt;Install node on your machine&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What is node?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We need node because&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run this script to install node.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nvm install node&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should see something like this in your terminal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
Downloading and installing node v10.6.0...
Downloading https://nodejs.org/dist/v10.6.0/node-v10.6.0-darwin-x64.tar.xz...
######################################################################## 100.0%
Computing checksum with shasum -a 256
Checksums matched!
Now using node v10.6.0 (npm v6.1.0)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can test whether you have npm installed correctly by typing &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;npm -v&lt;/code&gt; and you should see something like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;6.1.0&lt;/code&gt; returned in your console.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-a-directory&quot;&gt;Make a directory&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Already know how to do this? Make a directory and cd into it to install cabal then &lt;a href=&quot;#4&quot;&gt;go to the install instructions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We now need to decide on a place to store our cabal chat app. You might choose to make a folder called &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;p2p&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dat&lt;/code&gt; inside of which we will put cabal. To do this, you’ll need to understand a bit about navigating your computer’s file structure through the terminal. We can use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; (change directory) and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mkdir&lt;/code&gt; (make directory) to do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ illustration of a person going into a folder with cd ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new terminal session will usually start at &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;~&lt;/code&gt; which is the root directory of your computer. This is the most zoomed out you can be in this part of your computer. Inside of this directory (folder) there are other folders like your Desktop, Documents or any other folders you’d placed there. If you’d like to get a sense of what’s in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;~&lt;/code&gt;, type &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt; (which means list) into your terminal and hit enter. You should see a list of directories. This list shows you what you can &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Type &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cd Documents&lt;/code&gt; to change directories into your Documents folder. Inside of the Documents folder, we can now make a new directory called Dat by typing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mkdir Dat &amp;amp;&amp;amp; cd Dat&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This line says &lt;em&gt;“make a new directory called Dat and change directory to this new directory”&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;install-cabal-&quot;&gt;Install Cabal &lt;a name=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are going to clone the cabal files from github into our new Dat folder - this is like downloading an app, but instead we get a collection of files. To grab the latest from github run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git clone https://github.com/cabal-club/cabal.git &amp;amp;&amp;amp; cd cabal&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will install cabal and then open the folder. Next we need to install the dependencies to run the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;npm install&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[insert gif of install screen ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might take a bit, wait for the progress bar to complete. When it’s done, you’re ready to start chatting with us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;node cli.js --key dat://e0413ba557a81fa2d07f2969eb8e0e689ebf670a2c73d59637f9e192f1ae3704&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll join the chat with the name &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;conspirator&lt;/code&gt;. You can see how to change this by typing &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/help&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance to change your name, type &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/nick your_new_name&lt;/code&gt;. Send us a message in the default channel to say hi!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;write more about How to use chat in Cabal.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There’s a way to make new channels. You type /j newchannel and…&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-also, you can jump between the channels by control&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[final graphic of a group of people chatting on distributed web]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;final questions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some more questions for us to consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to have a private conversation? you’d need to make your own chat group with cabal. - how to do it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are the features you wish to see in the program?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;prevent users changing their names to be like someone else, privacy, integrity of information isses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;easier install and access&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;phone apps, or SMS based text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Cabal Joining a distributed (private) chat room!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Skillshares: Peers in Practice</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/skillshares/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Skillshares: Peers in Practice" /><published>2018-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/skillshares</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/skillshares/">&lt;p&gt;The Distributed Web of Care presents a skillshare series called &lt;strong&gt;Peers in Practice.&lt;/strong&gt; This series invites the artists in residence at the Ace Hotel to investigate the distribution of power, autonomy and control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through an intimate interactive event, participants and artists will develop a dialog related to their practices by performing acts of collective caring, discussion and documentation.
As a participant in the skillshare, all we require is an open mind and desire to share together. We will be experimenting with different modes of documentation throughout the events. &lt;strong&gt;We will also send out a small set of readings and ask you to generate a few questions based on those readings so we can come together with an informed baseline.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be four skillshares held between July 1st and July 22nd, culminating in a vibrant party in July 29th where the fellows and stewards from the Distributed Web of Care project will present their work on both tools and theory on a web of care, not control. Space is limited for the skillshare event. Please &lt;a href=&quot;https://airtable.com/shrnr16Oq6oalF1S1&quot;&gt;RSVP here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;stephanie-gray-and-eliza-chandler&quot;&gt;Stephanie Gray and Eliza Chandler&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date: 07.22.2018. 1~4pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/skillshare4_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poets/stephanie-gray&quot;&gt;Stephanie Gray&lt;/a&gt; is a poet-filmmaker known for Super 8 films and poetry that explore the experience of urban space, queerness, disability and class. She explores the mysterious ground between pop culture, fact, fiction and desire, while working between nostalgia, place and memory. She is the author of two poetry books, most recently, Shorthand and Electric Language Stars (Portable Press at Yo-Yo Labs, 2015), and four chapbooks, including Under the Surface (above/ground press, 2018) and A Country Road Going Back in Your Direction (Argos Books, 2015). Work also appears in the anthology How Lovely the Ruins (Spiegel &amp;amp; Grau/Random House, 2017).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/skillshare4_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eliza Chandler, an Assistant Professor at the School of Disability Studies at Ryerson University, aims to bring together the arts, disability studies, and justice-based activism. She teaches courses on disability arts and culture, disability rights and justice, and community-based social activism; she is the co-director of the project Bodies in Translation: Activist Art, Technology, and Access to Life, a many-partnered grant supports the development of activist art (including Deaf &amp;amp; disability art, fat art, and Indigenous art) and interrogates its connection to the enactment of social justice. Chandler is a practicing curator, a board member of the Ontario Arts Council, and the co-founder of Creative Users Projects, a community arts/activist initiative that supports crip artists through artistic development and works to create a more accessible arts culture. Prior to these roles, she was the founding artistic director of Tangled Art Gallery, a gallery in Toronto that showcases disability arts and advances accessible curatorial practices. Chandler regularly give lectures, interviews, and consultations related to disability arts, inclusive curatorial practices, and disability politics in Canada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://airtable.com/shrnr16Oq6oalF1S1&quot;&gt;Free, RSVP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All Events - Location: Ace Hotel Boardroom, 20 W 29th St, New York, NY 10001&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The space is accessible via service elevator. Please note your access needs in the RSVP form and ask the front desk for assistance. 7.22 skillshare will have a Communication Access Realtime Translation (CART) service&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;past-events&quot;&gt;Past Events&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;1-ari-melenciano&quot;&gt;#1 Ari Melenciano&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/skillshares1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date: 07.01.2018. 1~4pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ariciano.com/&quot;&gt;Ari Melenciano&lt;/a&gt; is a multidisciplinary artist, designer, creative technologist and DJ. She is a master’s candidate at NYU’s ITP department, practicing at the intersection of experiential design and emerging technologies via creative computation, human-computer interaction, engineering and design. She is the creator and producer of new media arts, culture and technology festival Afrotectopia, as well as the creator of Justice Factory, a data visualization platform that highlights social justice issues and human rights violations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@AriMelenciano_88366/el-museu-de-afrotopolis-building-a-museum-353-years-in-the-future-1cb9d9f668b8&quot;&gt;Building a Museum 353 Years in the Future&lt;/a&gt; by Ari about her residency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;2-mindy-seu&quot;&gt;#2 Mindy Seu&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/skillshares2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date: 07.08.2018. 1~4pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mindyseu.com/&quot;&gt;Mindy Seu&lt;/a&gt; is a designer and educator. She is currently a student in Harvard’s Graduate School of Design, where her research focuses on digital archives UI and methods of digitization. Formerly, she was a designer at 2x4 and instructor for Interactive 2 at California College of the Arts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/workshops.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The skillshare will also include the following short workshops presented by stewards of the DWC project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.laiyiohlsen.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lai Yi Ohlsen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peer to peer protocols require trust and the negotiation of shared resources - so does the dance floor. Webs of moving bodies and sound are an ideal environment to understand how we can, and already do, prioritize care over control within a system. With a good enough groove, peers work together without ever skipping a beat. ‘100 Scores’ by Lai Yi Ohlsen is a repository of improvisational movement scores based upon computer science algorithms. For DWC she will present scores related to the potential of the distributed, peer to peer web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://julianacastro.co/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Juliana Castro&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meme culture and fast-paced social networking have encouraged the use of copyrighted resources without proper attribution. This talk will highlight the benefits of open-access, show a selection of available public domain and Creative Commons archives, and address best practices and fair use uses of institutional repositories and other people’s work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://zachcoble.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zach Coble&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants will engage in a conversation about gathering and using data from the web for social good. The steward will briefly show recent projects and we will use these examples to create a dialog about the legal and ethical issues involved in such projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;3-jessia-lynne-and-shannon-finnegan&quot;&gt;#3 Jessia Lynne and Shannon Finnegan&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date: 07.15.2018. 1~4pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location: Ace Hotel Boardroom, 20 W 29th St, New York, NY 10001&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/skillshare3_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jessicalynne.co/&quot;&gt;Jessica Lynne&lt;/a&gt; is co-founder and editor of ARTS.BLACK, a journal of art criticism from Black perspectives. She received her B.A. in Africana Studies from NYU and has been awarded residencies and fellowships from Art21 and The Cue Foundation, Callaloo, and The Center for Book Arts. Her writing has appeared in publications such as Aperture, Art in America, The Brooklyn Rail, and Kinfolk. She was a Winter 2018 Columnist-in-Residence at &lt;a href=&quot;https://openspace.sfmoma.org/&quot;&gt;Open Space&lt;/a&gt;, SFMoMA’s interdisciplinary publishing platform, and is co-editor, alongside Sharon Louden, of the forthcoming book, The Innovators: Defining Change in the Art World, that will be published by Intellect Ltd. and The University of Chicago Press.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She is a board member of Black Art Futures Fund and The Organization of Women Writers of Africa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/skillshare3_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://shannonfinnegan.com/&quot;&gt;Shannon Finnegan&lt;/a&gt; is an artist whose practice involves a mix of drawing, design and writing. Her current motto is “Reinventing my strangeness as an art form that only I am the perfect practitioner of.” She’s created Anti-Stairs Club Lounge, Disability History PSA, and other projects about disability culture and access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://airtable.com/shrnr16Oq6oalF1S1&quot;&gt;Free, RSVP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are planning to offer skillshares and party in July in partnership with the Ace Hotel New York. We will announce details about workshops and events via Taeyoon Choi’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinyletter.com/tchoi8&quot;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt;. Please join us for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dwc-tchoi8.hashbase.io/posts/party/&quot;&gt;Distributed Web of Care Party&lt;/a&gt; on July 29th.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Distributed Web of Care presents a skillshare series called Peers in Practice. This series invites the artists in residence at the Ace Hotel to investigate the distribution of power, autonomy and control.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Distributed Web of Care Party</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/party/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Distributed Web of Care Party " /><published>2018-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/party</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/party/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/party/party.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;July 29th, 5-9pm, 2018&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Liberty Hall at Ace Hotel New York, 20 W 29th St, New York, NY 10001&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Free with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/distributed-web-of-care-party-tickets-47220143721&quot;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The party space is wheelchair accessible via service elevator. Please inquire about access needs. taeyoonstudio@gmail.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Distributed Web of Care Party will be held at the Liberty Hall at Ace Hotel New York on July 29th from 5-9pm. The party will be a collection of talks, presentations, interactions and music to illustrate the collective power of caring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team of Fellows, Stewards and Artists in residence will all contribute toward sharing their knowledge and expertise in a series of talks concerning the distributed web. These talks will be both technical and abstract, but grounded in the project’s mission:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Care, in contrast to cure, is a form of stewardship between people who support each other in communication, action, and social engagement. It is actualized by extending one’s mindfulness of another person’s dignity and feelings, while respecting their independence.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the talks, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laiyiohlsen.com/&quot;&gt;Lai Yi Ohlsen&lt;/a&gt; will lead a distributed dance. &lt;a href=&quot;http://laurelschwulst.com/&quot;&gt;Laurel Schwulst&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdxs.ist/&quot;&gt;Becca Abbe&lt;/a&gt; will be doing live drawing with code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event will progress into dancing and socializing with music curated by the multi-instrumental artist and DJ &lt;a href=&quot;http://stud1nt.nyc/&quot;&gt;stud1nt&lt;/a&gt; of Discwoman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/party/unnamed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;stud1nt is a multi-disciplinary sound artist from Queens. Their work sits at the intersection of improvisation and meticulous approaches to composition. A member of the collectives #KUNQ and Discwoman, their work is especially attentive to queerness, the body, sound, and space. stud1nt has given workshops on creative production at Vassar College, the New School, Recess Art, Pioneer Works, Moogfest, and Ableton Loop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The timing of the event is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5:00-6:30pm
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Talks and Discussion about care, distribution and publishing in the context of the distributed web by Taeyoon, Callil and Cleo&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6:30-7:00pm
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Collective Poetry and Distribution with &lt;a href=&quot;http://distributedweb.care/posts/skillshares/&quot;&gt;Distributed Web of Care Team&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7:00-7:30pm
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Movement as Peers with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laiyiohlsen.com/&quot;&gt;Lai Yi Ohlsen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Music with &lt;a href=&quot;http://stud1nt.nyc/&quot;&gt;Stud1nt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7:30-8:00pm
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Live Code Cameras with &lt;a href=&quot;http://laurelschwulst.com/&quot;&gt;Laurel Schwulst&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdxs.ist/&quot;&gt;Becca Abbe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Music with &lt;a href=&quot;http://stud1nt.nyc/&quot;&gt;Stud1nt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8:00-9:00pm
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Hang out!&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Music with &lt;a href=&quot;http://stud1nt.nyc/&quot;&gt;Stud1nt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party will be governed by the DWC &lt;a href=&quot;https://dwc-tchoi8.hashbase.io/posts/coc/&quot;&gt;code of conduct&lt;/a&gt;. It is open to the public and free with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/distributed-web-of-care-party-tickets-47220143721&quot;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Communities and new infrastructures</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/cleo/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Communities and new infrastructures" /><published>2018-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/cleo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/cleo/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/fellows/cleoimg.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;by Cleo, DWC fellow&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some things I am thinking about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the role and importance of communities in the access of information&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;communications through communities vs. information curated by platforms and medias&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;offline communities vs. online communities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;locality of the net&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;integration of the offline and the online&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ownership of information and related power structures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google exited China when I was just about to enter middle school in a small city somewhat close to Shanghai. That was around the time when I really started using the Internet. I was made aware of the importance of the freedom to access information in the digital age and started to see technology as an alternative possibility for that freedom. When censorship is done in the analog world (an example would be books banned from circulation in any market or library), the information being controlled is very hard to access. However, in the case of digital censorship, the counteraction can be easier and safer. Tools such as VPNs provide easy access to locally censored information while offering anonymity to users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, these technologies can be alienating and exclusive. For most of the general public with an Internet connection, the loss of Google did not have a substantial effect. But because of the government’s central control over digital information and the public’s need for open knowledge and discourse, the Internet in China grew into a very different thing then in most of the western countries. Even though there is a bootleg version of Facebook that was popular very briefly, it was forgotten quickly. There seem to be somewhat less of an interest in creating a version of real identities and connections virtually, and more of one in creating and discovering new communities through channels of online communication. Forums and chat groups became an important part of online activities for a lot of people. These forums and private chat groups are still monitored and censored by the government. After sensitive topics and keywords come up in a group chat, the chat group would usually get deleted. Even then, people were able to come up with alternative terms that address the same subjects without hitting the keyword detections. These forums therefore are becoming important channels for knowledge and discourse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I moved to the states for college. I went to a computer engineering program that was very competitive. Having gone into the program because of a fascination towards the poetics of computing, I soon became very disillusioned. My peers were the people who wanted to build digital infrastructures, but many of them fail to think about the communities being affected by the infrastructures outside of being either users or a part of the datasets. Everyone was concerned with efficiency and marketing, but few thought about the ethics of coding and algorithmic bias. During my first months in the program, I was told by almost every professor for the engineering classes I took that the program would be hard, but the financial payout was promising. I became skeptical of the approach taken by core engineering programs and the disconnect between the general social science classes and the technical classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was introduced to experimental music and performance art and started going to shows in living rooms, basements, and alternative venues. Around the same time I moved to Boston and transferred into a studio art program. I started booking and running shows as well as performing in them. I was excited by the ecology of these subculture communities and the focus on ideals and inclusivity. This extends to the larger creative community, but is unique in its dependency on a gift economy. A small group of people actively participate through creative endeavors, contribute through small donations, and usually both. This community thrives on the idea of supporting and caring for each other. However, communication is largely based on proprietary platforms that can limit the freedom of such communication while contradicting (or at least poorly reflecting) the idea of caring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/fellows/cleoprj.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jennifer Vanilla performing at Becoming Posthuman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Becoming Posthuman was an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/events/174088576497818/&quot;&gt;event&lt;/a&gt; I co-curated last year. I was trying to use the model of DIY underground shows on a new media art show. My own &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cleomiao.info/archive/&quot;&gt;art practice&lt;/a&gt; involves playful investigation of technology both critically and romantically. Recently I have been &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1OQQ7lqCsw5mOKZOpSKZjapr4D6AtghZNhZgfCs_jTYc/edit&quot;&gt;thinking&lt;/a&gt; a lot about how art like mine can exist within the larger art world. Is it necessary to adapt to the old institution and create tangible artifacts that a gallery can sell, or is it more important to establish new institutions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditional functions of art spaces see art as merchandise, and unavoidably have to consider the function of art for its patronage. Most of the art being made will not enter art museums. The end result of most art should not be as decoration in a private home or in an inconsequential semi-public space (such as hotels and offices).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The first thing that has to be conserved or even created is a situation where art can be seen and accessed. Why is this so? Because art is not art if it cannot be seen.- Hito Steyerl.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new structure for creative communities and the art world at large should consider a redistribution of power that is conscious of the post-internet context and what that means for the process of learning, creating, and dispersion. The distinction between the artists and the curator becomes vague. Traditionally, the curator represents the institutions. As art and curation integrate with each other, maybe it is time to think about a collective approach / strategy as a more sustainable model for creative communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was introduced to the idea of distributed systems by a friend who was looking into creating a mesh network in areas in Boston. Mesh networks immediately became interesting to me. It creates an ecosystem that promotes communities that are both offline and online. It allows for offline local communities to expand to a local “online” and vice versa. This is interesting in that it strengthens and broadens offline communities by creating another channel for communication, while adding an element of caring to digital connections. A similar case can be made for a distributed internet. Besides the expansion of communities, it also gives each member more access and control over information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One important question that was brought up during a conversation about potential mesh networks in Boston is how to make people want to use it. How do we make a tool accessible to anyone, and not just the technologists?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something that has to be considered. These distributed systems are exciting new infrastructures that can subvert power structures and give the power of data and information back to the people. In developing these new infrastructures, we need to build with care and consideration of communities.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Gardens</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/callil/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Gardens" /><published>2018-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/callil</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/callil/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/fellows/callil1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;by Callil, DWC fellow&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was young I lived next to a Biodynamic farm and intentional living community in upstate NY. I was able to freely roam through orchards, cropped fields and small gardens. As I spent time in these environments, unbeknownst to me I was brushing up against embedded knowledge by proxy. In the biodynamic context, the soil, plants and animals are seen as interrelated and dynamic. A farmer or gardener becomes steward of plants with the goal of creating a healthy and holistic system. Biodynamic stewardship comes through not only in caring for the plants,but also in the social structures that makes this approach possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that the Biodynamic framework was never explicitly taught, only implicitly discovered by participating in the farming. These abstract teachings were discovered mostly by stumbling on to the day of harvest. Now, years later this implicit knowledge, and the methods used to disseminate this knowledge is re-emerging for me in the context of my practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/fellows/callil2.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;My garden this morning&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I have been working on my garden here in Brooklyn. In many ways, I still carry with me a lot of the knowledge from the biodynamic context. One method I’ve been experimenting with is called the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wintergreenstudios.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/09/Three-Sisters-Garden.pdf&quot;&gt;Three Sisters&lt;/a&gt;, a technique I was exposed to by hearing this story…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;2&quot;&gt;2.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Corn, the oldest sister, was said to grow strong and proud. Squash, the youngest sister, crouched at the feet of the other two, keeping them protected from predators. Beans, the middle sister leaned on her older sister for support and twined the three together.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.essentialseeds.us/pdfs/the_three_sisters_growing_guide_1.1.pdf&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The act of seeding the Three Sisters is an act of stewardship &amp;amp; guidance that plays with the inherent strengths of each plant and the ecosystem it is part of. Recognizing these symbiotic structures is something that is important in the context of both farming and organizing social structures - so too is the practice of care and maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately I find myself in our current digital context seeking the spaces and communities where new narratives can be written that feel more like biodynamic farming or methods passed down through oral traditions. Maybe together we can make spaces where implicit knowledge is conveyed through the cultivated expression of a holistic point of view. One concrete example of a space where there is potential to create these new narratives is within the distributed web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though the usefulness of extending the metaphor of gardening to the distributed web can only take us so far, here are a few elements of the holistic practice of gardening that we might learn from to stretch the boundaries of the normative patterns in our digital spaces today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The notion of time and seasons as a forcing function for growth, death, rest and rebirth. Maybe as a rejection of the vectorized ideal of technology (uni-directional and totalizing)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slowness and patience in waiting for the development of one’s self and people around you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Seeding and cultivation as an intentional act with a clear understanding of the substrate in which it happens.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sanctuary and reflection related to spaces of calm, quiet and safety.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sustenance related to the growth of communities and knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The relationship between social structures and knowledge, especially knowledge that is embedded in practice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;3&quot;&gt;3.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeking out these patterns within a tech centered practice is one way of putting into practice some of the ideas above. This might take the form of using &lt;a href=&quot;https://hardlyeverything.com/&quot;&gt;tools&lt;/a&gt; that ask different things from you or designing &lt;a href=&quot;https://thecreativeindependent.com/notes/arena-tci-how-do-you-use-the-internet-mindfully/&quot;&gt;systems for your self&lt;/a&gt;. It might also look like organizing events and communities where ideas for a different kind of web can be experimented with and embodied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/fellows/callil3.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/fellows/callil4.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I helped organize an event called &lt;a href=&quot;https://peer-to-peer-web.com/nyc&quot;&gt;Peer-to-Peer Web NYC&lt;/a&gt; at SFPC - for the event my friend &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phil-cao.com/&quot;&gt;Phil Cao&lt;/a&gt; created this poster that uses plants, and flowers in bloom to represent our point of view of what the distributed web might be. During the event, we invited a wide range of local participants to share their projects and practices to illustrate how concepts of seeding, leeching, pollination texture and more can become profound ways of looking at what it means for diverse expressions of the web to form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also been participating in and organizing for groups like &lt;a href=&quot;https://nycmesh.net/&quot;&gt;NYCMesh&lt;/a&gt;. These groups serve as a fertile place to think about new approaches to technology; imagine if the distribution of knowledge was more like a folk tale rather than a singular post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;4&quot;&gt;4.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only recently have I been able to begin asking myself questions like: What are the materials we have to explore and what does it mean to view our digital spaces holistically? What are other disciplines beyond the digital sphere we might look towards?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When considering the concept of the distributed web, we might look towards both the metaphor and practice of gardening and farming. I hope that we can show how building for digital spaces requires respect, patience, and a real awareness of the environment around you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe we can write some new folk tales together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I was walking through a new garden. As I passed each plant they turned to me and smiled - the corn, being tall, had to bend down and said to me: “Come sit and while. I’ll tell you the story of how far my pollen has traveled, the bees that visit me and the minerals that help me grow. They are all connected and we can be too.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/fellows/callil5.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A seeder set up by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/louiscenter&quot;&gt;Louis Center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tchoi8&quot;&gt;Taeyoon Choi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tinanguyen_&quot;&gt;Tina Nguyen&lt;/a&gt;, Livia Huang and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/automaticyes&quot;&gt;Alexander Singh&lt;/a&gt; for their fantastic feedback and edits.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;References:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cultureandcommunication.org/galloway/anti-computer&quot;&gt;http://cultureandcommunication.org/galloway/anti-computer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://digital.library.upenn.edu/women/buffalo/garden/garden.html&quot;&gt;http://digital.library.upenn.edu/women/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://newcomputers.group/ready2use.html&quot;&gt;https://newcomputers.group/ready2use.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Announcing Summer 2018 Fellows</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/summer-2018-fellows/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Announcing Summer 2018 Fellows" /><published>2018-05-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/summer-2018-fellows</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/summer-2018-fellows/">&lt;p&gt;The Distributed Web of Care team is excited to announce two fellows for Summer 2018. We are thankful to everyone who applied to the fellowship. We look forward to engaging with the community via public programs in NYC this July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;design--storytelling-fellow&quot;&gt;Design &amp;amp; Storytelling Fellow&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/fellows/cleo.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cleomiao.info/&quot;&gt;cleo (yuekai) miao&lt;/a&gt; is a Chinese artist currently based in boston, MA. She is an anti-disciplinary media artist and works to make sense of identities and bodies in virtual spaces. She plays with both the poetics and the absurdity of digital tools and culture, and considers the reality that is configured and mediated by images. Through playful investigation, cleo questions and spectates the role and affect of photographic images and mediums. Having grown up with the Chinese Internet, she is passionate about new possibilities of freedom and democracy offered by technology. However, at the same time she is wary of the systematic and algorithmic oppression and violence supported by unethical or inconsiderate technological infrastructures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;technology--documentation-fellow&quot;&gt;Technology &amp;amp; Documentation Fellow&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/fellows/callil.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://callil.com&quot;&gt;Callil Capuozzo&lt;/a&gt; is a designer at General Trademark, an educator at the School of Visual Arts and a researcher at New Computer Working Group. He is interested in building creative tools through collaboration with artists, scientists and engineers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/care.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are planning to offer skillshares in July in partnership with the Ace Hotel New York, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acehotel.com/calendar/newyork/distributed-web-of-care-skillshare-070118&quot;&gt;July 1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acehotel.com/calendar/newyork/distributed-web-of-care-skillshare-070818&quot;&gt;July 8&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acehotel.com/calendar/newyork/distributed-web-of-care-skillshare-071518&quot;&gt;July 15&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acehotel.com/calendar/newyork/distributed-web-of-care-skillshare-072218&quot;&gt;July 22&lt;/a&gt;. We will announce details about workshops and events via Taeyoon Choi’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinyletter.com/tchoi8&quot;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to working with a diverse group of stewards. Stewards are guest collaborators, contributing to DWC initiatives with their domain expertise. Stewards are often invited to present at DWC events and to contribute to building the code base as well as code of conduct. In this volunteer role, stewards will lead their own projects utilizing access to technical resources and collaboration with the fellows and with Taeyoon directly. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://airtable.com/shrJKwgf305PUDKjm&quot;&gt;apply to become a steward&lt;/a&gt; on an ongoing basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An open call for Winter 2018 fellowship will be announced in August.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Distributed Web of Care team is excited to announce two fellows for Summer 2018. We are thankful to everyone who applied to the fellowship. We look forward to engaging with the community via public programs in NYC this July.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Care shirt and hoodie</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/products/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Care shirt and hoodie" /><published>2018-04-28T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/products</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/products/">&lt;p&gt;Care shirts and hoodies are fundraising for The Distributed Web of Care. All sales profit made through purchased merchandise will go directly towards supporting the Distributed Web of Care initiative and fellowship. The project explores Distributed Web as a peer-to-peer alternative web that prioritizes collective agency and individual ownership of data and code. The project asks us to unlearn the assumption that technological innovation and automation is an inherent good, asking instead how we can code to care and code carefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/products/shirt1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://taeyoonchoi.com/products/shirt/&quot;&gt;Care shirt is $35&lt;/a&gt; plus shipping&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/products/hoodie1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://taeyoonchoi.com/products/hoodie/&quot;&gt;Care hoodie is $70&lt;/a&gt; plus shipping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Care shirt and hoodie is available as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://taeyoonchoi.com/products/care-shirt-hoodie/&quot;&gt;package for $100&lt;/a&gt; plus shipping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pre-sale between May 1 to June 31st, 2018. Shipping begins mid July, 2018. For more information on size and to purchase, please visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://taeyoonchoi.com/shop/&quot;&gt;Taeyoon Workshop Shop&lt;/a&gt;. The products will ship worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Model &lt;a href=&quot;http://xxx.tiri.xxx/&quot;&gt;Tiri Kananuruk&lt;/a&gt; is a performance artist and programmer.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Care shirts and hoodies are fundraising for The Distributed Web of Care. All sales profit made through purchased merchandise will go directly towards supporting the Distributed Web of Care initiative and fellowship. The project explores Distributed Web as a peer-to-peer alternative web that prioritizes collective agency and individual ownership of data and code. The project asks us to unlearn the assumption that technological innovation and automation is an inherent good, asking instead how we can code to care and code carefully.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Artists in Residence at Ace Hotel New York</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/air/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Artists in Residence at Ace Hotel New York" /><published>2018-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/air</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/air/">&lt;p&gt;We are excited to curate a wonderful group of artists for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acehotel.com/newyork&quot;&gt;Ace Hotel&lt;/a&gt; Artists in Residence (AIR) in July 2018. The group of AIR are writers, artists, organizers and activists. Their practice are an inspiration for Distributed Web of Care. AIR will stay one night at the NYC hotel and produce work that will be shared via Ace Hotel’s media channels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Ace Hotel website
 “This July, our Artists in Residence are curated by Taeyoon Workshop, whose Distributed Web of Care (DWC) research initiative explores the Distributed Web as a peer-to-peer, alternative web which prioritizes collective agency and individual ownership of data and code. Through collaborations with artists, engineers, social scientists and community organizers, DWC imagines distributed networks as a form of interdependence and stewardship, in critical opposition to the networks that dominate the world today. Taeyoon Choi is an artist and cofounder of School for Poetic Computation and a fellow at Data and Society.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ari-melenciano&quot;&gt;Ari Melenciano&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ariciano.com/&quot;&gt;Ari Melenciano&lt;/a&gt; is a multidisciplinary artist, designer, creative technologist and DJ. She is a master’s candidate at NYU’s ITP department, practicing at the intersection of experiential design and emerging technologies via creative computation, human-computer interaction, engineering and design. She is the creator and producer of new media arts, culture and technology festival Afrotectopia, as well as the creator of Justice Factory, a data visualization platform that highlights social justice issues and human rights violations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acehotel.com/calendar/newyork/ace-air-taeyoon-ari-menlenciano&quot;&gt;Ace AIR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;jessica-lynne&quot;&gt;Jessica Lynne&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/jess.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jessicalynne.co/&quot;&gt;Jessica Lynne&lt;/a&gt; is a Brooklyn-based writer and arts administrator. She is also co-editor of ARTS.BLACK, a platform for art criticism from black perspectives, a Winter 2018 Columnist-in-Residence at Open Space and currently serves as the Manager of Development and Communication at Recess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acehotel.com/calendar/newyork/ace-air-taeyoon-jessica-lynne&quot;&gt;Ace AIR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;mindy-seu&quot;&gt;Mindy Seu&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/mindy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mindyseu.com/&quot;&gt;Mindy Seu&lt;/a&gt; is a designer and educator. She is currently a student in Harvard’s Graduate School of Design, where her research focuses on digital archives UI and methods of digitization. Formerly, she was a designer at 2x4 and instructor for Interactive 2 at California College of the Arts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acehotel.com/calendar/newyork/ace-air-taeyoon-mindy-seu&quot;&gt;Ace AIR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;stephanie-gray&quot;&gt;Stephanie Gray&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/stephanie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poets/stephanie-gray&quot;&gt;Stephanie Gray&lt;/a&gt; is a poet-filmmaker known for Super 8 films and poetry that explore the experience of urban space, queerness, disability and class. She explores the mysterious ground between pop culture, fact, fiction and desire, while working between nostalgia, place and memory. She is the author of two poetry books, most recently, Shorthand and Electric Language Stars (Portable Press at Yo-Yo Labs, 2015), and four chapbooks, including Under the Surface (above/ground press, 2018) and A Country Road Going Back in Your Direction (Argos Books, 2015). Work also appears in the anthology How Lovely the Ruins (Spiegel &amp;amp; Grau/Random House, 2017).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acehotel.com/calendar/newyork/ace-air-taeyoon-stephanie-gray&quot;&gt;Ace AIR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;shannon-finnegan&quot;&gt;Shannon Finnegan&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/shannon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://shannonfinnegan.com/&quot;&gt;Shannon Finnegan&lt;/a&gt; is an artist whose practice involves a mix of drawing, design and writing. Her current motto is “Reinventing my strangeness as an art form that only I am the perfect practitioner of.” She’s created Anti-Stairs Club Lounge, Disability History PSA, and other projects about disability culture and access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acehotel.com/calendar/newyork/ace-air-taeyoon-shannon-finnegan&quot;&gt;Ace AIR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We are excited to curate a wonderful group of artists for the Ace Hotel Artists in Residence (AIR) in July 2018. The group of AIR are writers, artists, organizers and activists. Their practice are an inspiration for Distributed Web of Care. AIR will stay one night at the NYC hotel and produce work that will be shared via Ace Hotel’s media channels.</summary></entry></feed>