<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2018-07-22T12:48:27-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Distributed Web of Care</title><subtitle>DWC </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Skillshares: Peers in Practice</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/skillshares/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Skillshares: Peers in Practice" /><published>2018-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/skillshares</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/skillshares/">&lt;p&gt;The Distributed Web of Care presents a skillshare series called &lt;strong&gt;Peers in Practice.&lt;/strong&gt; This series invites the artists in residence at the Ace Hotel to investigate the distribution of power, autonomy and control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through an intimate interactive event, participants and artists will develop a dialog related to their practices by performing acts of collective caring, discussion and documentation.
As a participant in the skillshare, all we require is an open mind and desire to share together. We will be experimenting with different modes of documentation throughout the events. &lt;strong&gt;We will also send out a small set of readings and ask you to generate a few questions based on those readings so we can come together with an informed baseline.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be four skillshares held between July 1st and July 22nd, culminating in a vibrant party in July 29th where the fellows and stewards from the Distributed Web of Care project will present their work on both tools and theory on a web of care, not control. Space is limited for the skillshare event. Please &lt;a href=&quot;https://airtable.com/shrnr16Oq6oalF1S1&quot;&gt;RSVP here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;stephanie-gray-and-eliza-chandler&quot;&gt;Stephanie Gray and Eliza Chandler&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date: 07.22.2018. 1~4pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/skillshare4_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poets/stephanie-gray&quot;&gt;Stephanie Gray&lt;/a&gt; is a poet-filmmaker known for Super 8 films and poetry that explore the experience of urban space, queerness, disability and class. She explores the mysterious ground between pop culture, fact, fiction and desire, while working between nostalgia, place and memory. She is the author of two poetry books, most recently, Shorthand and Electric Language Stars (Portable Press at Yo-Yo Labs, 2015), and four chapbooks, including Under the Surface (above/ground press, 2018) and A Country Road Going Back in Your Direction (Argos Books, 2015). Work also appears in the anthology How Lovely the Ruins (Spiegel &amp;amp; Grau/Random House, 2017).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/skillshare4_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eliza Chandler, an Assistant Professor at the School of Disability Studies at Ryerson University, aims to bring together the arts, disability studies, and justice-based activism. She teaches courses on disability arts and culture, disability rights and justice, and community-based social activism; she is the co-director of the project Bodies in Translation: Activist Art, Technology, and Access to Life, a many-partnered grant supports the development of activist art (including Deaf &amp;amp; disability art, fat art, and Indigenous art) and interrogates its connection to the enactment of social justice. Chandler is a practicing curator, a board member of the Ontario Arts Council, and the co-founder of Creative Users Projects, a community arts/activist initiative that supports crip artists through artistic development and works to create a more accessible arts culture. Prior to these roles, she was the founding artistic director of Tangled Art Gallery, a gallery in Toronto that showcases disability arts and advances accessible curatorial practices. Chandler regularly give lectures, interviews, and consultations related to disability arts, inclusive curatorial practices, and disability politics in Canada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://airtable.com/shrnr16Oq6oalF1S1&quot;&gt;Free, RSVP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All Events - Location: Ace Hotel Boardroom, 20 W 29th St, New York, NY 10001&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The space is accessible via service elevator. Please note your access needs in the RSVP form and ask the front desk for assistance. 7.22 skillshare will have a Communication Access Realtime Translation (CART) service&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;past-events&quot;&gt;Past Events&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;1-ari-melenciano&quot;&gt;#1 Ari Melenciano&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/skillshares1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date: 07.01.2018. 1~4pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ariciano.com/&quot;&gt;Ari Melenciano&lt;/a&gt; is a multidisciplinary artist, designer, creative technologist and DJ. She is a master’s candidate at NYU’s ITP department, practicing at the intersection of experiential design and emerging technologies via creative computation, human-computer interaction, engineering and design. She is the creator and producer of new media arts, culture and technology festival Afrotectopia, as well as the creator of Justice Factory, a data visualization platform that highlights social justice issues and human rights violations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@AriMelenciano_88366/el-museu-de-afrotopolis-building-a-museum-353-years-in-the-future-1cb9d9f668b8&quot;&gt;Building a Museum 353 Years in the Future&lt;/a&gt; by Ari about her residency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;2-mindy-seu&quot;&gt;#2 Mindy Seu&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/skillshares2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date: 07.08.2018. 1~4pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mindyseu.com/&quot;&gt;Mindy Seu&lt;/a&gt; is a designer and educator. She is currently a student in Harvard’s Graduate School of Design, where her research focuses on digital archives UI and methods of digitization. Formerly, she was a designer at 2x4 and instructor for Interactive 2 at California College of the Arts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/workshops.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The skillshare will also include the following short workshops presented by stewards of the DWC project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.laiyiohlsen.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lai Yi Ohlsen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peer to peer protocols require trust and the negotiation of shared resources - so does the dance floor. Webs of moving bodies and sound are an ideal environment to understand how we can, and already do, prioritize care over control within a system. With a good enough groove, peers work together without ever skipping a beat. ‘100 Scores’ by Lai Yi Ohlsen is a repository of improvisational movement scores based upon computer science algorithms. For DWC she will present scores related to the potential of the distributed, peer to peer web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://julianacastro.co/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Juliana Castro&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meme culture and fast-paced social networking have encouraged the use of copyrighted resources without proper attribution. This talk will highlight the benefits of open-access, show a selection of available public domain and Creative Commons archives, and address best practices and fair use uses of institutional repositories and other people’s work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://zachcoble.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zach Coble&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants will engage in a conversation about gathering and using data from the web for social good. The steward will briefly show recent projects and we will use these examples to create a dialog about the legal and ethical issues involved in such projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;3-jessia-lynne-and-shannon-finnegan&quot;&gt;#3 Jessia Lynne and Shannon Finnegan&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date: 07.15.2018. 1~4pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location: Ace Hotel Boardroom, 20 W 29th St, New York, NY 10001&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/skillshare3_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jessicalynne.co/&quot;&gt;Jessica Lynne&lt;/a&gt; is co-founder and editor of ARTS.BLACK, a journal of art criticism from Black perspectives. She received her B.A. in Africana Studies from NYU and has been awarded residencies and fellowships from Art21 and The Cue Foundation, Callaloo, and The Center for Book Arts. Her writing has appeared in publications such as Aperture, Art in America, The Brooklyn Rail, and Kinfolk. She was a Winter 2018 Columnist-in-Residence at &lt;a href=&quot;https://openspace.sfmoma.org/&quot;&gt;Open Space&lt;/a&gt;, SFMoMA’s interdisciplinary publishing platform, and is co-editor, alongside Sharon Louden, of the forthcoming book, The Innovators: Defining Change in the Art World, that will be published by Intellect Ltd. and The University of Chicago Press.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She is a board member of Black Art Futures Fund and The Organization of Women Writers of Africa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/skillshare3_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://shannonfinnegan.com/&quot;&gt;Shannon Finnegan&lt;/a&gt; is an artist whose practice involves a mix of drawing, design and writing. Her current motto is “Reinventing my strangeness as an art form that only I am the perfect practitioner of.” She’s created Anti-Stairs Club Lounge, Disability History PSA, and other projects about disability culture and access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://airtable.com/shrnr16Oq6oalF1S1&quot;&gt;Free, RSVP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are planning to offer skillshares and party in July in partnership with the Ace Hotel New York. We will announce details about workshops and events via Taeyoon Choi’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinyletter.com/tchoi8&quot;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt;. Please join us for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dwc-tchoi8.hashbase.io/posts/party/&quot;&gt;Distributed Web of Care Party&lt;/a&gt; on July 29th.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Distributed Web of Care presents a skillshare series called Peers in Practice. This series invites the artists in residence at the Ace Hotel to investigate the distribution of power, autonomy and control.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Distributed Web of Care Party</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/party/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Distributed Web of Care Party " /><published>2018-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/party</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/party/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/party/party.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;July 29th, 3-7pm, 2018&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Liberty Hall at Ace Hotel New York, 20 W 29th St, New York, NY 10001&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Free with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/distributed-web-of-care-party-tickets-47220143721&quot;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Distributed Web of Care Party will be held at the Liberty Hall at Ace Hotel New York on July 29th from 3-7pm. The party will be a collection of talks, presentations, interactions and music to illustrate the collective power of caring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team of Fellows, Stewards and Artists in residence will all contribute toward sharing their knowledge and expertise in a series of talks concerning the distributed web. These talks will be both technical and abstract, but grounded in the project’s mission:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Care, in contrast to cure, is a form of stewardship between people who support each other in communication, action, and social engagement. It is actualized by extending one’s mindfulness of another person’s dignity and feelings, while respecting their independence.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the talks, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laiyiohlsen.com/&quot;&gt;Lai Yi Ohlsen&lt;/a&gt; will lead a distributed dance. &lt;a href=&quot;http://laurelschwulst.com/&quot;&gt;Laurel Schwulst&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdxs.ist/&quot;&gt;Becca Abbe&lt;/a&gt; will be doing live drawing with code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event will progress into dancing and socializing with music curated by the multi-instrumental artist and DJ &lt;a href=&quot;http://stud1nt.nyc/&quot;&gt;stud1nt&lt;/a&gt; of Discwoman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/party/unnamed1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;stud1nt is a multi-disciplinary sound artist from Queens. Their work sits at the intersection of improvisation and meticulous approaches to composition. A member of the collectives #KUNQ and Discwoman, their work is especially attentive to queerness, the body, sound, and space. stud1nt has given workshops on creative production at Vassar College, the New School, Recess Art, Pioneer Works, Moogfest, and Ableton Loop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The timing of the event is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3:00-4:00pm
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Talks and Discussion about care, distribution and publishing in the context of the distributed web by Taeyoon, Callil and Cleo&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4:30-5:00pm
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Collective Poetry and Distribution with &lt;a href=&quot;http://distributedweb.care/posts/skillshares/&quot;&gt;Distributed Web of Care Team&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5:00-5:30pm
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Movement as Peers with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laiyiohlsen.com/&quot;&gt;Lai Yi Ohlsen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Music with &lt;a href=&quot;http://stud1nt.nyc/&quot;&gt;Stud1nt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5:30-6:00pm
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Live Code Cameras with &lt;a href=&quot;http://laurelschwulst.com/&quot;&gt;Laurel Schwulst&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdxs.ist/&quot;&gt;Becca Abbe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Music with &lt;a href=&quot;http://stud1nt.nyc/&quot;&gt;Stud1nt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6:00-7:00pm
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Hang out!&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Music with &lt;a href=&quot;http://stud1nt.nyc/&quot;&gt;Stud1nt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party will be governed by the DWC &lt;a href=&quot;https://dwc-tchoi8.hashbase.io/posts/coc/&quot;&gt;code of conduct&lt;/a&gt;. It is open to the public and free with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/distributed-web-of-care-party-tickets-47220143721&quot;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Communities and new infrastructures</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/cleo/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Communities and new infrastructures" /><published>2018-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/cleo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/cleo/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/fellows/cleoimg.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;by Cleo, DWC fellow&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some things I am thinking about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the role and importance of communities in the access of information&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;communications through communities vs. information curated by platforms and medias&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;offline communities vs. online communities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;locality of the net&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;integration of the offline and the online&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ownership of information and related power structures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google exited China when I was just about to enter middle school in a small city somewhat close to Shanghai. That was around the time when I really started using the Internet. I was made aware of the importance of the freedom to access information in the digital age and started to see technology as an alternative possibility for that freedom. When censorship is done in the analog world (an example would be books banned from circulation in any market or library), the information being controlled is very hard to access. However, in the case of digital censorship, the counteraction can be easier and safer. Tools such as VPNs provide easy access to locally censored information while offering anonymity to users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, these technologies can be alienating and exclusive. For most of the general public with an Internet connection, the loss of Google did not have a substantial effect. But because of the government’s central control over digital information and the public’s need for open knowledge and discourse, the Internet in China grew into a very different thing then in most of the western countries. Even though there is a bootleg version of Facebook that was popular very briefly, it was forgotten quickly. There seem to be somewhat less of an interest in creating a version of real identities and connections virtually, and more of one in creating and discovering new communities through channels of online communication. Forums and chat groups became an important part of online activities for a lot of people. These forums and private chat groups are still monitored and censored by the government. After sensitive topics and keywords come up in a group chat, the chat group would usually get deleted. Even then, people were able to come up with alternative terms that address the same subjects without hitting the keyword detections. These forums therefore are becoming important channels for knowledge and discourse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I moved to the states for college. I went to a computer engineering program that was very competitive. Having gone into the program because of a fascination towards the poetics of computing, I soon became very disillusioned. My peers were the people who wanted to build digital infrastructures, but many of them fail to think about the communities being affected by the infrastructures outside of being either users or a part of the datasets. Everyone was concerned with efficiency and marketing, but few thought about the ethics of coding and algorithmic bias. During my first months in the program, I was told by almost every professor for the engineering classes I took that the program would be hard, but the financial payout was promising. I became skeptical of the approach taken by core engineering programs and the disconnect between the general social science classes and the technical classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was introduced to experimental music and performance art and started going to shows in living rooms, basements, and alternative venues. Around the same time I moved to Boston and transferred into a studio art program. I started booking and running shows as well as performing in them. I was excited by the ecology of these subculture communities and the focus on ideals and inclusivity. This extends to the larger creative community, but is unique in its dependency on a gift economy. A small group of people actively participate through creative endeavors, contribute through small donations, and usually both. This community thrives on the idea of supporting and caring for each other. However, communication is largely based on proprietary platforms that can limit the freedom of such communication while contradicting (or at least poorly reflecting) the idea of caring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/fellows/cleoprj.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jennifer Vanilla performing at Becoming Posthuman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Becoming Posthuman was an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/events/174088576497818/&quot;&gt;event&lt;/a&gt; I co-curated last year. I was trying to use the model of DIY underground shows on a new media art show. My own &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cleomiao.info/archive/&quot;&gt;art practice&lt;/a&gt; involves playful investigation of technology both critically and romantically. Recently I have been &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1OQQ7lqCsw5mOKZOpSKZjapr4D6AtghZNhZgfCs_jTYc/edit&quot;&gt;thinking&lt;/a&gt; a lot about how art like mine can exist within the larger art world. Is it necessary to adapt to the old institution and create tangible artifacts that a gallery can sell, or is it more important to establish new institutions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditional functions of art spaces see art as merchandise, and unavoidably have to consider the function of art for its patronage. Most of the art being made will not enter art museums. The end result of most art should not be as decoration in a private home or in an inconsequential semi-public space (such as hotels and offices).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The first thing that has to be conserved or even created is a situation where art can be seen and accessed. Why is this so? Because art is not art if it cannot be seen.- Hito Steyerl.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new structure for creative communities and the art world at large should consider a redistribution of power that is conscious of the post-internet context and what that means for the process of learning, creating, and dispersion. The distinction between the artists and the curator becomes vague. Traditionally, the curator represents the institutions. As art and curation integrate with each other, maybe it is time to think about a collective approach / strategy as a more sustainable model for creative communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was introduced to the idea of distributed systems by a friend who was looking into creating a mesh network in areas in Boston. Mesh networks immediately became interesting to me. It creates an ecosystem that promotes communities that are both offline and online. It allows for offline local communities to expand to a local “online” and vice versa. This is interesting in that it strengthens and broadens offline communities by creating another channel for communication, while adding an element of caring to digital connections. A similar case can be made for a distributed internet. Besides the expansion of communities, it also gives each member more access and control over information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One important question that was brought up during a conversation about potential mesh networks in Boston is how to make people want to use it. How do we make a tool accessible to anyone, and not just the technologists?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something that has to be considered. These distributed systems are exciting new infrastructures that can subvert power structures and give the power of data and information back to the people. In developing these new infrastructures, we need to build with care and consideration of communities.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Gardens</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/callil/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Gardens" /><published>2018-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/callil</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/callil/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/fellows/callil1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;by Callil, DWC fellow&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was young I lived next to a Biodynamic farm and intentional living community in upstate NY. I was able to freely roam through orchards, cropped fields and small gardens. As I spent time in these environments, unbeknownst to me I was brushing up against embedded knowledge by proxy. In the biodynamic context, the soil, plants and animals are seen as interrelated and dynamic. A farmer or gardener becomes steward of plants with the goal of creating a healthy and holistic system. Biodynamic stewardship comes through not only in caring for the plants,but also in the social structures that makes this approach possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that the Biodynamic framework was never explicitly taught, only implicitly discovered by participating in the farming. These abstract teachings were discovered mostly by stumbling on to the day of harvest. Now, years later this implicit knowledge, and the methods used to disseminate this knowledge is re-emerging for me in the context of my practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/fellows/callil2.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;My garden this morning&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I have been working on my garden here in Brooklyn. In many ways, I still carry with me a lot of the knowledge from the biodynamic context. One method I’ve been experimenting with is called the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wintergreenstudios.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/09/Three-Sisters-Garden.pdf&quot;&gt;Three Sisters&lt;/a&gt;, a technique I was exposed to by hearing this story…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;2&quot;&gt;2.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Corn, the oldest sister, was said to grow strong and proud. Squash, the youngest sister, crouched at the feet of the other two, keeping them protected from predators. Beans, the middle sister leaned on her older sister for support and twined the three together.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.essentialseeds.us/pdfs/the_three_sisters_growing_guide_1.1.pdf&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The act of seeding the Three Sisters is an act of stewardship &amp;amp; guidance that plays with the inherent strengths of each plant and the ecosystem it is part of. Recognizing these symbiotic structures is something that is important in the context of both farming and organizing social structures - so too is the practice of care and maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately I find myself in our current digital context seeking the spaces and communities where new narratives can be written that feel more like biodynamic farming or methods passed down through oral traditions. Maybe together we can make spaces where implicit knowledge is conveyed through the cultivated expression of a holistic point of view. One concrete example of a space where there is potential to create these new narratives is within the distributed web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though the usefulness of extending the metaphor of gardening to the distributed web can only take us so far, here are a few elements of the holistic practice of gardening that we might learn from to stretch the boundaries of the normative patterns in our digital spaces today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The notion of time and seasons as a forcing function for growth, death, rest and rebirth. Maybe as a rejection of the vectorized ideal of technology (uni-directional and totalizing)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slowness and patience in waiting for the development of one’s self and people around you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Seeding and cultivation as an intentional act with a clear understanding of the substrate in which it happens.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sanctuary and reflection related to spaces of calm, quiet and safety.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sustenance related to the growth of communities and knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The relationship between social structures and knowledge, especially knowledge that is embedded in practice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;3&quot;&gt;3.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeking out these patterns within a tech centered practice is one way of putting into practice some of the ideas above. This might take the form of using &lt;a href=&quot;https://hardlyeverything.com/&quot;&gt;tools&lt;/a&gt; that ask different things from you or designing &lt;a href=&quot;https://thecreativeindependent.com/notes/arena-tci-how-do-you-use-the-internet-mindfully/&quot;&gt;systems for your self&lt;/a&gt;. It might also look like organizing events and communities where ideas for a different kind of web can be experimented with and embodied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/fellows/callil3.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/fellows/callil4.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I helped organize an event called &lt;a href=&quot;https://peer-to-peer-web.com/nyc&quot;&gt;Peer-to-Peer Web NYC&lt;/a&gt; at SFPC - for the event my friend &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phil-cao.com/&quot;&gt;Phil Cao&lt;/a&gt; created this poster that uses plants, and flowers in bloom to represent our point of view of what the distributed web might be. During the event, we invited a wide range of local participants to share their projects and practices to illustrate how concepts of seeding, leeching, pollination texture and more can become profound ways of looking at what it means for diverse expressions of the web to form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also been participating in and organizing for groups like &lt;a href=&quot;https://nycmesh.net/&quot;&gt;NYCMesh&lt;/a&gt;. These groups serve as a fertile place to think about new approaches to technology; imagine if the distribution of knowledge was more like a folk tale rather than a singular post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;4&quot;&gt;4.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only recently have I been able to begin asking myself questions like: What are the materials we have to explore and what does it mean to view our digital spaces holistically? What are other disciplines beyond the digital sphere we might look towards?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When considering the concept of the distributed web, we might look towards both the metaphor and practice of gardening and farming. I hope that we can show how building for digital spaces requires respect, patience, and a real awareness of the environment around you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe we can write some new folk tales together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I was walking through a new garden. As I passed each plant they turned to me and smiled - the corn, being tall, had to bend down and said to me: “Come sit and while. I’ll tell you the story of how far my pollen has traveled, the bees that visit me and the minerals that help me grow. They are all connected and we can be too.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/fellows/callil5.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A seeder set up by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/louiscenter&quot;&gt;Louis Center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tchoi8&quot;&gt;Taeyoon Choi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tinanguyen_&quot;&gt;Tina Nguyen&lt;/a&gt;, Livia Huang and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/automaticyes&quot;&gt;Alexander Singh&lt;/a&gt; for their fantastic feedback and edits.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;References:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cultureandcommunication.org/galloway/anti-computer&quot;&gt;http://cultureandcommunication.org/galloway/anti-computer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://digital.library.upenn.edu/women/buffalo/garden/garden.html&quot;&gt;http://digital.library.upenn.edu/women/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://newcomputers.group/ready2use.html&quot;&gt;https://newcomputers.group/ready2use.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Announcing Summer 2018 Fellows</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/summer-2018-fellows/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Announcing Summer 2018 Fellows" /><published>2018-05-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/summer-2018-fellows</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/summer-2018-fellows/">&lt;p&gt;The Distributed Web of Care team is excited to announce two fellows for Summer 2018. We are thankful to everyone who applied to the fellowship. We look forward to engaging with the community via public programs in NYC this July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;design--storytelling-fellow&quot;&gt;Design &amp;amp; Storytelling Fellow&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/fellows/cleo.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cleomiao.info/&quot;&gt;cleo (yuekai) miao&lt;/a&gt; is a Chinese artist currently based in boston, MA. She is an anti-disciplinary media artist and works to make sense of identities and bodies in virtual spaces. She plays with both the poetics and the absurdity of digital tools and culture, and considers the reality that is configured and mediated by images. Through playful investigation, cleo questions and spectates the role and affect of photographic images and mediums. Having grown up with the Chinese Internet, she is passionate about new possibilities of freedom and democracy offered by technology. However, at the same time she is wary of the systematic and algorithmic oppression and violence supported by unethical or inconsiderate technological infrastructures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;technology--documentation-fellow&quot;&gt;Technology &amp;amp; Documentation Fellow&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/fellows/callil.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://callil.com&quot;&gt;Callil Capuozzo&lt;/a&gt; is a designer at General Trademark, an educator at the School of Visual Arts and a researcher at New Computer Working Group. He is interested in building creative tools through collaboration with artists, scientists and engineers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/care.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are planning to offer skillshares in July in partnership with the Ace Hotel New York, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acehotel.com/calendar/newyork/distributed-web-of-care-skillshare-070118&quot;&gt;July 1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acehotel.com/calendar/newyork/distributed-web-of-care-skillshare-070818&quot;&gt;July 8&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acehotel.com/calendar/newyork/distributed-web-of-care-skillshare-071518&quot;&gt;July 15&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acehotel.com/calendar/newyork/distributed-web-of-care-skillshare-072218&quot;&gt;July 22&lt;/a&gt;. We will announce details about workshops and events via Taeyoon Choi’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinyletter.com/tchoi8&quot;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to working with a diverse group of stewards. Stewards are guest collaborators, contributing to DWC initiatives with their domain expertise. Stewards are often invited to present at DWC events and to contribute to building the code base as well as code of conduct. In this volunteer role, stewards will lead their own projects utilizing access to technical resources and collaboration with the fellows and with Taeyoon directly. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://airtable.com/shrJKwgf305PUDKjm&quot;&gt;apply to become a steward&lt;/a&gt; on an ongoing basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An open call for Winter 2018 fellowship will be announced in August.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Distributed Web of Care team is excited to announce two fellows for Summer 2018. We are thankful to everyone who applied to the fellowship. We look forward to engaging with the community via public programs in NYC this July.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Care shirt and hoodie</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/products/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Care shirt and hoodie" /><published>2018-04-28T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/products</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/products/">&lt;p&gt;Care shirts and hoodies are fundraising for The Distributed Web of Care. All sales profit made through purchased merchandise will go directly towards supporting the Distributed Web of Care initiative and fellowship. The project explores Distributed Web as a peer-to-peer alternative web that prioritizes collective agency and individual ownership of data and code. The project asks us to unlearn the assumption that technological innovation and automation is an inherent good, asking instead how we can code to care and code carefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/products/shirt1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://taeyoonchoi.com/products/shirt/&quot;&gt;Care shirt is $35&lt;/a&gt; plus shipping&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/products/hoodie1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://taeyoonchoi.com/products/hoodie/&quot;&gt;Care hoodie is $70&lt;/a&gt; plus shipping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Care shirt and hoodie is available as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://taeyoonchoi.com/products/care-shirt-hoodie/&quot;&gt;package for $100&lt;/a&gt; plus shipping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pre-sale between May 1 to June 31st, 2018. Shipping begins mid July, 2018. For more information on size and to purchase, please visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://taeyoonchoi.com/shop/&quot;&gt;Taeyoon Workshop Shop&lt;/a&gt;. The products will ship worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Model &lt;a href=&quot;http://xxx.tiri.xxx/&quot;&gt;Tiri Kananuruk&lt;/a&gt; is a performance artist and programmer.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Care shirts and hoodies are fundraising for The Distributed Web of Care. All sales profit made through purchased merchandise will go directly towards supporting the Distributed Web of Care initiative and fellowship. The project explores Distributed Web as a peer-to-peer alternative web that prioritizes collective agency and individual ownership of data and code. The project asks us to unlearn the assumption that technological innovation and automation is an inherent good, asking instead how we can code to care and code carefully.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Artists in Residence at Ace Hotel New York</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/air/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Artists in Residence at Ace Hotel New York" /><published>2018-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/air</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/air/">&lt;p&gt;We are excited to curate a wonderful group of artists for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acehotel.com/newyork&quot;&gt;Ace Hotel&lt;/a&gt; Artists in Residence (AIR) in July 2018. The group of AIR are writers, artists, organizers and activists. Their practice are an inspiration for Distributed Web of Care. AIR will stay one night at the NYC hotel and produce work that will be shared via Ace Hotel’s media channels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Ace Hotel website
 “This July, our Artists in Residence are curated by Taeyoon Workshop, whose Distributed Web of Care (DWC) research initiative explores the Distributed Web as a peer-to-peer, alternative web which prioritizes collective agency and individual ownership of data and code. Through collaborations with artists, engineers, social scientists and community organizers, DWC imagines distributed networks as a form of interdependence and stewardship, in critical opposition to the networks that dominate the world today. Taeyoon Choi is an artist and cofounder of School for Poetic Computation and a fellow at Data and Society.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ari-melenciano&quot;&gt;Ari Melenciano&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/ari.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ariciano.com/&quot;&gt;Ari Melenciano&lt;/a&gt; is a multidisciplinary artist, designer, creative technologist and DJ. She is a master’s candidate at NYU’s ITP department, practicing at the intersection of experiential design and emerging technologies via creative computation, human-computer interaction, engineering and design. She is the creator and producer of new media arts, culture and technology festival Afrotectopia, as well as the creator of Justice Factory, a data visualization platform that highlights social justice issues and human rights violations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acehotel.com/calendar/newyork/ace-air-taeyoon-ari-menlenciano&quot;&gt;Ace AIR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;jessica-lynne&quot;&gt;Jessica Lynne&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/jess.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jessicalynne.co/&quot;&gt;Jessica Lynne&lt;/a&gt; is a Brooklyn-based writer and arts administrator. She is also co-editor of ARTS.BLACK, a platform for art criticism from black perspectives, a Winter 2018 Columnist-in-Residence at Open Space and currently serves as the Manager of Development and Communication at Recess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acehotel.com/calendar/newyork/ace-air-taeyoon-jessica-lynne&quot;&gt;Ace AIR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;mindy-seu&quot;&gt;Mindy Seu&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/mindy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mindyseu.com/&quot;&gt;Mindy Seu&lt;/a&gt; is a designer and educator. She is currently a student in Harvard’s Graduate School of Design, where her research focuses on digital archives UI and methods of digitization. Formerly, she was a designer at 2x4 and instructor for Interactive 2 at California College of the Arts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acehotel.com/calendar/newyork/ace-air-taeyoon-mindy-seu&quot;&gt;Ace AIR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;stephanie-gray&quot;&gt;Stephanie Gray&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/stephanie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poets/stephanie-gray&quot;&gt;Stephanie Gray&lt;/a&gt; is a poet-filmmaker known for Super 8 films and poetry that explore the experience of urban space, queerness, disability and class. She explores the mysterious ground between pop culture, fact, fiction and desire, while working between nostalgia, place and memory. She is the author of two poetry books, most recently, Shorthand and Electric Language Stars (Portable Press at Yo-Yo Labs, 2015), and four chapbooks, including Under the Surface (above/ground press, 2018) and A Country Road Going Back in Your Direction (Argos Books, 2015). Work also appears in the anthology How Lovely the Ruins (Spiegel &amp;amp; Grau/Random House, 2017).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acehotel.com/calendar/newyork/ace-air-taeyoon-stephanie-gray&quot;&gt;Ace AIR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;shannon-finnegan&quot;&gt;Shannon Finnegan&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/air/shannon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://shannonfinnegan.com/&quot;&gt;Shannon Finnegan&lt;/a&gt; is an artist whose practice involves a mix of drawing, design and writing. Her current motto is “Reinventing my strangeness as an art form that only I am the perfect practitioner of.” She’s created Anti-Stairs Club Lounge, Disability History PSA, and other projects about disability culture and access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acehotel.com/calendar/newyork/ace-air-taeyoon-shannon-finnegan&quot;&gt;Ace AIR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We are excited to curate a wonderful group of artists for the Ace Hotel Artists in Residence (AIR) in July 2018. The group of AIR are writers, artists, organizers and activists. Their practice are an inspiration for Distributed Web of Care. AIR will stay one night at the NYC hotel and produce work that will be shared via Ace Hotel’s media channels.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ethics and Archiving the Web</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/eaw/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ethics and Archiving the Web " /><published>2018-04-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/eaw</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/eaw/">&lt;p&gt;The first public event of Distributed Web of Care was presented as a part of Rhizome’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://eaw.rhizome.org/&quot;&gt;Ethics &amp;amp; Archiving the Web&lt;/a&gt; conference at the New Museum, NYC, March 24, 2018. The workshop offered resources for getting started with the Distributed Web, and invited computer scientists and domain experts to host an open conversation on counter-narratives to the mainstream internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;taeyoon-choi&quot;&gt;Taeyoon Choi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first question that we would like to address: how can we define care in the context of the web? There are three kinds of networks that I drew in my painting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the far right you see a centralized network, there’s a very intense connection in the middle where different nodes are connected to. On the far left there is a decentralized network where there’s a variety of centralized networks that are connected to each other. What I’m interested in is the middle one, which is the distributed network. In a distributed network, each interconnected node has agency and can enact and disconnect or engage with other networks as needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How is the internet built today? The internet is an accumulation of these different forms of networks. It has this appearance of decentralization but its operations are centralized. GitHub is a good example of a decentralized network. I use GitHub to collaborate with other people and also do my teaching. I create my “master branch” and then students fork their own branch. When they are done working on their branch, they create a pull request for me to merge. Although GitHub supports decentralized collaboration, at the core of it, the nature of its repositories are incredibly centralized. It’s optimized for centralized forms of control and command. These words, such as control, command, server, host, all have a relationship to military action. It’s related to how the Internet, or the network as we know, has been created and continues to be used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We often hear words like “cloud computing” which abstracts the computing infrastructures into beautiful and playful images. We often see images like  Amazon web services logo. You can see the blobs of clouds and these boxes that could either be packages that you ordered or packets of data. There are obscure raindrops coming out of the clouds and it suggests that the computing is possible everywhere, that the cloud is like water, like humidity. However, we know the “cloud” is a massive interconnected physical infrastructure which exists across the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/amazoncloud.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingrid Burrington writes in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2016/01/amazon-web-services-data-center/423147/&quot;&gt;“Why Amazon’s Data Centers Are Hidden in Spy Country”&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic&lt;/em&gt;, “The databases alone are not archives anymore than data centers are libraries, and the rhetorical promise of The Cloud is as fragile as the strands of fiber-optic cable upon which its physical infrastructure rests. In part, the success of Amazon Web Services - arguable the success of The Cloud itself at this point - lies in its ability to abstract infrastructural problems into logistics problems.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Burrington’s comment sheds light on the most common use of cloud computing services as machines of bureaucracy. We often use the cloud computing for office tasks, such as spreadsheets, documents, or slides. We have grown accustomed to this abstracted notion of computing to logistics. Logistics is a part of the infrastructure equation. When we become accustomed to conveniences of such services, we are also growing dependencies on the physical infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking about computing for a while, especially thinking about how to give form to it, visualize it, build it, and be a part of it with projects like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://avant.org/thread/handmade-computer/&quot;&gt;Handmade Computer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_4.png&quot; alt=&quot;8-Bit City&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Computers are often compared to urban infrastructure. In my drawing above, there are buildings, highways, and people passing through different nodes as passengers. Sometimes there are traffic jams; sometimes there are roads that you have to pay to get to. When you’re building hardware, it really looks like urban planning. It’s tempting to think about computer architecture as cities, data path as roads, and people as data which all operates under a massive clock. However, the metaphor of city as computer is not complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an article, &lt;a href=&quot;https://placesjournal.org/article/a-city-is-not-a-computer/&quot;&gt;“A City Is Not a Computer”&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;em&gt;Places Journal&lt;/em&gt;, Shannon Mattern writes, “Our current paradigm, the city as computer, appeals because it frames the messiness of urban life as programmable and subject to rational order.” Mattern is criticizing this notion of cities as a computer and computers as a city. “There is more than information processing going on here. Urban information is made, commodified, accessed, secreted, politicized and operationalized. She is pointing to the fact that cities are not simply computers. The kind of activities that happen in cities and societies at large are not just information processing. Life is more complex than just data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this leads to some of the questions that I’ve been thinking, why we need to care about the distributed web. The first question I ask is: How can we resist the capitalist means of control and instead care for each other through the network? The word &lt;em&gt;care&lt;/em&gt; is important here because I think about care as an alternative to control. Control is how the network operates, The Internet consists of control mechanisms from different nodes. I’m focusing on this word control because &lt;a href=&quot;https://cidadeinseguranca.files.wordpress.com/2012/02/deleuze_control.pdf&quot;&gt;Gilles Deleuze&lt;/a&gt; talks about “societies of control” in contrast to “societies of discipline.” A society of discipline is like a confined space of imprisonment, while on the contrary, a society of control is more like a private highway. The free-floating traffic of information travels in what appears to be open space, but in reality it is highly regulated because of the infrastructure on which it is built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We optimize ourselves to operate within control protocols, efficiency and compliance to terms of service. We attempt “Search Engine Optimization” of the self. Meanwhile, the society of control does not provide space for the us to take agency and take care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these questions, I invited a group of colleagues from &lt;a href=&quot;http://datasociety.org&quot;&gt;Data and Society&lt;/a&gt; and students from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://sfpc.io&quot;&gt;School for Poetic Computation&lt;/a&gt; to share their thoughts on the concept of the Distributed Web of Care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Kelly Monson&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;kelly-monson&quot;&gt;Kelly Monson&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was thinking: if we want to keep this a public and decentralized network, how do we establish a rule set or a code of conduct that people are trusted to follow? How do you establish this without using a form of policing? That’s an important distinction. Also I think a lot about how if you have this network, how can you keep it from being exploited? If you have a tool that people use, then, depending on how big the system is, there will inevitably be bad actors. Someone will discover this platform, come in, and find it perfect ground for trolling. It’s important to attempt to poke holes in a system and to see how someone could exploit this it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taeyoon:&lt;/strong&gt; That’s where this notion of trust comes in: how can one build a system in a way that is structured to support care, but also is structured to build and support trust within the network?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kelly:&lt;/strong&gt; And how do you trust people to have empathy? Because there are varying degrees of concern for others - some people don’t have an understanding of other people’s experiences and others simply don’t want to understand. I think it’s really important to cultivate a culture of empathy and bring people to an understanding without policing. And that’s a very interesting subject because how do you force people to - well you don’t force - how do you suggest and encourage empathy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taeyoon:&lt;/strong&gt; I think that’s where stewardship comes in. It’s a form of leadership that’s bottom-up and supports mutual responsibilities. Stewardship is not a question of enforcement, but how to cultivate a culture where asking for accountability is a norm. It starts with good social practices, not rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kelly:&lt;/strong&gt; Many communities tend to start small. Best practices begin to form, and eventually the community may grow bigger. How do you maintain those practices as the community grows? And then what do you do with people who are making it difficult for other people in that space? Or making it feel unsafe? Or making people feel like they’re being exploited?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/surfing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Surfing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taeyoon:&lt;/strong&gt; I think of information as continuous streams of thoughts that affect our existence together, and of data as discrete points of differences. There’s surfing going on in the sine wave of information, and the discrete components of digital data are these blocks - we have to climb up these stairs. It really comes down to what is computable and what is not. What are the discrete points of the worldview that are compartmentalized into zeroes and ones, and what are the spaces between?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/distribution.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Surfing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are focusing on distribution instead of decentralization. Decentralization is essential for distribution, however, they are not the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also focusing on care instead of control. Care is this very soft sense of responsibility and accountability. Without care, everything becomes code. We can try and write codes of conduct and codes of expectation, but until it’s executed and implemented into use, it’s just code. It’s just abstract symbols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big question I have is: can we code to care, and can we code carefully?  Let’s think about care instead of control. Let’s think about person instead of user. Let’s try and unlearn instead of machine learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/manifesto.png&quot; alt=&quot;manifesto&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Question number two: how is the distributed web different from the decentralized web? To answer that we need to figure out how the web actually works today. I’ve invited Hans to give us a brief summary of how the architecture of the web is built today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_6.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hans Steinbrecher&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hans-steinbrecher&quot;&gt;Hans Steinbrecher&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have 3.2 billion people on the internet right now, and we have more devices on the internet than actual people - roughly 23 billion devices. And when I say devices, it’s not the computer with a keyboard necessarily, it can have a monitor or not, it can be a phone, a Chromecast, a thing in the industrial sense, it’s a connected CPU. Right now we have 23 billion devices and out of those we have clients and hosts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/Hans1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hans Steinbrecher&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hosts essentially serve content, they are servers and there are about 75 million of them. All of those servers have addresses, and we call those addresses domains. We have around 200 million active domains right now, and the domains are the applications, the companies, the dot com, and each of those servers essentially has a lot of data in them and databases and data centers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/Hans2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hans Steinbrecher&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These servers in the old school sense would be like me sitting at home having a server and jamming on it, but in the modern sense, just as we saw, we have Amazon Web Services (AWS), we have Google Cloud, we have Microsoft. We have these big cloud providers and they have essentially split into clouds. It’s always debatable how much is actually in the cloud but probably around 90% of computation is happening in the cloud. And it’s very, very centralized. That’s the point here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/Hans3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hans Steinbrecher&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taeyoon:&lt;/strong&gt; So it’s physically centralized in a couple nodes, and corporations own access as gatekeepers to these clouds as well. So it’s doubly centralized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hans:&lt;/strong&gt; The cloud providers offer you so many services and cool new techniques: machine learning and fancy databases, a lot of cool features that make building computer architecture today quite fun and accessible. If I work on Snapchat and want to focus on a cool experience for you, I’m probably not going to build an old infrastructure but rather I’m going to go to Google Cloud and say, “Hey I built my infrastructure on top of you because you have all these cool queues and cool distributed memory storage and stuff like that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taeyoon:&lt;/strong&gt; But it also means that they can take it away from you at any time. So it’s pricey and also you don’t really own it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hans:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah, that’s the point here, it’s really like private property. The companies think, “What’s going on in my cloud is my business. I’m the boss, I’m host, and I decide how transparent I am. You won’t know what’s going on in my cloud, in my back-end.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/Hans4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hans Steinbrecher&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taeyoon:&lt;/strong&gt; The key concern here is privacy. Because it’s “private property” but we don’t really retain ownership of this data, the company can do whatever it wants to do. We’ve seen many historic and recent examples of abuse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hans:&lt;/strong&gt; Intentional and unintentional abuse, probably. If I, the company, own all of this data and it’s my responsibility to take care of it–care in the sense of really fixing all loopholes where people can access it–it’s very vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the cloud, there’s a lot of effort going on to provide their services–there’s a technical effort just to keep the service up. If I’m a high-scaling business, I want to make sure all of this is available to you, I want to never be offline. I have people paying for this. The natural involvement of the engineers in the backend is this famous thing, the “CPA theorem”: you cannot be consistent, partition-tolerant, and available at the same time. You always have to deal with trade-offs and mitigate a bit. So, you distribute and you network over regions, and across the regions you have multiple duplicates of your service, making sure that there will be backups wherever there’s a failure. For example, you might send a snapchat that uses the Google Cloud regions across the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/Hans5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hans Steinbrecher&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One problem essentially is that we don’t know exactly what happens with our data even though a lot of effort goes into keeping the service up so that in one form or another, you always access your data from a centralized point of view. Let me show you a concrete example through video-conferencing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say Taeyoon and I are about to do a Google Hangout. We open the browser on our device and punch in the domain, then we go to a name server which resolves this domain to an IP address. This IP address is the address that Google associated with it when they bought the domain. Before we actually go to the server itself, we load the certificate which is associated with this domain to make the connection encrypted, so that no one can access it just by spoofing on the wire, which anyone could do. So, now that I have the certificate I can actually access the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that happens is loading the static assets. The static assets are what your application contains: your html, your JavaScript, your styles. And those static assets are hosted initially from the cloud provider–in this case, Google cloud–but they are distributed outside of this network in the form of CDN (Content Delivery Network). We connect to the closest node, and now that we have the application running, I want to have a video stream with Taeyoon. In order to do so, we will exchange session descriptors which will go through the Google Cloud servers and say, “Hey, I have a video cam and a microphone, and this kind of codex, framerate, and resolutions,” and I will send this to Taeyoon through centralized servers over TCP protocol, websockets, standard techniques, etc. We exchange session descriptors, and part of that is where the stream will be coming from, which is the IP address. In this case, Google Cloud is a centralized video or media bridge, so this IP indicates to Google hangouts one of their centralized media bridges. We will open a peer connection to this media bridge and establish a stream. A peer connection has multiple media streams and now we get going. The media streams are also encrypted, so the protocol is called RTPS. Google also has keys, so the stream itself is encrypted over the wire, but the media bridge is accessible and decrypted. Content can be indexed and accessed in one way or another, allowing features like muting, mixing, but also monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taeyoon:&lt;/strong&gt; The question really is: when this data is indexed on the cloud, do they retain some parts of it, or most of it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hans:&lt;/strong&gt; What’s the question? (laughs)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taeyoon:&lt;/strong&gt; Well, I guess that’s a question that they can’t really answer because it’s private property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hans:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah, it’s essentially this lack of transparency. Well I don’t know if it is. But it could be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;taeyoon-choi-1&quot;&gt;Taeyoon Choi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, that’s how the internet today works. Next, I’ll do a brief introduction to Distributed Data and Network to give you an overview of what we’re thinking about. I’m very new to this topic, and what I’m going to be covering is a very small fragment of a larger initiative. Some of these projects might be works in progress. What I’m attempting to do, along with my collaborators who share different ideas and facets of technical development, is to begin to think about the kind of network that we want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One project that I’ve been following is &lt;a href=&quot;https://ipfs.io/&quot;&gt;IPFS&lt;/a&gt;, which stands for Inter Planetary File System. It’s a p2p,  peer-to-peer, file sharing system that allows you to be a node, where you can share your data. One of it’s missions is bringing permanence in the web, as an alternative to how the HTML links usually rot over time, and we end up with this very impermanent web where we cannot keep track of all this data that we are building. There are more interesting technical details to IPFS, which I won’t get into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project that I’ve been following more closely is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://datproject.org/&quot;&gt;Dat Project&lt;/a&gt;, a distributed data community, or DAT. It’s filling in some of shortcomings of traditional p2p. For example, with Napster or BitTorrent, it’s pretty convenient to share an mp3 file, like a Britney Spears song. Britney’s song is really easy to share because it’s a piece of static content that is shared from multiple nodes. However, what traditional p2p is not very good at is updating content over time. If the song changes, how do we know which is the right song and which version should be kept track of? The Dat project is addressing those issues by making it easy to have a version controlled history of this file. Another shortcoming of p2p is that it’s difficult for large dataset such as a few terabytes of data. Technically BitTorrent breaks things apart and then puts them back together and with large datasets, the integrity of the data could be compromised in doing this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two projects, (Dat and IPFS), are closely related. Dat actually uses IPFS among other things to have this decentralized modes of sharing data. However, there are very important differences between them. Dat is developed by teams in Portland, Denmark, Taipei, Berlin. IPFS is concentrated in Palo Alto and has some venture capital funding behind it. They’re both open-sourced, but Dat is based on foundational support by a nonprofit. Their visions are slightly different. Where IPFS wants to be a permanent distributed web, Dat focuses on sharing data over large networks. The business model is very different as well. I believe that IPFS is related to FileCoin which is a a blockchain-based storage network and cryptocurrency, and they had an initial coin offering as fundraising for their revenue. Dat encourages users to host their own data or use subscription based services like &lt;a href=&quot;https://hashbase.io/&quot;&gt;Hashbase&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to walk you through the basic steps. There are a couple ways of accessing it. After you install Dat, You can use the Terminal to access Dat, type “dat clone” and a long address (hash), and you’re going to clone this address into your folder called “Demo.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_7.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dat clone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then it’s cloning 25 files. There are 3 connections right now so that means that there might be three other people sharing or cloning this data right now. Dat syncs quickly, and just like that we have cat pictures, somebody’s cat pictures that they felt like sharing on the Dat network. That person has the private key, which means they can update or take down their cat pictures at any point that they want. But the other nodes that are sharing the cat pictures do not have that private key: they have a public key and can access them, clone and mirror them, and distribute them, but they don’t have ownership of that data. By sharing a public key, you’re giving permission for others to re-host your data. These added or shared hosts can’t change or write new content, since you are the owner of your data, but they can host whatever data they have accessed from your Dat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I want to talk about how to get started with dat from a less technical standpoint. There are many ways to clone someone else’s file on the distributed web. A good place to start from is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://beakerbrowser.com/&quot;&gt;Beaker&lt;/a&gt; browser. You can download Beaker in your operating systems and you can start to share data with other folks through it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m greatful to Tara Vancil and Joe Hand who gave detailed editorial feedback for the next part.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you want to share your cat, you can share it by publishing your local copies. I don’t have a cat, so I made a cat drawing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_9.png&quot; alt=&quot;Rainbow cat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I feel inspired to share my cats, I can use the Beaker browser to add my folder called “cats” and then change thefile name to “rainbow cat.” I have reviewed the changes, as Beaker keeps track of different versions, and when I’m happy with the files, I publish the folder. The cat that I drew is sitting in the hard drive of my computer. But I have shared it over the Distributed Network. And I used Beaker to host and share the cat drawing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_10.png&quot; alt=&quot;hosting cat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And my cat drawing just got a unique dat key – dat://f7015de28d02cfb99debc6545aead91418b61c4ca74b905837be2608ed13f21a If I share this key with you, you can clone the cat drawing. However, if I don’t share it with you, you can’t access the file. In order to access the file of my cat drawing, you would need to know the actual address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_11.png&quot; alt=&quot;cat hash&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The great part about this way of sharing is that whenever I change the cat, it keeps track of the history and you can address those particular moments in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_12.png&quot; alt=&quot;cat revisions&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dat URLs are cryptographically unguessable, meaning you can only discover and decrypt the files for a dat if you know its URL. Nobody else can access it unless they know the specific address. By publishing the file and sending you the key, I’m inviting you to access the cat drawing on the computer that I’m using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a related note, in a little bit, I’m going to ask Sara to help us understand the concept of hash from a technical perspective and use-case scenario. Basically, hashes change over time depending on the versions. So as you can see at the very end there’s a plus six, so I’ve made six changes and it keeps track of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to get your own copy of someone else’s data and host or share it yourself. One way is by cloning data from remote into local. I’m going to clone pictures of &lt;a href=&quot;https://taravancil.com/&quot;&gt;Tara’s&lt;/a&gt;(who is one of the people behind Beaker) cat &lt;a href=&quot;https://hashbase.io/taravancil/sasha&quot;&gt;Sasha&lt;/a&gt; into my computer by using Beaker and now I have Sasha’s photos!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_8.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sasha's cat files&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beaker browser also has a built in tool for making editable copies of any Dat website by clicking “make an editable copy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interesting about peer to peer sharing is the full control over distribution of data. When I stop the Beaker browser, the cat drawing is no longer accessible to you, unless you’ve already cloned it. Once I’ve shared the URL with friends however, they can rebroadcast the files, allowing other people to seed them and them make accesible once I’ve stopped using the Beaker Browser. This allows for ways of getting around having to host the file on your browser or your computer, you can let other people host the file on their node as well or use hosting services like &lt;a href=&quot;https://hashbase.io/&quot;&gt;Hashbase&lt;/a&gt; which I mentioned earlier. This means that you can either make your cat available for other people and hold them responsible for it when you don’t want to be, like cat sitting. You can also use &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dat-land/dat-desktop&quot;&gt;DAT desktop app&lt;/a&gt; to clone remotes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_13.png&quot; alt=&quot;how to build your own distributed net&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, I have a lot of questions: how does this actually work? How we can specify different use-cases, like when we want to make our data available for certain people but not all people? How does the encryption work and how can we make the data perish if we don’t want to make it available? These are technical and philosophical questions that &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/seandockray&quot;&gt;Sean Dockray&lt;/a&gt;, an artist and a friend who inspired me to look at this, has been helping me understand. We are planning to share some of these resources soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The really important part is asking what can we do with the distributed web. I’m asking Callil, an artist,  designer, and developer to talk about some different implementations of these ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_14.png&quot; alt=&quot;Callil Capuozzo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;callil-capuozzo&quot;&gt;Callil Capuozzo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I organize &lt;a href=&quot;https://newcomputers.group/&quot;&gt;New Computer Working Group&lt;/a&gt; where we collectively research new, more fluid forms of computing and actively participate in the p2p web. I wanted to share some of the networks that I’m part of and some other examples of what the p2p web can look like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I want to mention that there are a lot of different things that make up the p2p web, such as social networks, file sharing, scientific data, web tools, art and blockchains. Torrents are still a very big part of it. But these days with the emergence of some new technologies, a lot of stuff is beginning to be centered around what it means to have social networks that are p2p or distributed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first example is called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scuttlebutt.nz/&quot;&gt;Scuttlebutt&lt;/a&gt;, which is an open platform or an open protocol for social networks that are fully distributed. It’s a different implementation than Dat or IPFS but very similar. As a user on the Scuttlebutt network, when you make a profile you get a hash that is your user profile. At first you don’t have any connections until you make a friend or you add somebody else’s hash to your network. So, if I add Taeyoon’s address to my network, not only do I get his messages that he has posted over time, but I also get access to his portion of the network, his friend list essentially. If I then follow another person in Taeyoon’s network, the area of the social network that I can access grows a bit more. In this model, you can see how these nodes begin to build up a representation of your local network that you’re participating in. What’s really interesting about this is that unlike Facebook or Twitter, there’s no central server that defines what that network is. This means you can have these small local spaces without connecting to a larger network. Or, you can go and connect to as many peers as you want. Scuttlebutt has also implemented interesting things like channels, which define how you hashtag a post. These channels can be empty if you don’t have a peer that has participated in it, meaning there’s no way to participate across networks unless you build bots, which are called “pubs” in the Scuttlebutt world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_15.png&quot; alt=&quot;Scuttlebutt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next example I want to talk about is a social network called &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.xxiivv.com/#rotonde&quot;&gt;Rotonde&lt;/a&gt;, which is built on Dat. I want to use this example in comparison to Scuttlebutt to show the divergent and different ways of building p2p social networks. Rotonde is similar in the sense that you really only get access to content when you follow people through your peers. One of the major differences between the two networks is the way they store your files on your computer. Scuttlebutt stores files in a non human readable hashed table, a hidden .sbb file that is essentially gibberish inside. With Rotonde, similar to how Taeyoon was showing you could upload or download your cat file, your profile contains an image, a JSON file of all your posts, and a web app– an index.html that renders the view. Your JSON file also includes your following list, so when loaded all the posts from those peers’ JSON files are also loaded into your feed. Because it’s a human readable front end, I can go in as a user and edit the page to look however I want. As a user of Rotonde, I don’t have a centrally defined look, feel or behavior of the social network. I can make the background blue. I can make all the posts into expandable pop-ups. I can do whatever I want because I own the front end and I own the definition of how this social network is expressed to me. As a web page, this is in contrast to Scuttlebutt, where there is more centralization right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_16.png&quot; alt=&quot;Rotonde&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve looked at social networks as one way the p2p web is being built. Another interesting part of the p2p web is publishing. Having access to publishing is an important part of what it means to own your data and define how your words are represented online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_17.png&quot; alt=&quot;Enoki&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_18.png&quot; alt=&quot;Enoki&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://panel.enoki.site/&quot;&gt;Enoki&lt;/a&gt; is a project which gives you the ability to build websites right within &lt;a href=&quot;https://beakerbrowser.com/&quot;&gt;Beaker Browser&lt;/a&gt;. Similar to the cat example, you go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://panel.enoki.site/&quot;&gt;panel.enoki.site&lt;/a&gt; and you basically fork or duplicate an Enoki project. This will download the whole entire project onto your computer and then give you access to an editor and a front end which you can instantly start to publish from. Once you’ve downloaded that, you receive the Dat url to share into the network which becomes accessible as soon as you hit publish. This platform is a really easy way for getting your stuff out there and then retaining ownership over it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_20.png&quot; alt=&quot;Gotenna&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of you may have heard of Brooklyn-based &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gotenna.com/&quot;&gt;Gotenna&lt;/a&gt;. We’ve been talking about what it means to have a p2p web which is accessible through a browser in the same way we already access web content. Gotenna is building something with similar ideals to this but by using physical devices. They provide a low power radio that can be used to make a mesh network between any other Gotenna user in the world. When you turn the device on it becomes a discoverable peer that any other Gotenna user can search for. So it starts to make a mini internet for you, a small community. It’s really good for places that are out in the wild which don’t have internet access. It also suggests the idea that you can build smaller networks that don’t necessarily have to be connected to the internet at large. With Gotenna, you don’t have to be connected all the time. You can go offline and make a smaller, more protected internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_21.png&quot; alt=&quot;Self Portrait&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_22.png&quot; alt=&quot;Self Portrait&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also want to mention that p2p spaces are perfect for art and for different forms of expression because of the ideals they capture. Some of you may know &lt;a href=&quot;http://art.teleportacia.org/olia.html&quot;&gt;Olia Lialina&lt;/a&gt;, she’s an amazing artist that has done tons of work over time. Recently she put out a project called &lt;a href=&quot;http://olia.lialina.work/&quot;&gt;Self Portrait&lt;/a&gt;, which is an expression of what it means to be distributed. When you visit the website, you get a diagram guide of how you should view this site. One part of the site loads a Dat URL, another part a Tor browser URL, and then finally, a regular HTTP URL. When you load them all up you get a beautiful gif that’s in sync. This work is a really interesting representation and expression of what it means as an individual to participate in the internet at large in all these different ways. There are a lot of ways artists can use these ideas and platforms in their work to express themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally I want to touch on blockchains because they are an important thing to mention. A lot of the ideals in these new technologies are similar, but blockchain, as opposed to social networks like Scuttlebutt or Rotonde, is built to be a network where there is trustless relationships with peers. With blockchain, you can have consensus even if you don’t have a relationship with the person you’re communicating with. This is in contrast to networks like Scuttlebutt, where you need to have explicit trust from the other person by means of following or agreeing to be a friend. This kind of social action is at odds with the blockchain model of a financial system. I think these two opposing forces is an interesting thing to think about in considering what the world of what p2p web is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_23.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sarah Gray&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sarah-gray&quot;&gt;Sarah Gray&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi, my name is Sarah. I’m a software engineer and currently a student at SFPC. I want to talk about the data structure called the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Merkle_tree&quot;&gt;Merkle tree&lt;/a&gt;, which is a very important piece of the distributed web in regards to IPFS and the blockchain. The Merkle tree is what gives you all of the complex-seeming addresses that we’ve seen in this presentation: strings of random, undecipherable numbers and letters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I approach a new data structure or a complex topic I like to break it down for myself and put it on ground that I’m familiar with so I can understand how it exists in the “real” world. If there are any human-scale analogs that can help build a bridge of understanding for myself and others, I will use them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Merkle tree is a way of organizing data. It’s called Merkle because the person who invented it was named Robert Merkle. I like to think of it as the data structure that lets you encode history such that you can’t go back and change it. It’s sort of like the “No Fake News” data structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to explain Merkle through Pig Latin. Merkle uses a cryptographic signature, but because cryptographic signatures are hard for humans to look at and understand, I want to talk about Merkle through the lens of Pig Latin so we can follow what’s happening. We’ll then go back at the end and talk about why the internet isn’t using Pig Latin and why cryptography itself is very important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_24.png&quot; alt=&quot;Merkle Tree Example&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we’re looking at here is a tree of data.  Let’s start at the bottom [of this slide] and assume that you have on your computer four objects: a picture of a cat, a pdf of a book, an mp3 of your favorite song, and a spreadsheet of some data. And what you want to do is take a backup of your system at that time where you have those four digital files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way that a Merkle tree works is that each of the leaves (which is the bottom row in the slide) is associated with a piece of data and that piece of data is encrypted. The contents of each leaf node is the encrypted representation of the data it is storing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you as a human look at your computer, you see a picture of a cat, a book, a song, and a graph, but under the hood each of these objects is just data, a series of  0’s and 1’s. A cryptographic hash function is applied to the data and encodes it. In the slide, this function is represented by &lt;strong&gt;h(data)&lt;/strong&gt; followed by the encoded version of the data. So using Pig Latin, “encrypting the cat image” would be represented as &lt;strong&gt;h(cat)&lt;/strong&gt; , encrypting the book would be represented by &lt;strong&gt;h(book)&lt;/strong&gt;, etc. etc. And in Pig Latin, those two function calls would output &lt;strong&gt;AtCat&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;OokBay&lt;/strong&gt;, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then the data rolls up the tree. The parent of these two children would take the two encrypted representations (of your cat and your book) and put them together to encrypt, creating a new encryption that represents a specific point in time. As you move up the tree, you go from four pieces of data to the two parents and then to the root node of the tree. The root node puts together the encrypted parent strings and runs the hashing algorithm, which again is Pig Latin in this example. This then gives you what’s called the Merkle root, and that piece of data is used to encode all of the data in your tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_25.png&quot; alt=&quot;Changed Merkle Tree Example&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s interesting about this structure is if you change any piece of data, the changes propagate all the way to the top. Let’s say we change our cat to a “red cat.” The Merkle root then changes from the previous example. We can see immediately that changes happened in the data-set and that the data is not the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the context of version control of the distributed web, a change might simply mean that you made an update and you have a new version of your cat file. In the context of the blockchain, it could be a sign that someone has tampered with the blocks. A transaction that was said to have happened might have been been tampered with, and then miners can know to ignore that transaction and leave it aside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re looking at this data structure from a security practise, it’s tamper-proof. When you’re looking at it from a content practise, it’s very specific version-control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sarah/dw-writings/blob/master/3-merkle-slides.md&quot;&gt;Here is a writeup with slides&lt;/a&gt; of what I’ve just spoken about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Merkle uses an encryption algorithm called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SHA-2&quot;&gt;SHA-256&lt;/a&gt; which is called a one way encryption algorithm. This means its very easy when you take an input to get the hash key that it encrypts to, but you can’t go backwards, i.e. you can’t take the encrypted string and then get the cat photo. That’s why it’s so secure. It’s never yet been cracked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However with Pig Latin as our encryption algorithm, it’s easy to go backwards because you know what it is, from “cat” to “atCay.” Also, with Pig Latin everytime you add more content, your “encrypted” string gets bigger and bigger. So using Pig Latin, the “encrypted” representation of the data would be bigger than the actual data itself. Whereas with the SHA-256, every encryption is 64 bits. So if you can have a file that’s extremely long or very short and it’s always going to be represented as a string that’s 64 bits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_26.png&quot; alt=&quot;SHA256 vs Pig Latin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taeyoon:&lt;/strong&gt; I asked my colleague Rishab to tell us a little bit about his research and what we can learn from Tor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_27.png&quot; alt=&quot;Rishab Nithyanand&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rishab-nithyanand&quot;&gt;Rishab Nithyanand&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/&quot;&gt;Tor&lt;/a&gt; is a very interesting idea because it’s sort of an overlay network, an attempt to implement a distributed system on top of a decentralized internet. Since Tor has been around now for about 15 years, we can learn from it all the problems you’re going to face when trying to build a distributed system on top of an established power structure. I want to talk about some of the problems that Tor has had, as we may face these things as issues in p2p systems later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally, Tor was built for anonymous communication. Now Tor has been repurposed by a lot of other parts of the world to allow people to circumvent censorship. Another thing about Tor is that it’s volunteer operated. One of the challenges it faces is the difficulty for volunteers to run relays which distribute the internet routing infrastructure that is already in place. The easiest way for people to do this is to rely on cloud services like Amazon and Google. This is because the way the traditional internet is set up makes it difficult to run routing infrastructures in our homes. Yet even if we were able to do this, Comcast, Verizon, and all of the other ISP(Internet Service Providers)’s would have problems with it. So, this is one way in which the traditional power structures are getting in the way of a distributed system. If you do do it on Amazon or Google, you’re then violating their terms of service and you’re going to get kicked out. You cannot run certain types of infrastructures that are required for Tor on these services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But a good thing that we find with Tor is that you end up with a lot of nice allies. There are a lot of ISP’s which have come out that make it really cheap and easy for users to run Tor infrastructure on their services. When we’re talking about censorship circumvention, there’s this new idea called decoy routing. It works on the idea that there are a lot of good allies and ISP’s around the world that want people from repressed and oppressed regions to have complete access to the internet. Perhaps completely unexpected, AT&amp;amp;T is a potential ally that wants people from Iran to be able to access the internet uncensored or unfiltered. With decoy routing, an ISP will establish a decoy channel for a user in Iran, so what it looks like to people on the outside and to the Iranian regime is that the user is using the AT&amp;amp;T infrastructure, autonomous system or network to access a site which isn’t cenesored, like amazon.com. In reality, the user and the ISP are winking at each other, saying, “We’ll pretend we’re going to amazon.com but we have a little secret in our communication stream which will make it look like I’m going to amazon.com but really I want to go to this news website.” Decoy routing establishes this “wink” in the communication stream between an ISP like AT&amp;amp;T and a user in Iran.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taeyoon:&lt;/strong&gt; I think the notion of trust comes into the spotlight here again, thinking about how can you can trust the anonymous systems. Then we begin considering how to redefine trust in a way where it’s beneficial for us to build stronger distributed responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rishab:&lt;/strong&gt; With systems like the blockchain and Tor, they’ve been built to withstand a  certain amount of bad behavior. I think distributed systems can be built to do that as well. The main issues and the main sources of attacks and vulnerabilities for Tor is that there are powerful entities that do not want distributed system to succeed. Correlation attacks come from ISP’s that are at either end of a Tor connection and can perform a traffic analysis to figure out who’s going where. The attacks are coming from powerful entities that exist on the centralized web that do not want the distributed web to succeed. We will have to figure out how to work with these things to make the distributed web a real thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taeyoon:&lt;/strong&gt; So the last part of the workshop is a question of how can we visualize, enact, perform and become the network of care. Before we perform this together, I wanted to ask if anyone from SFPC had anything to add or share?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_28.png&quot; alt=&quot;Nabil Hassein&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nabil-hassein&quot;&gt;Nabil Hassein&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think a lot about the connections between technology and imperialism. I read a lot of mainstream press stuff and I mostly hate it but I keep reading it, because it does have an influence and I try and understand it. In it there’s a lot of orientalist fear-mongering, stuff around the nature of “China is doing something.” Now some of it might actually be bad, but I definitely see the US government as the biggest problem in the world. It’s now been 15 years since the invasion of Iraq and the war is still ongoing there. So when I hear things like, “Oh the Iranian regime is doing something that’s so bad” I feel very skeptical of it and I wonder what’s the purpose and whether it’s supporting basically more war mongering. People still speak of the Iraq War as if it was a mistake and not a deliberate act, when it fact it was completely deliberate and planned. I think we need to have this context in mind when we think about the efforts of the Chinese government, for example, to basically have independent control over their own computing infrastructure rather than be perpetually reliant on the US government, which originally funded the internet and Tor and many of the other projects that people rely on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when I think about distributed and decentralized networks, I think about how can we actually have a radical diversity, where instead of everyone being constantly reliant on one single type of computing infrastructure or centralized provider, it becomes a question of what it might actually look like for many different nations and subgroups other than nations– whether black people or queer folks, disabled people– anyone with their own needs that aren’t being served by US imperialism and capitalism. These systems were not built for us and I don’t believe can be reformed for us, so I wonder what could radical diversity look like, and how we, as technologists, can build that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taeyoon:&lt;/strong&gt; So we’re going to try to visualize, enact, perform, and become the network of care, and to do that we are going to first visualize the internet as it stands today. And we are going to try to perform the distributed web of care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_29.png&quot; alt=&quot;group photo&quot; /&gt; 
&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_30.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;group photo&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_31.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;group photo&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_32.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;group photo&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_33.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;group photo&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_34.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;group photo&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_35.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;group photo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read a &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.fabled.net/sfpc,learning,workshop/thoughts-on-workshop-design&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; by Sarah Gray.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-thanks&quot;&gt;Special thanks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rhizome, The New Museum, Joe Hand and Danielle Robinson of the DAT project, Tara Vancil of the Beaker,  Sean Dockray, Sam Hart, Alexander R. Galloway, Agnes Pyrchla, Nitcha Tothong, Ailadi, Nabil Hassein, Sam Hart, Mindy Seu, Sarah Gray, Callil Capuozzo, Kelly Monson, Michael Connor, Rishab Nithyanandm and the workshop participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo: Alex Wagner, Lauren Studebaker&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transcription and editing: Shira Feldman&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Editing: Emilly Miller, Livia Huang&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;support&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distributed Web of Care is an independent, self funded initiative. We are actively searching for supporters. If you’d like to make donation, or hire Taeyoon Choi and the collaborators to lead a workshop, please contact studio@taeyoonchoi.com.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The first public event of Distributed Web of Care was presented as a part of Rhizome’s Ethics &amp;amp; Archiving the Web conference at the New Museum, NYC, March 24, 2018. The workshop offered resources for getting started with the Distributed Web, and invited computer scientists and domain experts to host an open conversation on counter-narratives to the mainstream internet.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Call for Fellows and Stewards</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/callforfellows/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Call for Fellows and Stewards" /><published>2018-04-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/callforfellows</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/callforfellows/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;design--storytelling-fellow&quot;&gt;Design &amp;amp; Storytelling Fellow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fellow will work with Taeyoon Choi alongside the Technology Fellow in designing and creating visual content for the ongoing Distributed Network of Care series, most importantly a project-specific website to be built by a static site generator and published on a distributed network. They should be experienced with web design (HTML, CSS, JS), typography, and collaboration with developers. They should have a particular interest in storytelling through digital and nonlinear forms, and an excitement for documenting workshops and future events with relevant artwork. They will create and publish openly DWC related content with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl-3.0.en.html&quot;&gt;GPL&lt;/a&gt; license with attributions to collaborators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fellow will also work with Taeyoon to assist in the planning of Uncomputable, taking place June 21-27th as well as the Distributed Web of Care Party to be hosted in July 29th. They should be present for both events and offer support with administration, facilitation and documentation. The application deadline is April 25th, with notification sent out by May 1st.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schedule&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;May 21-28: Onsite training and onboarding sessions. Part-time and flexible.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;June 15-July 31: Onsite work in Manhattan or Brooklyn. 4 days/week, 6 hours/day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Honorarium of $2000 for fellowship between June 15 and July 31, 2018. Fellows will be paid every two weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://airtable.com/shrbBTpEl8qgIWzkG&quot;&gt;Apply to become a Design &amp;amp; Storytelling Fellow, Summer 2018.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;technology--documentation-fellow&quot;&gt;Technology &amp;amp; Documentation Fellow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fellow will work with Taeyoon Choi alongside the Design Fellow to build and maintain custom static sites and distribute content via Dat and IPFS. They should have interest and experience in web  development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP), Distributed Networks and be able to teach technical tasks including data management, web security and web literacy. The fellow will provide technical assistance across DWC projects as well as support with website and database maintenance.  They will create and publish openly DWC related content with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl-3.0.en.html&quot;&gt;GPL&lt;/a&gt; license with attributions to collaborators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fellow will also work with Taeyoon to assist in the planning of Uncomputable, taking place June 21-27th as well as the Distributed Web of Care Party to be hosted in July 29th. They should be be present for both events and offer support with administration, facilitation and documentation. The application deadline is April 25th, with notification sent out by May 1st.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schedule&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;May 21-28: Onsite training and onboarding sessions. Part-time and flexible.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;June 15-July 31: Onsite work in Manhattan or Brooklyn. 4 days/week, 6 hours/day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Honorarium of $2000 for fellowship between June 15 and July 31, 2018. Fellows will be paid every two weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://airtable.com/shrbBTpEl8qgIWzkG&quot;&gt;Apply to become a Technology &amp;amp; Documentation Fellow, Summer 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stewards&quot;&gt;Stewards&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stewards are guest collaborators, contributing to DWC initiatives with their domain expertise. Stewards are often invited to present at DWC events and contribute to building the code base as well as code of conduct. In this volunteer role, stewards will lead their own projects utilizing access to technical resources and collaboration with the fellows and with Taeyoon directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2018, we’re looking for stewards with expertise in peer to peer web (IPFS, Dat and other formats), design and storytelling, alternative and distributed networks, Internet privacy, security, data and community activism. Stewards should demonstrate a willingness to share materials and insight as well as an investment in building community through teaching and learning. To apply, please send an email with a brief description of your expertise and what you are hoping to offer to the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://airtable.com/shrJKwgf305PUDKjm&quot;&gt;Apply to become a steward&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/care.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;support&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distributed Web of Care is an independent, self funded initiative. We are actively searching for supporters. If you’d like to make donation, or hire Taeyoon Choi and the collaborators to lead a workshop, please contact studio@taeyoonchoi.com.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Design &amp;amp; Storytelling Fellow</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Code of Conduct</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/coc/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Code of Conduct" /><published>2018-04-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/coc</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/coc/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/EAW/EAW_3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;open-sourceculturetech-citizenship&quot;&gt;Open [Source/Culture/Tech] Citizenship&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A supplemental goal of this Code of Conduct is to increase open [source/culture/tech] citizenship by encouraging participants to recognize and strengthen the relationships between our actions and their effects on our community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communities mirror the societies in which they exist and positive action is essential to counteract the many forms of inequality and abuses of power that exist in society. We seek to create an open and sharing environment deeply based in open source practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All open source (licensed or otherwise) and copyrighted work that is integrated into work inside and outside of the Distributed Web of Care event must be appropriately adhered to under the referenced work’s license guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you see someone who is making an extra effort to ensure our community is welcoming, friendly, and encourages all participants to contribute to the fullest extent, we want to know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;expected-behavior&quot;&gt;Expected Behavior&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Participate in an authentic and active way. In doing so, you contribute to the health and longevity of this community. This is a grassroots event that we build together from the ground up. Everyone is expected to contribute.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exercise consideration and respect in your speech and actions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Attempt collaboration before conflict.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be respectful of the space, tools, equipment, and materials.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Refrain from demeaning, discriminatory, or harassing behavior and speech.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Give attribution where attribution is due. Adhere to CC, open source, GNU and other licenses of work used and remixed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be mindful of your surroundings and of your fellow participants. Alert community leaders if you notice a dangerous situation, someone in distress, or violations of this Code of Conduct, even if they seem inconsequential.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;unacceptable-behavior&quot;&gt;Unacceptable Behavior&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No form of harassment will be tolerated. Harassment includes, but is not limited to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Verbal comments that reinforce social structures of domination related to gender, gender identity and expression, sexual orientation, skill level, disability, physical appearance, body size, race, age, or religion.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Intentionally lewd or sexually exploitative images in public spaces.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deliberate intimidation, stalking, following, or use of physical force; harassing photography or recording.
Sustained disruption of talks or other events; inappropriate physical contact.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unwelcome sexual attention; and advocating for, or encouraging, any of the above behavior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;enforcement&quot;&gt;Enforcement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants asked to stop any harassing behavior are expected to comply immediately. If a participant engages in harassing behavior, event organizers retain the right to take any actions to keep the event a welcoming environment for all participants. This includes warning the offender or expulsion from the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reporting&quot;&gt;Reporting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you feel unsafe, uncomfortable, or unwelcome, please speak to an organizer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/tchoi8&quot;&gt;Taeyoon Choi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/fablednet&quot;&gt;Sarah Gray&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Code of Conduct was adapted from the example policy from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://etextilespringbreak.org/&quot;&gt;eTextiles Spring Break&lt;/a&gt;, via &lt;a href=&quot;http://geekfeminism.wikia.com/wiki/Conference_anti-harassment/Policy&quot;&gt;Geek Feminism wiki&lt;/a&gt;, created by the Ada Initiative and other volunteers and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://berlincodeofconduct.org/&quot;&gt;Berlin Code of Conduct.net&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;support&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distributed Web of Care is an independent, self funded initiative. We are actively searching for supporters. If you’d like to make donation, or hire Taeyoon Choi and the collaborators to lead a workshop, please contact studio@taeyoonchoi.com.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Open [Source/Culture/Tech] Citizenship</summary></entry></feed>